[[('A', 'O'), ('coalition', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('announced', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('plan', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('sue', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Census', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('effort', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('agency', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('delete', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('40', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('joined', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Federation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('for', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Immigration', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Reform', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('announcing', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suit', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('filed', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Pittsburgh', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('spokesmen', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('news', 'O'), ('conference', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('contends', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('distribute', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Representatives', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('unfair', 'O'), ('shifts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Census', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('required', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('everyone', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('mention', 'O'), ('citizenship', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('instructs', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('apportionment', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('whole', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('persons', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('residing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('various', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('approach', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('upheld', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('similar', 'O'), ('suit', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('brought', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('immigration', 'O'), ('reform', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1980', 'O'), ('Census', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Nonetheless', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Dan', 'PERSON'), ('Stein', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('immigration', 'O'), ('reform', 'O'), ('federation', 'O'), ('contended', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('allowed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('determining', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('structure', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rep.', 'O'), ('Tom', 'PERSON'), ('Ridge', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Pa.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Census', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('should', 'O'), ('actually', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('everyone', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('develop', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('method', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('determine', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('illegally', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('deduct', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('figures', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('reapportioning', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rep.', 'O'), ('Jan', 'PERSON'), ('Meyers', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Kan.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('suggested', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Census', 'O'), ('form', 'O'), ('asking', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('respondents', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('citizerns', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
