[[('Lawmakers', 'O'), ('clashed', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('Census', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('debating', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('following', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('letter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), ('results', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('unfair', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('forum', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Census', 'O'), ('subcommittee', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('bills', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('require', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Census', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('figure', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('legally', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('delete', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('counts', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('reapportioning', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Representatives', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fairness', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Rep.', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('J.', 'PERSON'), ('Ridge', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Pa.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('contended', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('numbers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('benefit', 'O'), ('unfairly', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('totals', 'O'), ('give', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('extra', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Because', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('435-seat', 'O'), ('limit', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('gains', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('member', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('lose', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Ridge', 'PERSON'), ('cited', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1980', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Indiana', 'LOCATION'), ('lost', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('seats', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Subcommittee', 'O'), ('Chairman', 'O'), ('Mervyn', 'PERSON'), ('M.', 'PERSON'), ('Dymally', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Calif.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('unsure', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('bills', 'O'), ('backed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Ridge', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('constitutional', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), ('requires', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Census', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('cound', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('persons', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('purposes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('reapportionment', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('specify', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('am', 'O'), ('disturbed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('implication', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('undocumented', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('are', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('`persons', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Dymally', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Noting', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Indians', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('excluded', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('participation', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('commented', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('return', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('human', 'O'), ('beings', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('considered', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('equal', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eyes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Every', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('adopted', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('counted', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('added', 'O'), ('Rep.', 'O'), ('Don', 'PERSON'), ('Edwards', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Calif.', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('intent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('framers', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('apportionment', 'O'), ('purposes', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('Rep.', 'O'), ('Albert', 'PERSON'), ('G.', 'PERSON'), ('Bustamente', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Texas', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('termed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('worry', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('hysterical', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('pointing', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('movement', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('western', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('larger', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('representation', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('presence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Census', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('also', 'O'), ('opposes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('bills', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('contending', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('effort', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('determine', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('alien', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('delay', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('complicate', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('unlikely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('truth', 'O'), ('anyway', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Reps.', 'O'), ('Tom', 'PERSON'), ('Petri', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Wis.', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('F.', 'PERSON'), ('Goodling', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Pa.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('asserted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('violates', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('basic', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('equal', 'O'), ('representation', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('giving', 'O'), ('greater', 'O'), ('voice', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('live', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('Rep.', 'O'), ('Tim', 'PERSON'), ('Valentine', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-N.C.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('contended', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('granting', 'O'), ('representation', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('individuals', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('entered', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('breaking', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('laws', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
