[[('A', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('hanging', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('Census', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('resolved', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('decision', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('personnel', 'O'), ('stationed', 'O'), ('overseas', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('arguing', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('keep', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('blocked', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('effort', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('require', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('excluded', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('numbers', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('reapportionment', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('decade', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('raised', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('committee', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('1', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Census', 'O'), ('figures', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('redistribute', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('435', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('seats', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('distribute', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('governments', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('reapportionment', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('riveted', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('members', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('slow', 'O'), ('growth', 'O'), ('threatens', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('seats', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('North', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('growth', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('lagged', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('South', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Undocumented', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('largely', 'O'), ('concentrated', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('industrial', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('fear', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('loss', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('areas', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('counted', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('While', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('counted', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('personnel', 'O'), ('stationed', 'O'), ('overseas', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Commerce', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('settled', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('announcing', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Defense', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('ways', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1.2', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('1.6', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('civilian', 'O'), ('defense', 'O'), ('workers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('live', 'O'), ('overseas', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('deciding', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('yet', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('decided', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('possibilities', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ('owns', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('lived', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('battle', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('meanwhile', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('committee', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('floor', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rep.', 'O'), ('Tom', 'PERSON'), ('Ridge', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Pa.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('unsuccessfully', 'O'), ('sought', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('attach', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('appropriations', 'O'), ('measure', 'O'), ('providing', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('5.8', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('run', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('State', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Justice', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commerce', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('departments', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('800', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('bill', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('approved', 'O'), ('258-165', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Opponents', 'O'), ('noted', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), ('requires', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('seats', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('apportioned', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('persons', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('residing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Every', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('created', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('counted', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('non-citizens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('observed', 'O'), ('Rep.', 'O'), ('Don', 'PERSON'), ('Edwards', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Calif.', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('empowered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('identify', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('counted', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('responded', 'O'), ('Ridge', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Census', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('4', 'O'), ('billion', 'O'), ('budget', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('enough', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('identify', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('separate', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rep.', 'O'), ('Mervyn', 'PERSON'), ('Dymally', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Calif.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('debate', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('really', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('shifts', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('lead', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('seats', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('western', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Pennsylvania', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('care', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('unless', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Southwest', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('bring', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('lose', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('seat', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Dymally', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rep.', 'O'), ('Tim', 'PERSON'), ('Valentine', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-N.C.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('fair', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('constitutional', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Census', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('generally', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('opposed', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('attempt', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('delete', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('contending', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('determine', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('legally', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Asking', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('status', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('lying', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('refusing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('participate', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('resulting', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('potential', 'O'), ('undercount', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('areas', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
