[[('Public', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('throughout', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('have', 'O'), ('condemned', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('vote', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('exclude', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('shortchange', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('possibly', 'O'), ('deprive', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('millions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('dollars', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('services', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('programs', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('poor', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('outrageous', 'O'), ('piece', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('legislation', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('probably', 'O'), ('unconstitutional', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Assemblyman', 'PERSON'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Chacon', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('Friday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Chacon', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Diego', 'LOCATION'), ('Democrat', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Assembly', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Elections', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Reapportionment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Constitutional', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Amendments', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('created', 'O'), ('great', 'O'), ('confusion', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('stirred', 'O'), ('hopes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('especially', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('urban', 'O'), ('Democrats', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('overturned', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Representatives', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Major', 'O'), ('Impact', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('becomes', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('impact', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('influx', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('significantly', 'O'), ('boosts', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('thus', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('affect', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('size', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('congressional', 'O'), ('delegations', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('amount', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('doled', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('With', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('28', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('%', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nation', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('3', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('8', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Authorities', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('reapportionment', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('widely', 'O'), ('predicted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('would', 'O'), ('gain', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('congressional', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('gains', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('decade', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('counted', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('experts', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('anticipated', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('hard', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('exactly', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('congressional', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('lose', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('gotten', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('additional', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Milton', 'PERSON'), ('Marks', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Francisco', 'LOCATION'), ('Democrat', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('chairs', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Elections', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Reapportionment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Loss', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Funds', 'O'), ('Feared', 'O'), ('Jesse', 'PERSON'), ('R.', 'PERSON'), ('Huff', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('financial', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('lose', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('300', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('allocated', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('basis', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('determined', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('counts', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('measure', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('funds', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('services', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('80', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('annually', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('services', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('paid', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('half', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('amount', 'O'), ('paid', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mark', 'PERSON'), ('Tajima', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('legislative', 'O'), ('analyst', 'O'), ('employed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('administrative', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), ('Atty', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('James', 'PERSON'), ('K.', 'PERSON'), ('Hahn', 'PERSON'), ('described', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('vote', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('attempt', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('callous', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('self-serving', 'O'), ('interests', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('D.C.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('deny', 'O'), ('representation', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('financial', 'O'), ('resources', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('underprivileged', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Hahn', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('lose', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('money', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('goes', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('child', 'O'), ('care', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('housing', 'O'), ('rehabilitation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('counseling', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('services', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('homeless', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Immigration', 'O'), ('Law', 'O'), ('Overhaul', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('measure', 'O'), ('passed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('larger', 'O'), ('overhaul', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nation', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('immigration', 'O'), ('laws', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('becomes', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('place', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('annual', 'O'), ('cap', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('630,000', 'O'), ('immigrants', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('room', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Western', 'LOCATION'), ('Europe', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('bill', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('tough', 'O'), ('opposition', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Illinois', 'LOCATION'), ('with', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('alien', 'O'), ('populations', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('votes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Moreover', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Pittsburgh', 'LOCATION'), ('ruled', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('excluding', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('unconstitutional', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('impact', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('minimal', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('Myers', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('counsel', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('subcommittee', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('immigration', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('refugee', 'O'), ('affairs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Myers', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('measure', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('prohibit', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('receiving', 'O'), ('direct', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('benefits', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Social', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Security', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('payments', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('maintained', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('ineligibility', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('written', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('programs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Myers', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('assistance', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('receive', 'O'), ('comes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('form', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('block', 'O'), ('grants', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('qualify', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('direct', 'O'), ('financial', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('therefore', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('affected', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Puzzled', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Action', 'O'), ('Still', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('remain', 'O'), ('puzzled', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Tajima', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('sure', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('programs', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('foster', 'O'), ('care', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('abused', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('neglected', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('Supplemental', 'O'), ('Security', 'O'), ('Income', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('aged', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('blind', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('disabled', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('vulnerable', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('involve', 'O'), ('direct', 'O'), ('payments', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('money', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Orange', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('second-largest', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('alien', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('warned', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('effort', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Census', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('identify', 'O'), ('illegals', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('promote', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('fear', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('intimidation', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('immigrants', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Any', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('effort', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('discourage', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('participating', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('further', 'O'), ('reduce', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('figures', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('counted', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1980', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('wo', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('ludicrous', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Angelo', 'PERSON'), ('Doti', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('financial', 'O'), ('assistance', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Orange', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('County', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Social', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Services', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('fact', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stay', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('pay', 'O'), ('taxes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('avail', 'O'), ('themselves', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('services', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('We', 'O'), ('need', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('numbers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('To', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('eyes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Doti', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Times', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('writers', 'O'), ('Jerry', 'PERSON'), ('Gillam', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Marcida', 'PERSON'), ('Dodson', 'PERSON'), ('contributed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('article', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
