[[('The', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ('Social', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Services', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('wants', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('Orange', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('residents', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('counted', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('Census', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('ask', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Board', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Supervisors', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('position', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('resolution', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('introduced', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('supervisors', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('meeting', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Agency', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('excluded', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('mean', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('paper', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('200,000', 'O'), ('fewer', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('actual', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('lower', 'O'), ('figure', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('loss', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('56', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('revenue', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('letter', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('supervisors', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Larry', 'PERSON'), ('Leaman', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('agency', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('urged', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('board', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('adopt', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('resolution', 'O'), ('supporting', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('complete', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('opposing', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('attempts', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('systematically', 'O'), ('exclude', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('census', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Such', 'O'), ('exclusions', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('letter', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ('losing', 'O'), ('representatives', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('because', 'O'), ('districts', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('determined', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Just', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('efforts', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Census', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('boost', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('negotiators', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('agreed', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Before', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('action', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('voted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('bar', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Census', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('from', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('twice', 'O'), ('rejected', 'O'), ('efforts', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('exclude', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('agreement', 'O'), ('worked', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House-Senate', 'O'), ('conference', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('body', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('considered', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('approved', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Orange', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('contend', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('stake', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('included', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('1985', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Federal', 'O'), ('Immigration', 'O'), ('Reform', 'O'), ('Act', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), ('aliens', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('300,000', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Santa', 'LOCATION'), ('Ana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('44.5', 'O'), ('%', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Latinos', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('worried', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ramifications', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('undercounting', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('figured', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1980', 'O'), ('Census', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('shortchanged', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('50,000', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('If', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('included', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('meant', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('2.2', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('revenue', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('GEORGE', 'PERSON'), ('FRANK', 'PERSON')]]
