[[('But', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('risen', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Republican', 'O'), ('ranks', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('advocate', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('bootstrap', 'O'), ('conservatism', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('present', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('striking', 'O'), ('change', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Marshall', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('civil-rights', 'O'), ('pioneer', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('anchor', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('declining', 'O'), ('liberal', 'O'), ('faction', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('barely', 'O'), ('half', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('age', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('seat', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('named', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fill', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('age', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Marshall', 'PERSON'), ('helped', 'O'), ('create', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Now', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('extent', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('would', 'O'), ('add', 'O'), ('weight', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('majority', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('appears', 'O'), ('willing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('dismantle', 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('legacy', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Marshall', 'PERSON'), ('helped', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('build', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('While', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('opposition', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('policies', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('viewed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('incorporating', 'O'), ('quotas', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('preferences', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Opposes', 'O'), ('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('appeals', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('judge', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('ruled', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('outspoken', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('position', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('affirmative-action', 'O'), ('programs', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('unwise', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('unconstitutional', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('respects', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wild', 'O'), ('card', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('conservatives', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('jumped', 'O'), ('instantly', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('embrace', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('liberals', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('responses', 'O'), ('ranged', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('cautious', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('hostile', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('His', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('church-state', 'O'), ('relations', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('definition', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('constitutional', 'O'), ('due', 'O'), ('process', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('unknown', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Those', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('remain', 'O'), ('unknown', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('process', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('contentious', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('end', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('derail', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Studied', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('priesthood', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('attended', 'O'), ('Roman', 'O'), ('Catholic', 'O'), ('schools', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('college', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('studied', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('priesthood', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Catholic', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Church', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('vigorously', 'O'), ('opposes', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('apparently', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('position', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dimensions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('constitutional', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('privacy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('His', 'O'), ('position', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('probably', 'O'), ('sufficient', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('shift', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('direction', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('remains', 'O'), ('closely', 'O'), ('divided', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('My', 'O'), ('opposition', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('preferences', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('quotas', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('constitutional', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('opposition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('moral', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('ethical', 'O'), ('opposition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('conference', 'O'), ('sponsored', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Anti-Defamation', 'O'), ('League', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ("B'nai", 'O'), ("B'rith", 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('affirmative-action', 'O'), ('decision', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('split', 'O'), ('5-4', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('upholding', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Federal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Communications', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('policy', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('gives', 'O'), ('preference', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('acquiring', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('radio', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('licenses', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Justice', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('Brennan', 'PERSON'), ('wrote', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('decision', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('weeks', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('retired', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Marshall', 'PERSON'), ('joined', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Justice', 'O'), ('David', 'PERSON'), ('Souter', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('Brennan', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('successor', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('remain', 'O'), ('largely', 'O'), ('unknown', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Views', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('big', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('unknown', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('remain', 'O'), ('unknown', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('seat', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Appeals', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('widely', 'O'), ('viewed', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Capitol', 'LOCATION'), ('Hill', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('ideological', 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('rehearsal', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Some', 'O'), ('Democratic', 'O'), ('senators', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('again', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('votes', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('confirm', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('appeals', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('endorsements', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Three', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('denied', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Judge', 'O'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Bork', 'PERSON'), ('despite', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('voted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('confirm', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('now', 'O'), ('sits', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Leaders', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('deny', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('unless', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('expresses', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('precedents', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('continued', 'O'), ('adherence', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Roe', 'PERSON'), ('vs.', 'O'), ('Wade', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1973', 'O'), ('ruling', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('established', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('constitutional', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Abortion', 'O'), ('faction', 'O'), ('speaks', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Souter', 'O'), ('model', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('silence', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('evasion', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('absolutely', 'O'), ('unacceptable', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Kate', 'PERSON'), ('Michelman', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('executive', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Abortion', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rights', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Action', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('League', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Her', 'O'), ('reference', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Souter', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('September', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nominee', 'O'), ('gracefully', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('firmly', 'O'), ('deflected', 'O'), ('questions', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Howard', 'PERSON'), ('Metzenbaum', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Ohio', 'LOCATION'), ('Democrat', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('serves', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('endorsed', 'O'), ('Michelman', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('position', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'m", 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('reading', 'O'), ('tea', 'O'), ('leaves', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('voting', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dark', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('includes', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('Democrats', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('combative', 'O'), ('Republican', 'O'), ('conservatives', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('If', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('maintains', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('silence', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('unlikely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('founder', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('alone', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Rights', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('cautious', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cautious', 'O'), ('tone', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('essentially', 'O'), ('noting', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('concerns', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('urge', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('rush', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('judgment', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Leadership', 'O'), ('Conference', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Civil', 'O'), ('Rights', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('umbrella', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('185', 'O'), ('organizations', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('leading', 'O'), ('role', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('defeat', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bork', 'PERSON'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Introducing', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('nominee', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('televised', 'O'), ('news', 'O'), ('conference', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('drew', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('powerful', 'O'), ('appeal', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('life', 'O'), ('story', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('self-motivated', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('self-made', 'O'), ('success', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Judge', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('life', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('model', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('At', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('side', 'O'), ('stood', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('5', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Marshall', 'PERSON'), ('won', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('argument', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Brown', 'PERSON'), ('vs.', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Board', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Education', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('college', 'O'), ('freshman', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Marshall', 'PERSON'), ('joined', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('That', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('generation', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('rewriting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('rules', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('live', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('lives', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Well', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('presented', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('chapter', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('history', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('largely', 'O'), ('closed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('page', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('After', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('means', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('blanks', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('page', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('filled', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('CLARENCE', 'PERSON'), ('THOMAS', 'PERSON'), (';', 'O'), ('Born', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('23', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1948', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Pinpoint', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ga.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Education', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('B.A', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('from', 'O'), ('Holy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('College', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('1971', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('J.D', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('from', 'O'), ('Yale', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Law', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('School', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('1974.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Career', 'O'), (':', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1974-'77", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Missouri', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1977-'79", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Monsanto', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Co.', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1979-'81", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('legislative', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Danforth', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Mo', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1981-'82", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Education', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1982-'90", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Equal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Employment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Opportunity', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('1990-', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('U.S', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Circuit', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Appeals', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('for', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Columbia', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Source', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Who', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Who', 'O'), ('Among', 'O'), ('Black', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('WHAT', 'O'), ("'S", 'O'), ('NEXT', 'O'), ('?', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Now', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('nominated', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('step', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('September', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('August', 'O'), ('recess', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('After', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('committee', 'O'), ('makes', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('recommendation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('voted', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('full', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('promptly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('could', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('begins', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('October', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Source', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Mercury', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('News', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Services', 'ORGANIZATION')]]
