[[('Her', 'O'), ('critics', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('supportive', 'O'), ('spouse', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ("'ll", 'O'), ('accompany', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('husband', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('run', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('strong', 'O'), ('opinions', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('bound', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Some', 'O'), ("women's-rights", 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('upset', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('lobbying', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('comparable-worth', 'O'), ('legislation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('religious', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('troubled', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('anti-cult', 'O'), ('activities', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('involvement', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Lifespring', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('motivational', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Skin', 'O'), ('color', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Even', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('color', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('skin', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('determine', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('content', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('character', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('fact', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('drawn', 'O'), ('criticism', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('marriage', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('rejected', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('roots', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('respective', 'O'), ('careers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Thomases', 'PERSON'), ('have', 'O'), ('embraced', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('women', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('hindered', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('rather', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('helped', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('programs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('True', 'O'), ('equality', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('achieved', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('holding', 'O'), ('everyone', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('standard', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('believe', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('fair', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('anti-women', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Ricky', 'PERSON'), ('Silberman', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('vice', 'O'), ('chairwoman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('EEOC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('friend', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Thomases', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('She', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Virginia', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('opposed', 'O'), ('legislation', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('comparable', 'O'), ('worth', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('determining', 'O'), ('wages', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('economy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('workers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('women', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Conservative', 'O'), ('viewpoint', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Virginia', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('represented', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('viewpoint', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('jobs', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('staffer', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Republican', 'O'), ('congressman', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chamber', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('deputy', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Labor', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('advocates', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('colorblind', 'O'), ('society', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('marriage', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('example', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('philosophy', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('different', 'O'), ('symbolism', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('His', 'O'), ('marrying', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sign', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('rejection', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Russell', 'PERSON'), ('Adams', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Howard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Afro-American', 'O'), ('studies', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Great', 'O'), ('justices', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('roots', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('served', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('basis', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('understanding', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('lack', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sense', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('makes', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('troubling', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Religious', 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('wonder', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Some', 'O'), ('religious', 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('troubled', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dean', 'PERSON'), ('Kelley', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Churches', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'", 'O'), ('counselor', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('religious', 'O'), ('liberty', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('wrote', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('critique', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('that', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('grounds', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('organization', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('opposition', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('nominee', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('author', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('mention', 'O'), ('Virginia', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('text', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('concerned', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('involvement', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Cult', 'O'), ('Awareness', 'O'), ('Network', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('CAN', 'O'), (')', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Chicago-based', 'O'), ('organization', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('educates', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('destructive', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('cults', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('involvement', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('affect', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('husband', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('handling', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('religious-liberty', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('shares', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('subject', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('During', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ("'80s", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Virginia', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('enrolled', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Lifespring', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('self-help', 'O'), ('course', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('challenges', 'O'), ('students', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('responsibility', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('lives', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('percentage', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('program', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('300,000', 'O'), ('graduates', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('deeply', 'O'), ('disturbed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Lifespring', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('methods', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('involve', 'O'), ('intense', 'O'), ('emotional', 'O'), ('self-examination', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('clean', 'O'), ('break', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Virginia', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('troubled', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Lifespring', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('activities', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('eventually', 'O'), ('broke', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('organization', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Since', 'O'), ('1985', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('advocate', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('cult', 'O'), ('activities', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('When', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('served', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('labor-relations', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chamber', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commerce', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('from', 'O'), ('1985', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('represented', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('interests', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('business', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('congressional', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('comparable', 'O'), ('worth', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('child-care', 'O'), ('legislation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
