[[('But', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Howard', 'PERSON'), ('Metzenbaum', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Ohio', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('confirming', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('justices', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('learning', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('felt', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('free', 'O'), ('ride', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('tougher', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('ferreting', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('failure', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('give', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('answer', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('unwilling', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('vote', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Metzenbaum', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('CBS', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('Morning', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Arlen', 'PERSON'), ('Specter', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Pa.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('noted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Metzenbaum', 'PERSON'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('Justice', 'O'), ('David', 'PERSON'), ('Souter', 'PERSON'), ('during', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('position', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('appropriate', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ask', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('nominee', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ultimate', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('decide', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('specific', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Specter', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('yet', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('Reagan-Bush', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('nominee', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('remains', 'O'), ('silent', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('choose', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('ascends', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('weaken', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Metzenbaum', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('who', 'O'), ('voted', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Circuit', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Appeals', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('District', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('Columbia', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Orrin', 'PERSON'), ('Hatch', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Utah', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Today', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('literally', 'O'), ('nobody', 'O'), ('nominated', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('should', 'O'), ('give', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('regard', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('future', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Patrick', 'PERSON'), ('Leahy', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Vt.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('alone', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('throwing', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('decisions', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('legitimate', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ask', 'O'), ('Judge', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('settled', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('Roe', 'PERSON'), ('vs.', 'O'), ('Wade', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('legitimatizing', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), (')', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('privacy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('free', 'O'), ('speech', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('freedom', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('religion', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('opposed', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('on', 'O'), ('grounds', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('insensitive', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('concerns', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('elderly', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('Equal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Employment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Opportunities', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1980s', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('fact', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('African-American', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('basis', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('avoiding', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('careful', 'O'), ('scrutiny', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Julius', 'PERSON'), ('L.', 'PERSON'), ('Chambers', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('NAACP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Legal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Defense', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Education', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Fund', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('While', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('Democrats', 'O'), ('immediately', 'O'), ('blasted', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('party', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('biggest', 'O'), ('guns', 'O'), ('held', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Majority', 'O'), ('Leader', 'O'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Mitchell', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Maine', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Edward', 'PERSON'), ('M.', 'PERSON'), ('Kennedy', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Mass.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('promised', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('thorough', 'O'), ('review', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Confirmation', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'", 'O'), ('August', 'O'), ('recess', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('43', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('strengthen', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('6-3', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('majority', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nine', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('An', 'O'), ('unabashed', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('succeed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('leading', 'O'), ('liberal', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('justice', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('rejected', 'O'), ('suggestions', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('chose', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('because', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('wanted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('keep', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('seat', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('kept', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('word', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('by', 'O'), ('picking', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('merits', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fact', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('minority', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('better', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('news', 'O'), ('conference', 'O'), ('outside', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('vacation', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Kennebunkport', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Maine', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Potential', 'O'), ('opponents', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nominee', 'O'), ('promised', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('statements', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ignore', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('race', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('examine', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('background', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Judge', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('mean', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('protecting', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('constitutional', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Simon', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Ill.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('When', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('EEOC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Reagan', 'PERSON'), ('administration', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('``', 'O'), ('seemed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('ways', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('weaken', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('basic', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('protections', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Simon', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('On', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('occasions', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('expressed', 'O'), ('objections', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('quotas', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('1985', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Federal', 'O'), ('enforcement', 'O'), ('agencies', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('turned', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('statutes', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('heads', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('requiring', 'O'), ('discrimination', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('form', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('hiring', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('promotion', 'O'), ('quotas', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('so-called', 'O'), ('goals', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('timetables', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('1987', 'O'), ('article', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Yale', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Law', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('&', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('amp', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Policy', 'O'), ('Review', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('referred', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('social', 'O'), ('engineering', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('vote', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('contribute', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('increasingly', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('anti-choice', 'O'), ('majority', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Alan', 'PERSON'), ('Cranston', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('D-Calif.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('looked', 'O'), ('forward', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('process', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('example', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('indeed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('hope', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('answer', 'O'), ('questions', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('WHAT', 'O'), ("'S", 'O'), ('NEXT', 'O'), ('?', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Now', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('nominated', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('step', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('September', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('August', 'O'), ('recess', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('After', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('committee', 'O'), ('makes', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('recommendation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('voted', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('full', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('promptly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('could', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('begins', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('October', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Source', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Mercury', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('News', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wire', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Services', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('CLARENCE', 'PERSON'), ('THOMAS', 'PERSON'), (';', 'O'), ('Born', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('23', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1948', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Pinpoint', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ga.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Education', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('B.A', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('from', 'O'), ('Holy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('College', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('1971', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('J.D', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('from', 'O'), ('Yale', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Law', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('School', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('1974.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Career', 'O'), (':', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1974-'77", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Missouri', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1977-'79", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Monsanto', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Co.', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1979-'81", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('legislative', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Danforth', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('R-Mo', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1981-'82", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Education', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ("1982-'90", 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Equal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Employment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Opportunity', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('1990-', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('U.S', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Circuit', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Appeals', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('for', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Columbia', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Source', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Who', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Who', 'O'), ('Among', 'O'), ('Black', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O')]]
