[[('Yet', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('matter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('weeks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('goes', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('as', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('nominee', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('join', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('increasingly', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('dramatic', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('philosophical', 'O'), ('transformation', 'O'), ('reveals', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('Horatio', 'PERSON'), ('Alger', 'PERSON'), ('journey', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('rural', 'O'), ('Southern', 'O'), ('poverty', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('nomination', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('To', 'O'), ('friends', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('story', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('courage', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('foes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('story', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('opportunism', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Racial', 'O'), ('anger', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('protest', 'O'), ('lyrics', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('homespun', 'O'), ('homilies', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('grandfather', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ruler-slapping', 'O'), ('discipline', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nuns', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('taught', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Catholic', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('segregated', 'O'), ('Savannah', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ga.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('anger', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('writings', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('Wright', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Malcolm', 'PERSON'), ('X', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('iconoclastic', 'O'), ('theories', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('academicians', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('Sowell', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('Barclay', 'PERSON'), ('Allen', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('protest', 'O'), ('lyrics', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('singer-songwriter', 'O'), ('Nina', 'PERSON'), ('Simone', 'PERSON'), ('--', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('story', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('glimpsed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('dozens', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('interviews', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('tens', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('pages', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('documents', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Judiciary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('influences', 'O'), ('helped', 'O'), ('shape', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('beliefs', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('subject', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('bitter', 'O'), ('controversy', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('takes', 'O'), ('immense', 'O'), ('pride', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('staked', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('independent', 'O'), ('course', 'O'), ('despite', 'O'), ('suffering', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('heavy', 'O'), ('personal', 'O'), ('toll', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('lost', 'O'), ('friends', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('condemnation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Black', 'O'), ("'intellectual", 'O'), ('clones', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('refuse', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('submit', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('racially', 'O'), ('derogatory', 'O'), ('orthodoxy', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('share', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('opinion', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('busing', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('believe', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('racist', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('act', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('intellectual', 'O'), ('clones', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('1984', 'O'), ('speech', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('students', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Yale', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Law', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('School', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('earned', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('degree', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('underscores', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('role', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('minority', 'O'), ('figure', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('minority', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('repeatedly', 'O'), ('quoting', 'O'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Frost', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('poetic', 'O'), ('recollection', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Two', 'O'), ('roads', 'O'), ('diverged', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wood', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('traveled', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('difference', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Even', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('friends', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('trouble', 'O'), ('explaining', 'O'), ('why', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('took', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('different', 'O'), ('road', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('youth', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('shared', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('liberal', 'O'), ('attitudes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('bright', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('born', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('segregated', 'O'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('age', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('freedom', 'O'), ('rides', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('lunch', 'O'), ('room', 'O'), ('sit-ins', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1964', 'O'), ('Civil', 'O'), ('Rights', 'O'), ('Act', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('erasing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('overt', 'O'), ('signs', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('discrimination', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Holy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('student', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('turbulent', 'O'), ('1960s', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('joined', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('wore', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('beret', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('leather', 'O'), ('jacket', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('decorated', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('dormitory', 'O'), ('room', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('poster', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Malcolm', 'PERSON'), ('X.', 'PERSON'), (';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('came', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('college', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('wrongheaded', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('His', 'O'), ('rightward', 'O'), ('shift', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('account', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('circling', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('values', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Yale', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('law', 'O'), ('student', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('1971', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('1974.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('admitted', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('affirmative', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('program', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('gotten', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Friend', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('view', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Whatever', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('reasons', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('classmates', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('faculty', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Yale', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('are', 'O'), ('unable', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('pinpoint', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('particular', 'O'), ('turning', 'O'), ('points', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('pivotal', 'O'), ('events', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('``', 'O'), ('became', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('process', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Harry', 'PERSON'), ('Singleton', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('friend', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('By', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('arrived', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Jefferson', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mo.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1974', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Danforth', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('supporter', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Republican', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('attitudes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('largely', 'O'), ('formed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('His', 'O'), ('philosophy', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('felt', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('affording', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('opportunities', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('willing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('rely', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nature', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('servitude', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('lawyer', 'O'), ('Harvey', 'PERSON'), ('Tettlebaum', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('worked', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Several', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('captured', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Reagan', 'PERSON'), ('transition', 'O'), ('team', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('offered', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('reluctant', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('friends', 'O'), ('urged', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('shun', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('rare', 'O'), ('opportunity', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('policy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('accepted', 'O'), ('successive', 'O'), ('jobs', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Equal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Employment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Opportunity', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('colorblind', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('jobs', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('began', 'O'), ('questioning', 'O'), ('preferences', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('jobs', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('historically', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('discrimination', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Later', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('openly', 'O'), ('opposing', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('preferences', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('denouncing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('decisions', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('upheld', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('calling', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('colorblind', 'O'), ('Constitution', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Some', 'O'), ('critics', 'O'), ('cynically', 'O'), ('attribute', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('ideological', 'O'), ('metamorphosis', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('opportunism', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('interviewed', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('nomination', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('responded', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('offered', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('explanation', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('change', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('heart', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('handwritten', 'O'), ('notes', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('files', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('recalled', 'O'), ('telling', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('Democratic', 'O'), ('grandparents', 'O'), ('why', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('Republican', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('You', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('Republican', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('incredulous', 'O'), ('grandparents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Remember', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('when', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('beg', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('myself', 'O'), ('?', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('Remember', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('ever', 'O'), ('amounted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('anything', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sweat', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('MY', 'O'), ('brow', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('MY', 'O'), ('elbow', 'O'), ('grease', 'O'), ('?', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('And', 'O'), ('remember', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('rather', 'O'), ('starve', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('anyone', 'O'), ('give', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('something', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('?', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('Politically', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('choice', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('party', 'O'), ('openly', 'O'), ('standing', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('values', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Republican', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Party', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
