[[('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('brother', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Their', 'O'), ('sister', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('reared', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('aunt', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('43', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('credits', 'O'), ('everything', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('achieved', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('grandparents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('choked', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('twice', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('mentioned', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('hostile', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('taught', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('rely', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('himself', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('shaped', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('individualism', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('race', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('society', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('guide', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('raised', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('survive', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('totalitarianism', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('segregation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('wrote', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('paper', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Heritage', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Foundation', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('policy', 'O'), ('institute', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('raised', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('survive', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('spite', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dark', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('oppressive', 'O'), ('cloud', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('governmentally', 'O'), ('sanctioned', 'O'), ('bigotry', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Self-sufficiency', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('security', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Self-sufficiency', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('spiritual', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('emotional', 'O'), ('security', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('tools', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('carve', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('secure', 'O'), ('freedom', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('added', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Those', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('attempt', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('capture', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('daily', 'O'), ('counseling', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('oversight', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('common', 'O'), ('sense', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('vision', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('grandparents', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('governmental', 'O'), ('program', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('engaging', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('sheer', 'O'), ('folly', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('beliefs', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('brought', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('steps', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('make', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('suspect', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('veterans', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('struggle', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('accountable', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wrongs', 'O'), ('done', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Yet', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Washington', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Post', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('journalist', 'O'), ('Juan', 'PERSON'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('pointed', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('firmly', 'O'), ('grounded', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('intellectual', 'O'), ('tradition', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Booker', 'PERSON'), ('T.', 'PERSON'), ('Washington', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('advocated', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('self-reliance', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('mutual', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('principal', 'O'), ('means', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('advancement', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('born', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('23', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1948', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Pinpoint', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ga.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('marshes', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Savannah', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('mother', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Leola', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('18', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('lived', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('plumbing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Before', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('birthday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('father', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('North', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('family', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('mother', 'O'), ('remarried', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('husband', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('marriage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Taken', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('grandparents', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('At', 'O'), ('age', 'O'), ('7', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('live', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('grandparents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('grandfather', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Myers', 'PERSON'), ('Anderson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('formal', 'O'), ('schooling', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('life', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('taught', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('He', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('barely', 'O'), ('read', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('write', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('read', 'O'), ('enough', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('read', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bible', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('1983', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Washington', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Post', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tough', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('He', 'O'), ('elaborated', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Heritage', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Foundation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('paper', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Of', 'O'), ('course', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('grandparents', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), ('rigid', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('expectations', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('mean', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('compassionate', 'O'), ('thing', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('teach', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fend', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('ourselves', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('hostile', 'O'), ('environment', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('lay', 'O'), ('beyond', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('confines', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('poverty', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('segregation', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('totally', 'O'), ('closed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('grandfather', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Catholic', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('enrolled', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('all-black', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('run', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('church', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('also', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('sure', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('thank', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nuns', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('wanted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('priest', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('1967', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('accepted', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('all-white', 'O'), ('Immaculate', 'O'), ('Conception', 'O'), ('Seminary', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Conception', 'O'), ('Junction', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mo', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('shock', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Other', 'O'), ('seminarians', 'O'), ('referred', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('spot', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('horse', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Disgusted', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('end', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Flirts', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ("'black", 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('went', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('attend', 'O'), ('Holy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Worcester', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mass', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1960s', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('flirted', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('politics', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('considered', 'O'), ('himself', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('follower', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Malcolm', 'PERSON'), ('X', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('true', 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('degree', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Yale', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1974.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('lawyer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('worked', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Missouri', 'LOCATION'), ('Attorney', 'O'), ('General', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('C.', 'PERSON'), ('Danforth', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('joined', 'O'), ('Monsanto', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Co.', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('introduction', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('came', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1979', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('By', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Danforth', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Republican', 'O'), ('senator', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Thomas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('Democrat', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('joined', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('legislative', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('1982', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('named', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Reagan', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('lead', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Equal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Employment', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Opportunity', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('His', 'O'), ('tenure', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('investigates', 'O'), ('discrimination', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('controversial', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Critics', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('agency', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('soft', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Abandoning', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('hiring', 'O'), ('goals', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('timetables', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('focused', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('resolving', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('individual', 'O'), ('discrimination', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('credit', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('improving', 'O'), ('efficiency', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('When', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('nominated', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Appeals', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('for', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('the', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('District', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Columbia', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('steppingstone', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('contentious', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('process', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('forecast', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('smoothly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('perhaps', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Reagan', 'PERSON'), ('administration', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('outspoken', 'O'), ('critics', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('seat', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('appeals', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), ('1990.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Thomas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('lives', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('suburban', 'O'), ('Virginia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('married', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('life', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ('could', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
