[[('A', 'O'), ('top', 'O'), ('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fiery', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('jet', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('further', 'O'), ('erode', 'O'), ('popular', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('defense', 'O'), ('programs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Remscheid', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('brigade', 'O'), ('leader', 'O'), ('Berthold', 'PERSON'), ('Hoehler', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('body', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('construction', 'O'), ('worker', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('pulled', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('rubble', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('raisng', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), ('toll', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Seven', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('hurt', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('remained', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('critical', 'O'), ('condition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Later', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('4,000', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('torchlight', 'O'), ('vigil', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('procession', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('downtown', 'O'), ('Remscheid', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('remember', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('victims', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('demand', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('end', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('low-level', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('missions', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('Thunderbolt', 'O'), ('II', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('tore', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('swath', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('destruction', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('working-class', 'O'), ('neighborhood', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('central', 'O'), ('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Remscheid', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rescue', 'O'), ('workers', 'O'), ('continued', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('comb', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('debris', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('crews', 'O'), ('tore', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('remains', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('demolished', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Welt', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('am', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sonntag', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('newspaper', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('inspector', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('certain', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('impact', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('sinking', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('defense', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('difficult', 'O'), ('psychological', 'O'), ('situation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Dieter', 'PERSON'), ('Wellershoff', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('quoted', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Wellershoff', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('referring', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('polls', 'O'), ('indicating', 'O'), ('dwindling', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('defense', 'O'), ('spending', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('increasing', 'O'), ('dissatisfaction', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('disruptive', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('often', 'O'), ('deadly', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('maneuvers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('am', 'O'), ('alarmed', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('West', 'O'), ('Germans', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('lost', 'O'), ('sight', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hard', 'O'), ('facts', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('defense', 'O'), ('realities', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('hopes', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('continued', 'O'), ('peace', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('hinge', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('NATO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('security', 'O'), ('preparedness', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('staunch', 'O'), ('NATO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('ally', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('borders', 'O'), ('East', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Czechoslovakia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('thus', 'O'), ('putting', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('East-West', 'O'), ('struggle', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Wellershoff', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('comments', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('appear', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('newspaper', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Sunday', 'O'), ('editions', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('text', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('telexed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('advance', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('news', 'O'), ('media', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('skies', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('crowded', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('hundreds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('jets', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('helicopters', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('series', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('deadly', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('fueled', 'O'), ('growing', 'O'), ('calls', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('halt', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('drastic', 'O'), ('reductions', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('low-level', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Even', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('fatal', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('95', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('alone', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('included', 'O'), ('70', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('base', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('August', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Following', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Remscheid', 'LOCATION'), ('crash', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('temporary', 'O'), ('suspensions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('low-level', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('missions', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('inadvertently', 'O'), ('flew', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('attempting', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('join', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('formation', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('statement', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('quoting', 'O'), ('Maj.', 'O'), ('Gen.', 'O'), ('Marcus', 'PERSON'), ('A.', 'PERSON'), ('Anderson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('initiated', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('separation', 'O'), ('maneuver', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('normal', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('formation', 'O'), ('lose', 'O'), ('visual', 'O'), ('contact', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lead', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('climbed', 'O'), ('above', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('continued', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('descent', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('why', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Anderson', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('speculated', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('disoriented', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('tried', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('climb', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('bad', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Witnesses', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('engines', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
