[[('A', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('attack', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('burned', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), ('this', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('routine', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Pentagon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('ejected', 'O'), ('safely', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Thunderbolt', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Europe', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('weeks', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Another', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('Dec.', 'O'), ('8', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Tracy', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ariz.', 'LOCATION'), ('Dan', 'PERSON'), ('Howard', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pentagon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('originally', 'O'), ('identified', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('81st', 'O'), ('Tactical', 'O'), ('Fighter', 'O'), ('Wing', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('RAF', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bentwaters', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('England', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('later', 'O'), ('corrected', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('assigned', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('10th', 'O'), ('Tactical', 'O'), ('Fighter', 'O'), ('Wing', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('RAF', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alconbury', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Howard', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('9:53', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('EST', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('St.', 'LOCATION'), ('Ives', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Cambridge', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('ejected', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('chute', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('sighted', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('status', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Howard', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('carrying', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('dummy', 'O'), ('bombs', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('practice', 'O'), ('33mm', 'O'), ('ammunition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('twin-engine', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('designed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('troops', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('enemy', 'O'), ('tanks', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('targets', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('older', 'O'), ('model', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('designed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('highly', 'O'), ('maneuverable', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('low', 'O'), ('speeds', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('low', 'O'), ('altitude', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('carry', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('bombs', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('ammunition', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Thunderbolt', 'O'), ('II', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('safest', 'O'), ('planes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('statistically', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('inventory', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Nonetheless', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('comes', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('weeks', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('slammed', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Remscheid', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('dozens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('prompted', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('NATO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('allies', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('agree', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('suspend', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('until', 'O'), ('Jan.', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('suspension', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('parties', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('increased', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('demands', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('end', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('low-level', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Remscheid', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('heart', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Tohono', 'O'), ("O'Odham", 'O'), ('Indian', 'O'), ('Reservation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('80', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Tuscon', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('ejected', 'O'), ('safely', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Howard', 'PERSON'), ('refused', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('discuss', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('England', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pentagon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('awaiting', 'O'), ('initial', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('scene', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('survived', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Thunderbolt', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('flew', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1975', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('became', 'O'), ('operational', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1977', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('longer', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('production', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('700', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('inventory', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Statistically', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('safest', 'O'), ('fighter', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('attack', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('currently', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('inventory', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('chalked', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('rate', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('4', 'O'), ('Class', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('mishaps', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('flying', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('lifetime', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('consists', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('1.75', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('Class', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('mishap', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('either', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fatality', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('exceeding', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('500,000', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('describes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('A-10', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('simple', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('effective', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('survivable', 'O'), ('twin-engine', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('targets', 'O'), ('...', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('excellent', 'O'), ('maneuverability', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('low', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('speeds', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('altitude', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('highly', 'O'), ('accurate', 'O'), ('weapons', 'O'), ('delivery', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
