[[('Two', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('F-16', 'O'), ('fighter', 'O'), ('jets', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('exploded', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('F-16', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Black', 'LOCATION'), ('Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('in-flight', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Gail', 'PERSON'), ('Hayes', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('mission', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Bodenheim', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mainz', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('She', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('assigned', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('50th', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tactical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Fighter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wing', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('at', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hahn', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Base', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('1:30', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ('aboard', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('condition', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('board', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('unknown', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Ms.', 'O'), ('Hayes', 'PERSON'), ('told', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Associated', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Press', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('telephone', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('European', 'O'), ('headquarters', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('Hugo', 'PERSON'), ('Lenxweiler', 'PERSON'), ('told', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('AP', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('telephone', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilots', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('able', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('eject', 'O'), ('safely', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Lenxweiler', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Lenxweiler', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('ejected', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Identities', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilots', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('immediately', 'O'), ('released', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('planes', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('hundred', 'O'), ('yards', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('populated', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('hurt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('preliminary', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('indicated', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('F-16s', 'O'), ('rammed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Both', 'O'), ('planes', 'O'), ('exploded', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('impact', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('90', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Air', 'O'), ('Force', 'O'), ('Spokesman', 'O'), ('1st', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Al', 'PERSON'), ('Sattler', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Black', 'LOCATION'), ('Forest', 'LOCATION'), ('crash', 'O'), ('ejected', 'O'), ('safely', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('examined', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Karlsruhe', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('noon', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('6', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('EDT', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('village', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Marxzell-Burbach', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Sattler', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('52nd', 'O'), ('Tactical', 'O'), ('Fighter', 'O'), ('Wing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('stationed', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Spangdahlen', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('NATO', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('tactical', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('exercise', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('conducted', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Canadian', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Baden-Soellingen', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Sattler', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('personnel', 'O'), ('secured', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crashes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('teams', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('experts', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('sites', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('determine', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crashes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
