[[('A', 'O'), ('B-52', 'O'), ('bomber', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('burst', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('flames', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('runway', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('practicing', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('touch-and-go', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('landings', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('K.I', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Sawyer', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Force', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('All', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('survived', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('normally', 'O'), ('equipped', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('carry', 'O'), ('nuclear', 'O'), ('bombs', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('1:15', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Naomi', 'PERSON'), ('Siegal', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Strategic', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Command', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('installation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('weapons', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('aboard', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Col.', 'O'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Peck', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('SAC', 'O'), ('headquarters', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Omaha', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Neb', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('practicing', 'O'), ('landings', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('seven-hour', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('touch-and-go', 'O'), ('approaches', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Peck', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('During', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('maneuvers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('landing', 'O'), ('gears', 'O'), ('touch', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('land', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('All', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('sections', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('burned', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('impact', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Senior', 'O'), ('Airman', 'O'), ('Tim', 'PERSON'), ('Sanders', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('crawled', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('helped', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('section', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Marquette', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('General', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('hospitals', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('broken', 'O'), ('bones', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('burned', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Bicking', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('Sawyer', 'PERSON'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Senior', 'O'), ('Airman', 'O'), ('Tim', 'PERSON'), ('Sanders', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('aboard', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mark', 'PERSON'), ('Hartney', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('29', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('commander', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Mulberry', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Fla.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('1st', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('S.', 'PERSON'), ('Debruzzi', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('26', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Brighton', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Minn.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Anthony', 'PERSON'), ('D.', 'PERSON'), ('Phillips', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('28', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('radar', 'O'), ('navigator', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Folkston', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ga.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('1st', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('James', 'PERSON'), ('W.', 'PERSON'), ('Herrmann', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('30', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('navigator', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Sharpsville', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Pa.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('1st', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Daniel', 'PERSON'), ('McCarrick', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('electronic', 'O'), ('warfare', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Succasunna', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('N.J.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Airman', 'O'), ('1st', 'O'), ('Class', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Joseph', 'PERSON'), ('A.', 'PERSON'), ('Vallie', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('gunner', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Stephenson', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mich.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Maj.', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('R.', 'PERSON'), ('Kroeger', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('52', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('instructor', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Fountain', 'LOCATION'), ('Hills', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ariz.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('1st', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Gregory', 'PERSON'), ('C.', 'PERSON'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('26', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('upgrade', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Henning', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Minn.', 'LOCATION'), ('All', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Sawyer', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Ann', 'PERSON'), ('Parent', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Marquette', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('General', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hospital', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Hartney', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Debruzzi', 'PERSON'), ('were', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('fair', 'O'), ('condition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Phillips', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Vallie', 'PERSON'), ('were', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('stable', 'O'), ('condition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('McCarrick', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('satisfactory', 'O'), ('condition', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Kroeger', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('condition', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Herrmann', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), ('were', 'O'), ('listed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('stable', 'O'), ('condition', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('hospital', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Technical', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Anita', 'PERSON'), ('Bailey', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Hartney', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('commander', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('Debruzzi', 'PERSON'), ('also', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('qualified', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fly', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Bailey', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('She', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('controls', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('counting', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('blessings', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Bailey', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('You', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('together', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('together', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('classified', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('kind', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('exercises', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Sawyer', 'PERSON'), ('were', 'O'), ('canceled', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), ('runways', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('remained', 'O'), ('open', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Bailey', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Peck', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('board', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('investigate', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('adding', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('appear', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('factor', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Peck', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('unusual', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('B-52', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('missions', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Crews', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('trained', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fly', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('eight-engine', 'O'), ('B-52', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('deployed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('1950s', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('biggest', 'O'), ('bomber', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wingspan', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('185', 'O'), ('feet', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('maximum', 'O'), ('takeoff', 'O'), ('weight', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('488,000', 'O'), ('pounds', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('B-52', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('commissioned', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1962', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('involving', 'O'), ('B-52s', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bomber', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('aborted', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('takeoff', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('overshot', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('runway', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Castle', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Force', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('central', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Feb.', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('B-52', 'O'), ('bomber', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('radar', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ("Arizona'a", 'LOCATION'), ('Monument', 'LOCATION'), ('Valley', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('October', 'O'), ('1984', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('wings', 'O'), ('clipped', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('mesa', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('trouble', 'O'), ('recently', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('B-52', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('successor', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('B-1B', 'O'), ('bomber', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('smaller', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('B-52', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('B-1B', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('fly', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('supersonic', 'O'), ('speeds', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('carry', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('bombs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Four', 'O'), ('B-1Bs', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('flying', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('nine', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('apart', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('November', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('One', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('280', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('B-1Bs', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('smashing', 'O'), ('onto', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('runway', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Ellsworth', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Force', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('S.D.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Nov.', 'O'), ('17', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('Nov.', 'O'), ('8', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('B-1B', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('burned', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('field', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Dyess', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Force', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('either', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('investigators', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('disclosed', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Six', 'O'), ('crewmen', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('Oct.', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('tanker', 'O'), ('en', 'O'), ('route', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('K.I', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Sawyer', 'PERSON'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Wurtsmith', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Force', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('near', 'O'), ('Oscoda', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('incomplete', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Wurtsmith', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Sawyer', 'PERSON'), ('are', 'O'), ('Michigan', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('SAC', 'O'), ('bases', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
