[[('Coast', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Guard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('vessels', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('searched', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('crewman', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('F-14', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('fighter', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('plunged', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Atlantic', 'LOCATION'), ('Ocean', 'LOCATION'), ('off', 'O'), ('North', 'LOCATION'), ('Carolina', 'LOCATION'), ('while', 'O'), ('practicing', 'O'), ('combat', 'O'), ('maneuvers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('crewmate', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Six', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('F-14', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('aviators', 'O'), ('bailed', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('airfield', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Diego', 'LOCATION'), ('suburb', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('El', 'LOCATION'), ('Cajon', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('sending', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('smashing', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('hangar', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Utah', 'LOCATION'), ('escaped', 'O'), ('injury', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('third', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('Hatteras', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('N.C.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('afternoon', 'O'), ('22', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('east', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Oregon', 'LOCATION'), ('Inlet', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('fishing', 'O'), ('boat', 'O'), ('picked', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('crewman', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('pronounced', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('identity', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('aviator', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('crewmate', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('released', 'O'), ('pending', 'O'), ('notification', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('relatives', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Five', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('fliers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('remained', 'O'), ('hospitalized', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('following', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('El', 'LOCATION'), ('Cajon', 'LOCATION'), ('15', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('east', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Diego', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('35', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('upside', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('hangars', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Gillespie', 'LOCATION'), ('Field', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('exploded', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('blaze', 'O'), ('ignited', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('hangar', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('attached', 'O'), ('extension', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('spared', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('nearby', 'O'), ('restaurant', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('crewman', 'O'), ('tried', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('guide', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('runway', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Gillespie', 'LOCATION'), ('Field', 'LOCATION'), ('before', 'O'), ('bailing', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Gary', 'PERSON'), ('Hughes', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('commanding', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Naval', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Station', 'LOCATION'), ('Miramar', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('grateful', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('particularly', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('El', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cajon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('populated', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('passed', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('mile', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('elementary', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('tricks', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('parachutes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Washington', 'PERSON'), ('Moscuso', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sixth-grader', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Ballantyne', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elementary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('School', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Atlantic', 'LOCATION'), ('accident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Cmdr', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mike', 'PERSON'), ('John', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Atlantic', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Fleet', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Norfolk', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Va.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('engaged', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('mock', 'O'), ('dogfights', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('F-14', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('A-4', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('restricted', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('airspace', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('North', 'LOCATION'), ('Carolina', 'LOCATION'), ('coast', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('flying', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('routine', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('mission', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('determined', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('sank', 'O'), ('soon', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('impact', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('twin-engine', 'O'), ('supersonic', 'O'), ('fighter', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('attached', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Fighter', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Squadron', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('143', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('at', 'O'), ('Oceana', 'LOCATION'), ('Naval', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Station', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Virginia', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Va', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('northern', 'O'), ('Utah', 'LOCATION'), ('today', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('F-16A', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('fighter', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Hill', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Force', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('bailed', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('assigned', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Hill', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('388th', 'O'), ('Tactical', 'O'), ('Fighter', 'O'), ('Wing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('routine', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('mission', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Spokeswoman', 'O'), ('Silvia', 'PERSON'), ('Le', 'PERSON'), ('Mons-Liddle', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('9:05', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('MDT', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('She', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('site', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Promontory', 'LOCATION'), ('Mountains', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('peninsula', 'O'), ('jutting', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Great', 'LOCATION'), ('Salt', 'LOCATION'), ('Lake', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('specific', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
