[[('Nine', 'O'), ('reservists', 'O'), ('helping', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('buildup', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Persian', 'LOCATION'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('were', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('13', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('cargo', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('huge', 'O'), ('C-5A', 'O'), ('transport', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nearly', 'O'), ('3-week-old', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('round-the-clock', 'O'), ('deployment', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('personnel', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('equipment', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('gulf', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('speculate', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('mishap', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Brig', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Gen.', 'O'), ('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('Swope', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('316th', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Division', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('indication', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Four', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('17', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('aboard', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cargo', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('massive', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('tumbled', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('field', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('stopover', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('bound', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('gulf', 'O'), ('region', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('bound', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Frankfurt', 'LOCATION'), ('carrying', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('supplies', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('food', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('maintenance', 'O'), ('equipment', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('troops', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Saudi', 'LOCATION'), ('Arabia', 'LOCATION'), ('following', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Aug.', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('Iraqi', 'O'), ('invasion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Kuwait', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Late', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('released', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('names', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('victims', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('hometowns', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('listed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Nine', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reservists', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('433rd', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Military', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Airlift', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Wing', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('from', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Kelly', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Base', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Antonio', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('stationed', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), ('or', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('nearby', 'O'), ('Hahn', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Listed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('433rd', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('Maj.', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('M.', 'PERSON'), ('Gordon', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Maj.', 'O'), ('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('W.', 'PERSON'), ('Chase', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rosendo', 'PERSON'), ('Herrera', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('engineer', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Carpio', 'PERSON'), ('Villarreal', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('engineer', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Daniel', 'PERSON'), ('G.', 'PERSON'), ('Perez', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('loadmaster', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Edward', 'PERSON'), ('E.', 'PERSON'), ('Sheffield', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('loadmaster', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Maj.', 'O'), ('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('M.', 'PERSON'), ('Price', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Lonty', 'PERSON'), ('A.', 'PERSON'), ('Knutson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Daniel', 'PERSON'), ('Garza', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Bradley', 'PERSON'), ('Schuldt', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rande', 'PERSON'), ('Hulec', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('sergeants', 'O'), ('Samuel', 'PERSON'), ('Gardner', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Marc', 'PERSON'), ('Cleyman', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('Hahn', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Listed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Col.', 'O'), ('Frederick', 'PERSON'), ('Arzt', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dwight', 'PERSON'), ('Pettit', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('McChord', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('state', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Cynthia', 'PERSON'), ('Borecky', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('England', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Lorenzo', 'PERSON'), ('Galvan', 'PERSON'), ('Jr.', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('433rd', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('hospitalized', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('satisfactory', 'O'), ('condition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rourk', 'PERSON'), ('Sheehan', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Landstuhl', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Army', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('hospital', 'O'), ('nearby', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('433rd', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('active', 'O'), ('duty', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('reservists', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wing', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('voluntarily', 'O'), ('participating', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Desert', 'O'), ('Shield', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('arranging', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('civilian', 'O'), ('jobs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('60th', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Military', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Airlift', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Squadron', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('from', 'O'), ('Travis', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Base', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('en', 'O'), ('route', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Rhein-Mein', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('near', 'O'), ('Frankfurt', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), ('air', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('12:30', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('clipped', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tops', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('crashing', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('breaking', 'O'), ('apart', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Twisted', 'O'), ('chunks', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('wings', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('landing', 'O'), ('gear', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('fuselage', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('debris', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('scattered', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Firefighters', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('dousing', 'O'), ('smoldering', 'O'), ('sections', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('wreckage', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('hazy', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('visibility', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('mile', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Swope', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('uncommon', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('C-5', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Miesau', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('removing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cache', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('chemical', 'O'), ('weapons', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('agreement', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('West', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('Defense', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ministry', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('posed', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('danger', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('operation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('largest', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('base', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Europe', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('90', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Frankfurt', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('C-5', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('largest', 'O'), ('transport', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('fleet', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('costs', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('148', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('C-5', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('4', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1975', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('C-5B', 'O'), ('carrying', 'O'), ('Vietnamese', 'O'), ('orphans', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('shortly', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('takeoff', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Saigon', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('172', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('anniversary', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('collision', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Ramstein', 'LOCATION'), ('which', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('70', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
