[[('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('war', 'O'), ('planes', 'O'), ('participating', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Desert', 'O'), ('Shield', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('flying', 'O'), ('again', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('grounded', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('24', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('following', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('rash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('crashes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Pentagon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('regular', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('schedules', 'O'), ('resumed', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('noon', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('5', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('EDT', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('account', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('majority', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('air', 'O'), ('missions', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Persian', 'LOCATION'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('region', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('``', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('changed', 'O'), ('anything', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('operations', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suspension', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A.C.', 'PERSON'), ('Roper', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Central', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Command', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Saudi', 'LOCATION'), ('Arabia', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('wanted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('examine', 'O'), ('potential', 'O'), ('hazards', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('sure', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('everything', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prevent', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('identified', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('common', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('common', 'O'), ('contributing', 'O'), ('factors', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('added', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pentagon', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('Pete', 'PERSON'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('gulf', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('separate', 'O'), ('crashes', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ordinary', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('suspension', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('indicated', 'O'), ('otherwise', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('gave', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('pilots', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('gulf', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('safety', 'O'), ('awareness', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('briefings', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('order', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('review', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('need', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fly', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('safely', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Aircraft', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('operational', 'O'), ('missions', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('grounded', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Col.', 'O'), ('Miguel', 'PERSON'), ('Monteverde', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('Pentagon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Those', 'O'), ('included', 'O'), ('reconnaissance', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('refueling', 'O'), ('tanker', 'O'), ('planes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('F-15', 'O'), ('jets', 'O'), ('patrolling', 'O'), ('areas', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Kuwait', 'LOCATION'), ('or', 'O'), ('Iraqi', 'O'), ('borders', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('pilots', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('planes', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('safety', 'O'), ('briefings', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('schedules', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('changed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('So', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('degradation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('ability', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('defend', 'O'), ('ourselves', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Monteverde', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Desert', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Shield', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('largest', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('buildup', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'O'), ('War', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('involves', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('700', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('combat', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Desert', 'LOCATION'), ('Shield', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('classified', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('disclosed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('compare', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('rate', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('previous', 'O'), ('deployments', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('toll', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('accidental', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Desert', 'O'), ('Shield', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('rose', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('31', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('F-111', 'O'), ('fighter-bomber', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('mission', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Saudi', 'LOCATION'), ('Arabia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('pilots', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('F-4', 'O'), ('Phantom', 'O'), ('reconnaissance', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Saudi', 'LOCATION'), ('Arabia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('Marine', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('UH-1', 'O'), ('Huey', 'O'), ('helicopters', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('carrying', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Arabian', 'LOCATION'), ('Sea', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('service', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('measures', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('review', 'O'), ('safety', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('gulf', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('concerned', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('concerned', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('happened', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('short', 'O'), ('period', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('reporters', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('safety', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Desert', 'LOCATION'), ('Shield', 'LOCATION'), ('remained', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Given', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('amount', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('flying', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('done', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('extraordinary', 'O'), ('circumstances', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('higher', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('ordinary', 'O'), ('operating', 'O'), ('tempo', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('service', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('concern', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Five', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('fatal', 'O'), ('crashes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('gulf', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('start', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Desert', 'O'), ('Shield', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('F-111', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('F-4', 'O'), ('Phantom', 'O'), ('reconnaissance', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('F-15E', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('Marine', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('UH-1', 'O'), ('Huey', 'O'), ('helicopters', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('C-5', 'O'), ('transport', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('while', 'O'), ('ferrying', 'O'), ('equipment', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Saudi', 'LOCATION'), ('Arabia', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('non-fatal', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('gulf', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fifteen', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('helicopters', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
