[[('A', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('F-111', 'O'), ('fighter-bomber', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Saudi', 'LOCATION'), ('Arabia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fourth', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('deployed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('kingdom', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Desert', 'O'), ('Shield', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Eight', 'O'), ('Marines', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('helicopters', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('northern', 'O'), ('Arabian', 'LOCATION'), ('Sea', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('An', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('F-4', 'O'), ('reconnaissance', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Lt.', 'O'), ('Cmdr', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('J.D', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('van', 'PERSON'), ('Sickle', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('F-111', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Arabian', 'O'), ('peninsula', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('mission', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('names', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('flyers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('withheld', 'O'), ('pending', 'O'), ('notification', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('kin', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('attached', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('48th', 'O'), ('Tactical', 'O'), ('Fighter', 'O'), ('Wing', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('RAF', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lakenheath', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('wing', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Turkey', 'LOCATION'), ('as', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('forces', 'O'), ('massed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('region', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('response', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Iraq', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Aug.', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('takeover', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Kuwait', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Today', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('brought', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('nine', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Persian', 'LOCATION'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('region', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Desert', 'O'), ('Shield', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('Marines', 'O'), ('aboard', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('UH-1', 'O'), ('Huey', 'O'), ('helicopters', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('vanished', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('officially', 'O'), ('listed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('addition', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Saudi', 'LOCATION'), ('Arabia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('13', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('personnel', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('C-5', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('cargo', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('ferrying', 'O'), ('supplies', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('equipment', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Saudi', 'O'), ('peninsula', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('F-111', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('dawn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('F-model', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('latest', 'O'), ('version', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('23-year-old', 'O'), ('swing-wing', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('F-model', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('powerful', 'O'), ('engines', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('state-of-the-art', 'O'), ('equipment', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('operate', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('enemy', 'O'), ('targets', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('carry', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('tons', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('bombs', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('missiles', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('weapons', 'O'), ('systems', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
