[[('BFN', 'O'), ('[', 'O'), ('Text', 'O'), (']', 'O'), ('Tokyo', 'LOCATION'), ('--', 'O'), ('An', 'O'), ('F-15', 'O'), ('fighter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Forces', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Okinawa', 'LOCATION'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Kadena', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('4', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Commenting', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Akira', 'PERSON'), ('Takeshita', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('deputy', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Defense', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Facilities', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Administration', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('[', 'O'), ('DFAA', 'O'), (']', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Such', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('regrettable', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('actually', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('shortly', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('DFAA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('asked', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('command', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Forces', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Japan', 'LOCATION'), ('[', 'O'), ('USFJ', 'O'), (']', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('thorough', 'O'), ('measures', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('safe', 'O'), ('management', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('bases', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Okinawa', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('conduct', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('thorough', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Kadena', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('public', 'O'), ('affairs', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('gave', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('briefing', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('DFAA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('released', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('briefing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('briefing', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('An', 'O'), ('F-15', 'O'), ('fighter', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Kadena', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('routine', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('0924', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('4', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('belonged', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('44th', 'O'), ('Fighter', 'O'), ('Squadron', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('18th', 'O'), ('Wing', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('safely', 'O'), ('ejected', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('team', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('investigating', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('details', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('once', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('completed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('800', 'O'), ('meters', 'O'), ('northeast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Kadena', 'LOCATION'), ('Air', 'LOCATION'), ('Base', 'LOCATION'), ('runway', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('site', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('facilities', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr.', 'O'), ('Takeshita', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('safe', 'O'), ('management', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('bases', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Okinawa', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('asked', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('side', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('DFAA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('immediately', 'O'), ('expressed', 'O'), ('regret', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('command', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Forces', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Yokota', 'PERSON'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Naha', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('DFAA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Bureau', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('expressed', 'O'), ('regret', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commander', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Forces', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Okinawa', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('We', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('continue', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ask', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('safe', 'O'), ('management', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('military', 'O'), ('bases', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Japan', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
