[[('A', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('trainer', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('Sunday', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('deck', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('carrier', 'O'), ('Lexington', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('damaging', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two-seat', 'O'), ('T-2', 'O'), ('Buckeye', 'LOCATION'), ('caused', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('fires', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('World', 'O'), ('War', 'O'), ('II-era', 'O'), ('ship', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('sailors', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('brought', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('control', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Cmdr', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dennis', 'PERSON'), ('Hessler', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('naval', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Pensacola', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('landing', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('unclear', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('aboard', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('deck', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('minor', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Pentagon', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Lexington', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('oldest', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('carrier', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('17', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('port', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Pensacola', 'LOCATION'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Coast', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Guard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lt.', 'O'), ('Mark', 'PERSON'), ('Kasper', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Orleans', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('assigned', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Training', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Squadron', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('19', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Meridian', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Miss.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Naval', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Station', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('victims', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('identities', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('withheld', 'O'), ('pending', 'O'), ('notification', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('kin', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('helicopters', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('hospitals', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Kasper', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('burn', 'O'), ('victim', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('South', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alabama', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Medical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Mobile', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Kasper', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Coast', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Guard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('sent', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Mobile', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fly', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('team', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('ordnance', 'O'), ('experts', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Panama', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Pensacola', 'LOCATION'), ('because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('apparently', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('concerned', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('fuel', 'O'), ('cells', 'O'), ('aboard', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('explode', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('46-year-old', 'O'), ('Lexington', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('carrier', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Navy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('exclusively', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
