[[('A', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('blasted', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('North', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('town', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('dawn', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('destroying', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('college', 'O'), ('library', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('blowing', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('rooftops', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('flipping', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('leaving', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('touched', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('4:30', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Madison', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('east', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Tallahassee', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('12-mile', 'O'), ('swath', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('destruction', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('huge', 'O'), ('roar', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('heard', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tree', 'O'), ('crack', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('gone', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Marie', 'PERSON'), ('Prince', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Madison', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('sheriff', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('dispatcher', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('passed', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('blocks', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Four', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Sheriff', 'O'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Peavy', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fifteen', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('none', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('critical', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Madison', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('County', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Memorial', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hospital', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('administrator', 'O'), ('Jeannie', 'PERSON'), ('Baker', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('house-to-house', 'O'), ('search', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('bodies', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('baby', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('freed', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('separate', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('trapped', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Peavy', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('mobile', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('blown', 'O'), ('apart', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('seriously', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Madison', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('County', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Civil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Defense', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Director', 'O'), ('Bernard', 'PERSON'), ('Wilson', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('leave', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Not', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dish', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('You', 'O'), ("'d", 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('trailer', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Dorothy', 'PERSON'), ('Butler', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('sister', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('victims', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rescue', 'O'), ('units', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('adjoining', 'O'), ('counties', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('helping', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('enforcement', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('forestry', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('State', 'O'), ('prisoners', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cleanup', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Peavy', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('estimate', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('struck', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Southeast', 'LOCATION'), ('with', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('lightning', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('hail', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Trees', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('roofs', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('mobile', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Madison', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('3,500', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ('seat', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Madison', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('thinly', 'O'), ('populated', 'O'), ('tobacco', 'O'), ('growing', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('piney', 'O'), ('woods', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('rolling', 'O'), ('hills', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('swamps', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('border', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('twister', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('destructive', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('shopping', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('proceeded', 'O'), ('straight', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('North', 'LOCATION'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('Junior', 'LOCATION'), ('College', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('totaled', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('library', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('roof', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('auditorium', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Peavy', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('twister', 'O'), ('blew', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('blew', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('roof', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('nearby', 'O'), ('church', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('overturned', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('knocked', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Peavy', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('far', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('knew', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Peavy', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('sweep', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('lasted', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('30', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Electric', 'O'), ('company', 'O'), ('workers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('restoring', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('throughout', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('struck', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('towns', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Malone', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Bascom', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('100', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Madison', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('management', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Mader', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Three', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('trailer', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('seriously', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('slightly', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Many', 'O'), ('county', 'O'), ('roads', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('blocked', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('fallen', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('surveying', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('helicopter', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('spawned', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('belt', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('thunderstorms', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('pushed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cold', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Hail', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('size', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('golf', 'O'), ('balls', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('damaging', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mississippi', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Alabama', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('More', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('inch', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('rain', 'O'), ('fell', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Waycross', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ga.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('70', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('northeast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('gusts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('40', 'O'), ('mph', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Valdosta', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Weather', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Elsewhere', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('blown', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('barn', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tin', 'O'), ('roof', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('blown', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('building', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('nine', 'O'), ('mobile', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Bainbridge', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ga.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('seriously', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('sheriff', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('shreds', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Bainbridge', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('northwest', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Tallahassee', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('9-year-old', 'O'), ('girl', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Cottonwood', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ala.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('lightning', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('stood', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('stove', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('lightning', 'O'), ('accompanied', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Houston', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('about', 'O'), ('60', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('northwest', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Tallahasse', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Bulloch', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('mobile', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('heavily', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), ('shortly', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('dawn', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('service', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Tornado', 'O'), ('watches', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('14', 'O'), ('southeastern', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('northeastern', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('counties', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Madison', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('1959', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('injury', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Weather', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
