[[('Rescuers', 'O'), ('crawled', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('collapsed', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('shops', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('victims', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('carved', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('3-mile', 'O'), ('stretch', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('destruction', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('17', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('463', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('leaving', 'O'), ('1,000', 'O'), ('homeless', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('blocks', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('putting', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('blender', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('putting', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('liquefy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('rescue', 'O'), ('worker', 'O'), ('Bob', 'PERSON'), ('Caraway', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('specialty', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('cave', 'O'), ('rescues', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('dig', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('rubble', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('survivors', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('bodies', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('series', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('touched', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('arc', 'O'), ('spanning', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Deep', 'O'), ('South', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Midwest', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('19', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('far-flung', 'O'), ('property', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Huntsville', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('teams', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('cranes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('floodlights', 'O'), ('searched', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('hampered', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('wind-whipped', 'O'), ('rain', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('temperatures', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('plummeted', 'O'), ('overnight', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('73', 'O'), ('degrees', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('30s', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Gov', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Guy', 'PERSON'), ('Hunt', 'PERSON'), ('sent', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Guardsmen', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('Friday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Terry', 'PERSON'), ('Abbott', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('aerial', 'O'), ('surveys', 'O'), ('indicate', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('twister', 'O'), ('hopped', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('25-mile', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('straight', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('Huntsville', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('By', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('afternoon', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('severe', 'O'), ('thunderstorms', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('crossing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Northeast', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Weather', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('put', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Maryland', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Delaware', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Pennsylvania', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Jersey', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Connecticut', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Rhode', 'LOCATION'), ('Island', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Massachusetts', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Vermont', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Hampshire', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Pennsylvania', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('service', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('unconfirmed', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('knocked', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Gettysburg', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Elsewhere', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('_In', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('19', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('critically', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('200', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('evacuated', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('strus.C.', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('toppled', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('downed', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Greenwood', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('S.C.', 'LOCATION'), ('No', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('either', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Tornadoes', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('minor', 'O'), ('property', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Mississippi', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Kentucky', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Indiana', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_In', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Virginia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('believed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('swept', 'O'), ('Jefferson', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('early', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('overturning', 'O'), ('trailers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('blowing', 'O'), ('roofs', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('downing', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Four', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('seriously', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Heavy', 'O'), ('thunderstorms', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dozen', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Alorton', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ill.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('seriously', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('struck', 'O'), ('Huntsville', 'LOCATION'), ('with', 'O'), ('virtually', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('warning', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('afternoon', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('streets', 'O'), ('grew', 'O'), ('busy', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('approach', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('rush', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('matter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('seconds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('hurled', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('crushed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('apartments', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('stores', 'O'), ('looked', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('bombed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('fast', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Lucy', 'PERSON'), ('Lee', 'PERSON'), ('Rusk', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('battered', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('debris', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('big', 'O'), ('pop', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('everything', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Weather', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('issued', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('urgent', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('warning', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('4:39', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), ('CST', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('spotted', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('municipal', 'O'), ('golf', 'O'), ('course', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('By', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('tearing', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('means', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('considered', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('warning', 'O'), ('means', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('believed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('exist', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Huntsville', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Maj.', 'O'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Moder', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('463', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('twister', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('plowed', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('rural', 'O'), ('areas', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('shopping', 'O'), ('mall', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('adjacent', 'O'), ('apartments', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('Ottman', 'PERSON'), ('initially', 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('19', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('clerk', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Kitty', 'PERSON'), ('Whitworth', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), ('toll', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('lowered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('17', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('bodies', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('She', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('firm', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('30', 'O'), ('youngsters', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('kindergarten', 'O'), ('class', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('building', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('apartments', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('stores', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mayor', 'O'), ('Steve', 'PERSON'), ('Hettinger', 'PERSON'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('homeless', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('1,000', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('preparing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('request', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), ('assistance', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('worker', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('building', 'O'), ('owned', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Madison', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('County', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jaycees', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('42', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('staying', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('described', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mood', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('survivors', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('shock', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('mostly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('disbelief', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('thankful', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('alive', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('thankful', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('families', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('alive', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('adding', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shelter', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('calls', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('worried', 'O'), ('relatives', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('Alabama', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('deadliest', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('1975', 'O'), ('twister', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('22', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Birmingham', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Danny', 'PERSON'), ('Cooper', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('management', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Montgomery', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Along', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('highway', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('complex', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('flipped', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('smashed', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('telephone', 'O'), ('poles', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('crushed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('roadway', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('strewn', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('bandages', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('gloves', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('workers', 'O'), ('treating', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Humana', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hospital', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('administrator', 'O'), ('David', 'PERSON'), ('Miller', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('doctors', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('difficulty', 'O'), ('reaching', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hospital', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('blocked', 'O'), ('roads', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Those', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('spoke', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('awe', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('fury', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('huge', 'O'), ('roar', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('enormous', 'O'), ('amount', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('shaking', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('tearing', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('everything', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('hold', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('real', 'O'), ('estate', 'O'), ('broker', 'O'), ('Ike', 'PERSON'), ('Carroll', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Heavy', 'O'), ('overhead', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('snapping', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('circus', 'O'), ('performer', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('snap', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('whip', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Carroll', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('All', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('heavy', 'O'), ('arcing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('flashing', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('popping', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('snapping', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('top', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('...', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('arc-welder', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('bright', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Kenneth', 'PERSON'), ('Lenhard', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('undergone', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('operation', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Crestwood', 'LOCATION'), ('Hospital', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('returned', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('room', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('room', 'O'), ('blew', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('passed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('anything', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('covered', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Lenhard', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('`What', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('heck', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'m", 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('half', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("'", 'O')]]
[[("''", 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('downtown', 'O'), ('Jones', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Valley', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Elementary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('School', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Waterford', 'LOCATION'), ('Square', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('adjacent', 'O'), ('Queensbury', 'LOCATION'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('complexes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reduced', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('rubble', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Kindergarteners', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('pupils', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('twister', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('NASA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Marshall', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Space', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Flight', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Army', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Redstone', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Arsenal', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('space', 'O'), ('agency', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('weapons', 'O'), ('testing', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Alabama', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('addition', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Huntsville', 'LOCATION'), ('total', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Near', 'O'), ('Palmetto', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Ga.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('resident', 'O'), ('Jeff', 'PERSON'), ('Bryant', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Sweetbriar', 'LOCATION'), ('Mobile', 'LOCATION'), ('Home', 'LOCATION'), ('Park', 'LOCATION'), ('near', 'O'), ('Interstate', 'O'), ('85', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('vibrate', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('twister', 'O'), ('approached', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Then', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('heard', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('loud', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('swirling', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('humming', 'O'), ('noise', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('recalled', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('sound', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('train', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('everybody', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('lived', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('train', 'O'), ('track', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('sound', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('train', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('sounded', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('range', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Thomas', 'PERSON'), ('Farr', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('driving', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Interstate', 'O'), ('85', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('picking', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('tossing', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('toys', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('interstate', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('18-wheeler', 'O'), ('flip', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('flipped', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('100', 'O'), ('yards', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('guy', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('thrown', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('passenger', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('landed', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('feet', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
