[[('Here', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('facts', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Weather', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Insurance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Information', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('news', 'O'), ('accounts', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('_Tornadoes', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('month', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('frequent', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('3', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('6', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), ('_Most', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('track', 'O'), ('southwest', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('northeast', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('paths', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('spiral', 'O'), ('erratically', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_The', 'O'), ('portion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('thunderstorm', 'O'), ('adjacent', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('hail', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_There', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('32', 'O'), ('tornado-related', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1988', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('59', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1987', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('below', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('average', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('99', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Less', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('classified', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('violent', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('speeds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('200', 'O'), ('mph', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('averaging', 'O'), ('26', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('longest', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('219', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('Missouri', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Illinois', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Indiana', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), ('1925', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Tornadoes', 'O'), ('travel', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('average', 'O'), ('30', 'O'), ('mph', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('stand', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('70', 'O'), ('mph', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_The', 'O'), ('largest', 'O'), ('single', 'O'), ('outbreak', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('twisters', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('1974', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('148', 'O'), ('storms', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('300', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('13', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_When', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('threatens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('seek', 'O'), ('shelter', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('basement', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('central', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('building', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('windows', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
