[[('_Alabama', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Seventeen', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Huntsville', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('touched', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('rush', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('463', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('1,000', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('homeless', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Three', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Clay', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('Alabama', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_District', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Columbia', 'LOCATION'), (':', 'O'), ('Heavy', 'O'), ('thunderstorms', 'O'), ('packing', 'O'), ('50-60', 'O'), ('mph', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('swept', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('area', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('rush', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('flooding', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('streets', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('About', 'O'), ('10,000', 'O'), ('customers', 'O'), ('lost', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('mostly', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Maryland', 'LOCATION'), ('suburbs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Georgia', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('19', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('critically', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('200', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('evacuated', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('struck', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('mobile', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('parks', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('interstate', 'O'), ('highway', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Palmetto', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('southeast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Atlanta', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Illinois', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Strong', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('St.', 'LOCATION'), ('Clair', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('southwestern', 'O'), ('Illinois', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Damage', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('3', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('5', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Indiana', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('spotted', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('afternoon', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('Richmond', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Ohio', 'LOCATION'), ('border', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('ripped', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('top', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('silo', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('tipped', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('semi-trailer', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('ditch', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('driver', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('slightly', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Kentucky', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('28', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('2.5', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('believed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('mile-long', 'O'), ('swath', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('destruction', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Flaherty', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Meade', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Damage', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Bullitt', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('LaRue', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Hardin', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Pendleton', 'LOCATION'), ('counties', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Maryland', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Delaware', 'LOCATION'), (':', 'O'), ('Heavy', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('leveled', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('church', 'O'), ('building', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Kent', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Md.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('lifted', 'O'), ('roofs', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('buildings', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Baltimore', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('tens', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('utility', 'O'), ('customers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Reports', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Kent', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Md.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Hockessin', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Del', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Weather', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('unable', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('immediately', 'O'), ('confirm', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Mississippi', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Scattered', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('outages', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('radar', 'O'), ('showed', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Neshoba', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Kemper', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('counties', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('east-central', 'O'), ('portion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_New', 'O'), ('Jersey', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('High', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('blamed', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('widespread', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('outages', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('touched', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Piscataway', 'LOCATION'), ('shortly', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('noon', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('collapsing', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('damaging', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('One', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('minor', 'O'), ('injury', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('bridge', 'O'), ('connecting', 'O'), ('Elizabeth', 'PERSON'), ('with', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('closed', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('tractor', 'O'), ('trailers', 'O'), ('overturned', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('heavy', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('truck', 'O'), ('driver', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('passenger', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('minor', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Bergen', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_New', 'O'), ('York', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('severe', 'O'), ('thunderstorm', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tree', 'O'), ('crashing', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('elementary', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('roof', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Newburgh', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('60', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('18', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('12-foot', 'O'), ('steel', 'O'), ('beam', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('apparently', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('blown', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('water', 'O'), ('tower', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Tornadoes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Peekskill', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_North', 'LOCATION'), ('Carolina', 'LOCATION'), (':', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('pair', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Henderson', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('vacant', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Ohio', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('High', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('described', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('hopscotched', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('north-central', 'O'), ('Ohio', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('ripping', 'O'), ('roofs', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('barns', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('destroying', 'O'), ('farm', 'O'), ('sheds', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('damaging', 'O'), ('trailer', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('One', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('hospitalized', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lightning', 'O'), ('strike', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('slightly', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('flying', 'O'), ('debris', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_Pennsylvania', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('High', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('funnel', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('ripped', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('roofs', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('downed', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('Pennslyvania', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('shattering', 'O'), ('windows', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Philadelphia', 'LOCATION'), ('skyscrapers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('75,000', 'O'), ('customers', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('southeastern', 'O'), ('Pennsylvania', 'LOCATION'), ('lost', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_South', 'O'), ('Carolina', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), ('downed', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Greenwood', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('_West', 'O'), ('Virginia', 'LOCATION'), (':', 'O'), ('High', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('knocked', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('ripped', 'O'), ('roofs', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('toppled', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('trailer', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Jefferson', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Frederick', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Md.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('family', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('seriously', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Weather', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('probably', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
