[[('1990', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('fast', 'O'), ('becoming', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('worst', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('flooding', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('middle', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('sections', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('So', 'O'), ('far', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('726', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('touched', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('nationwide', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('ahead', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('640', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('recorded', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('30-year', 'O'), ('average', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('482', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('recorded', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('January', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Frederick', 'PERSON'), ('Ostby', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Severe', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Storms', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Forecast', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('here', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('nation', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('747', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('1973', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('biggest', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('1950', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('forecast', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('keeping', 'O'), ('reliable', 'O'), ('records', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storms', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('756', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1982', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('seem', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pace', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Ostby', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('culprit', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('barrage', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Plains', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('persistent', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Coast', 'LOCATION'), ('pattern', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('low', 'O'), ('pressure', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('upper', 'O'), ('atmosphere', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('keeping', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('stream', 'O'), ('anchored', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('latitude', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('storms', 'O'), ('seem', 'O'), ('particularly', 'O'), ('violent', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('illustrated', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), ('13', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('swath', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('mile', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('brought', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('300', 'O'), ('mph', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('field', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Kansas', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('strongest', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('since', 'O'), ('1985', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('weekend', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('worst', 'O'), ('outburst', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('1974', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Ostby', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('101', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('touched', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Kansas', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Kentucky', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('leaving', 'O'), ('nine', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('dead', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('break', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('pattern', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('hand', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('summer', 'O'), ('wears', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('land', 'O'), ('warms', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('cold', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Canada', 'LOCATION'), ('retreats', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('moves', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('boundary', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('jet', 'O'), ('stream', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Ostby', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Our', 'O'), ('longer', 'O'), ('range', 'O'), ('computer', 'O'), ('forecasts', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('suggestive', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('kind', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('readjustment', 'O'), ('beginning', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('place', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('upper', 'O'), ('atmosphere', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('trends', 'O'), ('indicates', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Midwest', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('particularly', 'O'), ('Kansas', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Missouri', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('heading', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('six-year', 'O'), ('period', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('intense', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('century', 'O'), ('shows', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('concentrated', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('regions', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('five-', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('six-year', 'O'), ('periods', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('WeatherData', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Inc', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('warning', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('impending', 'O'), ('storms', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('becoming', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('sophisticated', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('leading', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fewer', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Tornadoes', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('average', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1980s', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('52', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1970s', 'O'), ('nearly', 'O'), ('100', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Ostby', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('better', 'O'), ('watches', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('better', 'O'), ('warnings', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('better', 'O'), ('response', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Ostby', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Ostby', 'PERSON'), ('credited', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('quicker', 'O'), ('response', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('computers', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('allow', 'O'), ('meteorologists', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('sources', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('data', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('satellite', 'O'), ('readings', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('clearly', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Flooding', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Plains', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('destructive', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), ('toll', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('flash', 'O'), ('floods', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Shadyside', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Ohio', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('rose', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('21', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('flood', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('deadly', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Authorities', 'O'), ('held', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('hope', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dozen', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('listed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Wegee', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Pipe', 'O'), ('creeks', 'O'), ('overflowed', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('storms', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('dumped', 'O'), ('5', 'O'), ('{', 'O'), ('inches', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('rain', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('3', 'O'), ('{', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('floods', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('70', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('40', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Flooding', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('blamed', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('16', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('An', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('10,000', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('forced', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('hundreds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('millions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('dollars', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
