[[('Tetsuya', 'PERSON'), ('Theodore', 'PERSON'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('saw', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('natural', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1982', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('meeting', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('lover', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Since', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('passion', 'O'), ('really', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('professor', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('geophysical', 'O'), ('science', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('studying', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('42', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('considered', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('foremost', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('violent', 'O'), ('storms', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fujita', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('69', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('spends', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('lab', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chicago', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('creating', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('research', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('creates', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('fan', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('makes', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('swirling', 'O'), ('motion', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('fan', 'O'), ('above', 'O'), ('simulates', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('low-pressure', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('adding', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('updraft', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mix', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('With', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bit', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('steam', 'O'), ('added', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('phenomenon', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('creates', 'O'), ('twisters', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('feet', 'O'), ('tall', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('miniature', 'O'), ('versions', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('impossible', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('redirect', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('squelch', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('full-size', 'O'), ('cousins', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('tried', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('crawling', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('rulers', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('books', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('change', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('direction', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('came', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('from', 'O'), ('Japan', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1953', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('partly', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Tornadoes', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('rare', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Japan', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('hometown', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('quite', 'O'), ('impressed', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('localized', 'O'), ('severity', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('When', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('team', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('studying', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('shear', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('beautiful', 'O'), ('thing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Of', 'O'), ('course', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('added', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('terrible', 'O'), ('thing', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Forecasters', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('trouble', 'O'), ('predicting', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('helped', 'O'), ('define', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('conditions', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('spawn', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Groups', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('thunderstorms', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('spawn', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('single', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('storms', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('multiple', 'O'), ('storms', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('compete', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Each', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('tries', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('rotate', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('ca', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('human', 'O'), ('beings', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('rich', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('richer', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('poor', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('poorer', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('also', 'O'), ('discovered', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('strong', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('actually', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('twisters', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('calls', 'O'), ('suction', 'O'), ('vortices', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('rotating', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('larger', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('suction', 'O'), ('vortex', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('pick', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('something', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('standing', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('completely', 'O'), ('safe', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('studied', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('dropped', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('lakes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('untouched', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('whole', 'O'), ('flocks', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('cows', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('sheep', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('lived', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('experience', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('developed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('scale', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('measuring', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('strength', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('runs', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('zero', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('break', 'O'), ('twigs', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('twister', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('rip', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('foundations', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('considers', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('movements', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('downbursts', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('microbursts', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('significant', 'O'), ('achievements', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Downbursts', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('powerful', 'O'), ('drafts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('moving', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('thunderstorm', 'O'), ('cloud', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Scientists', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('drafts', 'O'), ('dissipated', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('reaching', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Microbursts', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('smaller', 'O'), ('versions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('downbursts', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('dangerous', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('give', 'O'), ('pilots', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('react', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Safety', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Board', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('cited', 'O'), ('microbursts', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('term', 'O'), ('coined', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('17', 'O'), ('aircraft', 'O'), ('accidents', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('577', 'O'), ('fatalities', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Among', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1985', 'O'), ('crash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Delta', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('L-1011', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Dallas', 'LOCATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('137', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('downburst', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('implicated', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('collapse', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wall', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Newburgh', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('N.Y.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('nine', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('helped', 'O'), ('persuade', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Federal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aviation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Administation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('installing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('radar', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('47', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('airports', 'O'), ('beginning', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('1990s', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Doppler', 'O'), ('radar', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('credited', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('helping', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('jetliners', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('airport', 'O'), ('avoid', 'O'), ('potentially', 'O'), ('catastrophic', 'O'), ('microbursts', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('retires', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('teaching', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('continue', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('research', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('university', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('one', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('drove', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tornado', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('better', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Fujita', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('safer', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
