[[('Thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('peole', 'O'), ('prayed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('cheered', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('danced', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('beat', 'O'), ('drums', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('observed', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('traditions', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('darkened', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Indonesia', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Philippines', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('blacked', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'LOCATION'), ('for', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('108-mile', 'O'), ('swath', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Indian', 'LOCATION'), ('Ocean', 'LOCATION'), ('across', 'O'), ('Indonesia', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Philippine', 'O'), ('island', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mindanao', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Asia', 'LOCATION'), ('as', 'O'), ('far', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('India', 'LOCATION'), ('_', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('Southeast', 'LOCATION'), ('Asia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('China', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Japan', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Guinea', 'LOCATION'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Australia', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pacific', 'LOCATION'), ('islands', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Scientists', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('end', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('sunset', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('Alaska', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Clouds', 'O'), ('obscured', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('spectacular', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Jakarta', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Indonesia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Hong', 'LOCATION'), ('Kong', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('Mindanao', 'LOCATION'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Davao', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tourists', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('gathered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('observe', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('3', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('650', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('southeast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Manila', 'LOCATION'), ('despite', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('scattered', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('President', 'O'), ('Corazon', 'PERSON'), ('Aquino', 'PERSON'), ('flew', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('witness', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('event', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('Fisher', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('High', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Altitude', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Observatory', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Boulder', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Colo.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('despite', 'O'), ('scattered', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('confident', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('useful', 'O'), ('pictures', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Jakarta', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Wilson', 'PERSON'), ('Sinambela', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Aeronautics', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('observed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('1,000', 'O'), ('tourists', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Sumatra', 'LOCATION'), ('capital', 'O'), ('Palembang', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Indonesians', 'O'), ('prayed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('beat', 'O'), ('drums', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('herald', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('start', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('southwestern', 'O'), ('Sumatra', 'LOCATION'), ('before', 'O'), ('heading', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Philippines', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Kuala', 'LOCATION'), ('Lumpur', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('blocked', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('80', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('Malaysian', 'O'), ('Hindus', 'O'), ('visited', 'O'), ('temples', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('pray', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('protection', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('harm', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Kurukshetra', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('India', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('1', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('pilgrims', 'O'), ('dipped', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('waters', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sacred', 'O'), ('Sannihit', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Brahmsarover', 'O'), ('tanks', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('address', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('announced', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('start', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Hymns', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('chanted', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('conch', 'O'), ('shells', 'O'), ('blown', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ceremony', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('90', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Delhi', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Clouds', 'O'), ('blocked', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('moments', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('General', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Santos', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('City', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cloud', 'O'), ('cover', 'O'), ('broke', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('setting', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('wild', 'O'), ('cheering', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('watched', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('phenomenon', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('scorching', 'O'), ('tropical', 'O'), ('heat', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Street', 'O'), ('lights', 'O'), ('switched', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Naragcas', 'LOCATION'), ('tribe', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('festival', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('danced', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('streets', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('beat', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('drums', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Baguio', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('130', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Manila', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('pregnant', 'O'), ('women', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('Ilocano', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('rinsed', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('hair', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), ('dripped', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('burned', 'O'), ('rice', 'O'), ('straws', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('traditional', 'O'), ('ritual', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('According', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('superstition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('babies', 'O'), ('conceived', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('shortly', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('deformed', 'O'), ('unless', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('mothers', 'O'), ('practice', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ritual', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Many', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('Filipinos', 'O'), ('marked', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('church', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Philippines', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('Asia', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('predominately', 'O'), ('Christian', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('phenomenon', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('reminder', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('God', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('mankind', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('repent', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('sins', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Theresa', 'PERSON'), ('Teopengco', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('employee', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('20,000', 'O'), ('tourists', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Philippines', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Scientists', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('afforded', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('opportunity', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('witness', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('skies', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('usually', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Davao', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('60', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('northeast', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('hundreds', 'O'), ('scurrying', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('airport', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('General', 'O'), ('Santos', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Church', 'O'), ('bells', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Davao', 'LOCATION'), ('tolled', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('civilians', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('firecrackers', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('fired', 'O'), ('weapons', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('mark', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Manila', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('skies', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('blocked', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('75', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('surface', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('height', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('passenger', 'O'), ('bus', 'O'), ('collided', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('jeep', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('drivers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('probably', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('skyward', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('accident', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('policeman', 'O'), ('Ricardo', 'PERSON'), ('Manansala', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('impossible', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('gaze', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sky', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('drive', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('vehicle', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Solar', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('positions', 'O'), ('itself', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Chinese', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('recorded', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('2137', 'O'), ('B.C.', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('regarding', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('signs', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('battle', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dragon', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
