[[('Solar', 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), ('yielded', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('flare-producing', 'O'), ('sunspots', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('silhouetted', 'O'), ('mountains', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('crowds', 'O'), ('gathered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('western', 'O'), ('North', 'LOCATION'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('childlike', 'O'), ('delight', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wonder', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('nature', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Ed', 'PERSON'), ('Krupp', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Griffith', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Observatory', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('600', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('400', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('watched', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('block', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('37', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('surface', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('10:50', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('PST', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('certainly', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lively', 'O'), ('crowd', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('festival', 'O'), ('atmosphere', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('kind', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('neat', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('map', 'O'), ('maker', 'O'), ('Jan', 'PERSON'), ('Mayne', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('dozens', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('watching', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('types', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('California', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Technology', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Pasadena', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('passed', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('watching', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('Caltech', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('mountains', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('edge', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('silhouetted', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('gas', 'O'), ('jets', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('surface', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('giant', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('sunspots', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('produced', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('intense', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('flare', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('burst', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('heat', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('radiation', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('1984', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('stunning', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('sunspot', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Krupp', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('extent', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('diagonal', 'O'), ('line', 'O'), ('stretching', 'O'), ('roughly', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Mazatlan', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('northeast', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Dallas', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Chicago', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Views', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('farther', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('notice', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('slight', 'O'), ('dimming', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('sunlight', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('You', 'O'), ('ca', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('difference', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('second-stage', 'O'), ('smog', 'O'), ('alert', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('joked', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('observer', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Caltech', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Several', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('viewed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('welder', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('helmets', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('downtown', 'O'), ('Anchorage', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Alaska', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('obscured', 'O'), ('80', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('9:13', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('AST', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Francisco', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('eclipsed', 'O'), ('46', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('9:52', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('event', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('thick', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('delayed', 'O'), ('arriving', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('airport', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('slight', 'O'), ('dimming', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('noticed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Seattle', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('partly', 'O'), ('cloudy', 'O'), ('skies', 'O'), ('allowed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('glimpse', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('56', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('10:10', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('PST', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('percentage', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('blocked', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('maximum', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('locations', 'O'), ('included', 'O'), ('52', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('11:28', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('MST', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Edmonton', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Alberta', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('46', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('11:09', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('MST', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Boise', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Idaho', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('36', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('11:10', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('MST', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Salt', 'LOCATION'), ('Lake', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('35', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('9:58', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('PST', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Las', 'LOCATION'), ('Vegas', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('11:17', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('MST', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('12:42', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), ('CST', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Minneapolis', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('measly', 'O'), ('3', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('12:44', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), ('CST', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Milwaukee', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fearful', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('suffer', 'O'), ('eye', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('warned', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('staring', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('directly', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('inadequate', 'O'), ('filters', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('smoked', 'O'), ('glass', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('photographic', 'O'), ('film', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('filters', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Alan', 'PERSON'), ('MacRobert', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Sky', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('&', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('amp', 'ORGANIZATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Telescope', 'O'), ('magazine', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('245', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('eye', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('after', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1970', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('warnings', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('danger', 'O'), ('reduced', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('1984', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('From', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('single', 'O'), ('spot', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Earth', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('occurs', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Ken', 'PERSON'), ('Libbrecht', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('professor', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('astrophysics', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Caltech', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Total', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('single', 'O'), ('location', 'O'), ('roughly', 'O'), ('once', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('centuries', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('somewhere', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('happen', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1991', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('sweeping', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pacific', 'LOCATION'), ('Ocean', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('lower', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('coast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Central', 'LOCATION'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('finally', 'O'), ('Colombia', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Brazil', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('MacRobert', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
