[[('Cloudy', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), ('threatened', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('mar', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Finnish', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('foreign', 'O'), ('skygazers', 'O'), ('hoping', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('glimpse', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('land', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('midnight', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('forecast', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('turn', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('worse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('evening', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Finnish', 'O'), ('Meteorological', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Services', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('predicted', 'O'), ('cloudy', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('chance', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('showers', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('Finland', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Sunday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Joensuu', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('news', 'O'), ('broadcast', 'O'), ('late', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), ('showed', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('cloudy', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), ('drizzle', 'O'), ('falling', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Finland', 'LOCATION'), ('starts', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('4:03', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('Sunday', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('9:03', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), ('EDT', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('gradually', 'O'), ('moving', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('begins', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('4:52', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Helsinki', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('83', 'O'), ('seconds', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('After', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('phase', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('move', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('uncovering', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('ends', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('5:45', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Helsinki', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('About', 'O'), ('10,000', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('3,000', 'O'), ('foreigners', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('converged', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Joensuu', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Soviet', 'O'), ('border', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('conditions', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('considered', 'O'), ('especially', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('weather', 'O'), ('permitting', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Helsinki', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('phase', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), ('16', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('sunrise', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('1', 'O'), ('degree', 'O'), ('above', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('horizon', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('Joensuu', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('310', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('northeast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Helsinki', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('5', 'O'), ('degrees', 'O'), ('above', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('horizon', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('phase', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('better', 'O'), ('angle', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('watchers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('rises', 'O'), ('unusually', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('summer', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('extreme', 'O'), ('northern', 'O'), ('latitudes', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('Finland', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('located', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('comes', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('unusually', 'O'), ('late', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('winter', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Ten', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Joensuu', 'PERSON'), ('hired', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('handle', 'O'), ('arrangements', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('influx', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('visitors', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Marjut', 'LOCATION'), ('Cadia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('underestimated', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('event', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('completely', 'O'), ('sold', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('10,000', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('eyeglasses', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('event', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('extra', 'O'), ('stock', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('finished', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('During', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('newspapers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('radio', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('full', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('advice', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('spectators', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stare', 'O'), ('directly', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('viewers', 'O'), ('wo', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('worry', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('above', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Finnair', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('airline', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('arranged', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dozen', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('watchers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('private', 'O'), ('companies', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('planes', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('provide', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('arc', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('125', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('northern', 'O'), ('Baltic', 'LOCATION'), ('Sea', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('southeast', 'O'), ('Finland', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Kola', 'LOCATION'), ('Peninsula', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('northeast', 'O'), ('Soviet', 'LOCATION'), ('Union', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Aleutian', 'LOCATION'), ('Islands', 'LOCATION'), ('near', 'O'), ('Alaska', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Scientists', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('conduct', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('experiments', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('gravity', 'O'), ('test', 'O'), ('measurements', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('radius', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('scientific', 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('longer', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('seven-minute', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('seen', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('northern', 'O'), ('Kenya', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('30', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1973', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Seppo', 'PERSON'), ('Linnaluoto', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Ursa', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Astronomical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('place', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('observations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('northeast', 'O'), ('Soviet', 'LOCATION'), ('Union', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('seen', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Finland', 'LOCATION'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1945', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
