[[('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('worship', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('passed', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('ancient', 'O'), ('civilizations', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('modern', 'O'), ('beachgoers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('gearing', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('blotted', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('President', 'O'), ('Carlos', 'PERSON'), ('Salinas', 'PERSON'), ('de', 'PERSON'), ('Gortari', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('appointed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Cabinet-level', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prepare', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('astronomers', 'O'), ('bill', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('slar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('century', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Posters', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('placed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), ('subways', 'O'), ('promoting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('event', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('resorts', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('scrambling', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('accommodate', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('rush', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tourists', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('history', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('Miguel', 'PERSON'), ('Gil', 'PERSON'), ('Guzman', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('secretary-general', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Mexican', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Astronomical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Society', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('swath', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('populous', 'O'), ('regions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('globe', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('turning', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('14', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('31', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('reaches', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('through', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Brazil', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('165-mile-wide', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('dark', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('almost', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('maximum', 'O'), ('length', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('pass', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('planet', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('abruptly', 'O'), ('swallowing', 'O'), ('midday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('light', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('except', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('weird', 'O'), ('glow', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('horizon', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('People', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('British', 'LOCATION'), ('Columbia', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Buenos', 'LOCATION'), ('Aires', 'LOCATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('experience', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Viewing', 'O'), ('conditions', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('poor', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Latin', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('rainy', 'O'), ('season', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), ('1991', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('banking', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('roll', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('financial', 'O'), ('favor', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('bills', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('northwestern', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Sur', 'LOCATION'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('place', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('average', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('300', 'O'), ('cloudless', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Baja', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('California', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Sur', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('alone', 'O'), ('plans', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('spend', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('26.5', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('safety', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('enthusiasts', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('banks', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('raking', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('millions', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('tourism', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('For', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('astronomy', 'O'), ('buffs', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('staking', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('turf', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('chance', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('century', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('hotels', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('route', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('full', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Tourism', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('seeking', 'O'), ('private', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('campgrounds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('schools', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('auditoriums', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('influx', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('Sur', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('tourist', 'O'), ('facilities', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('handle', 'O'), ('120,000', 'O'), ('visitors', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('90', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('capacity', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('booked', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('tourism', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('Rodolfo', 'PERSON'), ('Palacios', 'PERSON'), ('says', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('ships', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('pressed', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('service', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('floating', 'O'), ('hotels', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('13,500', 'O'), ('amateur', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('professional', 'O'), ('astronomers', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Japan', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Soviet', 'LOCATION'), ('Union', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('China', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Canada', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('England', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('France', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('have', 'O'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('reservations', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('tourists', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('booked', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('hotel', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('completed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Pacific', 'LOCATION'), ('coast', 'O'), ('region', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Nayarit', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('bracing', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('1', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('visitors', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('double', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Cuernavaca', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('35', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('hosting', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('geophysicists', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('congress', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('expedition', 'O'), ('plans', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('17,887-foot', 'O'), ('Popocapetl', 'O'), ('volcano', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('second-highest', 'O'), ('peak', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Others', 'O'), ('plan', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('boats', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('sea', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('An', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('astronomical', 'O'), ('coincidence', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('400', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('smaller', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('400', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('closer', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('earth', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('smaller', 'O'), ('body', 'O'), ('appears', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('cover', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('larger', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rosy', 'O'), ('rays', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('shoot', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('edges', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('forming', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('astronomers', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('corona', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('crown', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Temperatures', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('drop', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('5', 'O'), ('{', 'O'), ('degrees', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('stars', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('planets', 'O'), ('Mercury', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Venus', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('Mars', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Jupiter', 'LOCATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('shine', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Streetlights', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('triggered', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('developing', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('half-hour', 'O'), ('documentaries', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('TV', 'O'), ('spots', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dangers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('astronomy', 'O'), ('professor', 'O'), ('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('Galindo', 'PERSON'), ('says', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Since', 'O'), ('September', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('university', 'O'), ('newspaper', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('publishing', 'O'), ('installments', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('book', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('translated', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('Indian', 'O'), ('languages', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('plans', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('supervise', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('production', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('lenses', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
