[[('While', 'O'), ('Angel', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('followers', 'O'), ('meditate', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prepare', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('journey', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('French', 'O'), ('New', 'O'), ('Age', 'O'), ('musician', 'O'), ('Jean-Michel', 'PERSON'), ('Jarre', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('coordinating', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('elaborate', 'O'), ('sound-and-light', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('play', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('foot', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pyramids', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Teotihuacan', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('capital', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Also', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('E-day', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('crowded', 'O'), ('cruise', 'O'), ('ships', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('linger', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Pacific', 'LOCATION'), ('Coast', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('tourists', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('drive', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('usually', 'O'), ('boasting', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('skies', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('billed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('promising', 'O'), ('site', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('nature', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), ('fans', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Japan', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Netherlands', 'LOCATION'), ('are', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('droves', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('Californians', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('proximity', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('propensity', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('mystical', 'O'), ('phenomena', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('conspicuous', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chic', 'O'), ('hot', 'O'), ('spot', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('watchers', 'O'), ('wo', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('big', 'O'), ('island', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('18,000', 'O'), ('tourists', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('anyway', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('enjoy', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sunshine', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('joined', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('additional', 'O'), ('30,000', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('coming', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Even', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lack', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('island', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('visitors', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('funneled', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('relatively', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('airport', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Kailua', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Airlines', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('are', 'O'), ('adding', 'O'), ('scores', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ferry', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('neighboring', 'O'), ('islands', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Car', 'O'), ('rental', 'O'), ('companies', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('shipped', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('3,000', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('extra', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('More', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('caller', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mainland', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('asked', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('visitors', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('bureau', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('island', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('danger', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tipping', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tourists', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('weight', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('host', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('biggest', 'O'), ('share', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('travelers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('partly', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('easy', 'O'), ('access', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('partly', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('longest', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('maximum', 'O'), ('length', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('longest-lasting', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('2132', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Alan', 'PERSON'), ('Dyer', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('associate', 'O'), ('editor', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Astronomy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('magazine', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('midday', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('consist', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('160-mile', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('lunar', 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('speeding', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('5,000', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('surface', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('While', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('Mexicans', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('forward', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('event', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('quietly', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('precautions', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('pre-Colombian', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('viewed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('bad', 'O'), ('omens', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun-worshiping', 'O'), ('Aztecs', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('capital', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Sonora', 'LOCATION'), ('market', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('specializing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('magic', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('vendors', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('stocked', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('garlic', 'O'), ('bulbs', 'O'), ('tied', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('red', 'O'), ('ribbon', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('hawk', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('protection', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('bad', 'O'), ('vibrations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('thriving', 'O'), ('trade', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('place', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('magnets', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('low', 'O'), ('blood', 'O'), ('pressure', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('carry', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('pockets', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('copper', 'O'), ('coins', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('pregnant', 'O'), ('women', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('place', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('charms', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('belly', 'O'), ('buttons', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('could', 'O'), ('probably', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('otherworldly', 'O'), ('intervention', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('cope', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('scores', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tourists', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('arriving', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('half', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('Peninsula', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('hotels', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('rooms', 'O'), ('reserved', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('All', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('booked', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('fear', 'O'), ('competition', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('campsites', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('worried', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Californians', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('drive', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('spur', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moment', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('fuel', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Marivi', 'PERSON'), ('Lerdo', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('promotes', 'O'), ('tourism', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Although', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('isolation', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('limit', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('size', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crowds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('locals', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('predicting', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('By', 'O'), ('God', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('road', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('island', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('circle', 'O'), ('route', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('often', 'O'), ('narrows', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('lanes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('shop', 'O'), ('owner', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('insanity', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('worrying', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('wo', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('enough', 'O'), ('alcohol', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('food', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('island', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('manager', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('restaurant', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('disco', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('named', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('coincidence', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('While', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('fret', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('infrastructure', 'O'), ('capacity', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('Californians', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('preparing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('revel', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('New', 'O'), ('Age', 'O'), ('wonderland', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('These', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('ever', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('missed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('single', 'O'), ('episode', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ("'Star", 'O'), ('Trek', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Ken', 'PERSON'), ('Stewart', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('planning', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('lead', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('caravan', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('enthusiasts', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Diego', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Cabo', 'LOCATION'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Lucas', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('tip', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('heavily', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('planning', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('formed', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Intersecretarial', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('things', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('supposed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('oversee', 'O'), ('production', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('60', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('protective', 'O'), ('lenses', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Newspapers', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('carrying', 'O'), ('frequent', 'O'), ('reminders', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stare', 'O'), ('directly', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('During', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mystic', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('scientific', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('far', 'O'), ('apart', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('At', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('observatories', 'O'), ('atop', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Mauna', 'LOCATION'), ('Kea', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dormant', 'O'), ('volcano', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('highest', 'O'), ('peak', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pacific', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('researchers', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('turn', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('outer', 'O'), ('atmosphere', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('covers', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('rest', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('star', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Twenty', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('downhill', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Crystal', 'O'), ('Grotto', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Honomu', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Wendy', 'PERSON'), ('Gilliam', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('selling', 'O'), ('pouches', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('stones', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('corona', 'O'), ('crystals', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('advising', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('expose', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('energy', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('passes', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('certain', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('vortexes', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('opened', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('awakened', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('DO', 'O'), ("N'T", 'O'), ('LOOK', 'O'), ('DIRECTLY', 'O'), ('AT', 'O'), ('IT', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('progress', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Staring', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('your', 'O'), ('feeling', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('thing', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('burn', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('your', 'O'), ('retina', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('permanent', 'O'), ('image', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('crescent', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('severe', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('permanent', 'O'), ('vision', 'O'), ('loss', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('safest', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('indirectly', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('projecting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('image', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pinhole', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('onto', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sheet', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('paper', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('Other', 'O'), ('safe', 'O'), ('methods', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('check', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('Pieces', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('arc-welders', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('glass', 'O'), ('labeled', 'O'), ('14', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('available', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('welding', 'O'), ('supply', 'O'), ('stores', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('welders', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('goggles', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('suitable', 'O'), ('protection', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('(', 'O'), ('check', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('Two', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('layers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mylar', 'O'), ('plastic', 'O'), ('heavily', 'O'), ('coated', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('aluminum', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('stores', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('selling', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('glasses', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('material', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('COMING', 'O'), ('TUESDAY', 'O'), ('IN', 'O'), ('SCIENCE', 'O'), ('&', 'O'), ('amp', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('MEDICINE', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('All', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('details', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('nature', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('stunning', 'O'), ('events', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('How', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('directions', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pinhole', 'O'), ('projector', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
