[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('maybe', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('greatest', 'O'), ('natural', 'O'), ('occurrence', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('witness', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Larry', 'PERSON'), ('Toy', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Chabot', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('astronomy', 'O'), ('professor', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('phenomenon', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('awe-inspiring', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Solar', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), ('twice', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('earth', 'O'), ('line', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('(', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('line-up', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('except', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('orbit', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('tilted', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('crosses', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(')', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('variations', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('orbit', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('fewer', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('third', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('200', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('earth', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('surface', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('races', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('east', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('1,000', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('5,000', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('thousand', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Most', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('poles', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('difficult-to-reach', 'O'), ('terrain', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('average', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('eclipsed', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('once', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('360', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('narrow', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('cross', 'O'), ('inhabited', 'O'), ('areas', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('flock', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('experience', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('totality', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), ('snap', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('stars', 'O'), ('snap', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('gaze', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('shaggy', 'O'), ('corona', 'O'), ('hanging', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dark', 'O'), ('sky', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('daylight', 'O'), ('abruptly', 'O'), ('returns', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('opportunity', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('twice', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('couple', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('decades', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('East', 'LOCATION'), ('Coast', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1970', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Northwest', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'LOCATION'), ('Northern', 'LOCATION'), ('Plains', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1979.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('performance', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('century', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('unusual', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('reasons', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('peak', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('observers', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('longest-lasting', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('century', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('53', 'O'), ('seconds', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('150-mile-wide', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('Central', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('capital', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('puts', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('history', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('Alan', 'PERSON'), ('Dyer', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('editor', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Astronomy', 'O'), ('magazine', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Finally', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('pass', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('largest', 'O'), ('cluster', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('astronomical', 'O'), ('observatories', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('audience', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('dozen', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('intent', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('getting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ("'ve", 'O'), ('ever', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('great', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mountain', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Harold', 'PERSON'), ('Zirin', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('California', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Technology', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('astronomer', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('observatories', 'O'), ('atop', 'O'), ('Mauna', 'LOCATION'), ('Kea', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dormant', 'O'), ('volcano', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('makes', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('piece', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('island', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Historic', 'O'), ('events', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('For', 'O'), ('science', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('proved', 'O'), ('especially', 'O'), ('historic', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('1868', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('spectroscopic', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('halo', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('element', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('named', 'O'), ('helium', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Helios', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Greek', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('god', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1919', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('astronomers', 'O'), ('spotted', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('star', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('instead', 'O'), ('peeking', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('edge', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('confirmation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Albert', 'PERSON'), ('Einstein', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('prediction', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('star', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('gravity', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('bend', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('significance', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('researchers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('For', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('thing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('chasing', 'O'), ('eclipses', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('trekking', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('remote', 'O'), ('regions', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('delicate', 'O'), ('astronomical', 'O'), ('instruments', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('capture', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('data', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('lost', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('glamour', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('especially', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tight', 'O'), ('budgets', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('For', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('gathered', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('instruments', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('simulate', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('coming', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('ca', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('resist', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('13,800', 'O'), ('feet', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mauna', 'LOCATION'), ('Kea', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('tallest', 'O'), ('island', 'O'), ('mountain', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('above', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('dry', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('clean', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('choicest', 'O'), ('spots', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cosmos', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('oxygen', 'O'), ('deprivation', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('concern', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('unlike', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('headed', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('astronomers', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('packing', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('underwear', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('jackets', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('sometimes', 'O'), ('happens', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('temperature', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('summit', 'O'), ('drops', 'O'), ('below', 'O'), ('freezing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('7', 'O'), ('observatories', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Seven', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nine', 'O'), ('observatories', 'O'), ('atop', 'O'), ('Mauna', 'LOCATION'), ('Kea', 'LOCATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('(', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Keck', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Observatory', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('built', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('California', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('California', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Institute', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Technology', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('original', 'O'), ('construction', 'O'), ('schedule', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('completed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(')', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('What', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('temperature', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('composition', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('upper', 'O'), ('atmosphere', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('layers', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chromosphere', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('corona', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('normally', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('difficult', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('examine', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('glare', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('hope', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('provide', 'O'), ('clues', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('causes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('11-year', 'O'), ('cycle', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('sunspots', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('flares', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('peak', 'O'), (')', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('propels', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('why', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('outer', 'O'), ('atmosphere', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('paradoxically', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('hotter', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('lower', 'O'), ('atmosphere', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Solar', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('studies', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('At', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('observatories', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('astronomers', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('repeated', 'O'), ('photographs', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('corona', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('material', 'O'), ('accelerating', 'O'), ('outward', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Others', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('emissions', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('microwave', 'O'), ('frequencies', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('learn', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('details', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('temperature', 'O'), ('varies', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('altitude', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('frankly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('astronomers', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lights', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ("'ll", 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('fighting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('temptation', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('abandon', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('instruments', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('outside', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('biggest', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Zirin', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
