[[('Sure', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ("'ll", 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('able', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('oh', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hundreds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('customers', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('themselves', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mirror', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('audience', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('3-D', 'O'), ('horror', 'O'), ('flick', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('appears', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Golden', 'LOCATION'), ('State', 'LOCATION'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('acting', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Actually', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('ca', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('wait', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Millions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Californians', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('pause', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('join', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('international', 'O'), ('ritual', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('watching', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('longest-lasting', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('2132.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('What', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('natural', 'O'), ('phenomenon', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('?', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('said', 'O'), ('Bert', 'PERSON'), ('Beecher', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Minolta', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Planetarium', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('at', 'O'), ('De', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Anza', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('safer', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('volcano', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Eyeshades', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('hot', 'O'), ('item', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Bay', 'LOCATION'), ('Area', 'LOCATION'), ('people', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('desperately', 'O'), ('seeking', 'O'), ('eyeshades', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('24', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Orion', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Telescope', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Cupertino', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('sell', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('stock', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('900', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), ('Viewers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Mylar', 'O'), ('plastic', 'O'), ('lenses', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('supposedly', 'O'), ('safe', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Welding', 'O'), ('supply', 'O'), ('stores', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('inundated', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('calls', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('welder', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('glasses', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('plastic', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Local', 'O'), ('planetariums', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('observatories', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('deluged', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('requests', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('wanting', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('attend', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('sessions', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bay', 'LOCATION'), ('Area', 'LOCATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('privy', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('63', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('coverage', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('10:10', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('12:34', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Some', 'O'), ('Bay', 'LOCATION'), ('Area', 'LOCATION'), ('``', 'O'), ('umbraphiles', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('lovers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('leaving', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('details', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('chance', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Flights', 'O'), ('heavily', 'O'), ('booked', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Flights', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('--', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('seen', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('heavily', 'O'), ('booked', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('sunstruck', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('spending', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('dollars', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stand', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('6', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('53', 'O'), ('seconds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('darkness', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Scott', 'PERSON'), ('Wiener', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('computer', 'O'), ('company', 'O'), ('executive', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Saratoga', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('flying', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('buddies', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('toast', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('corona', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Coronas', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('figure', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'ll", 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cab', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Wiener', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('stood', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('line', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('telescope', 'O'), ('store', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), ('Viewers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ("'ll", 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('glasses', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('stick', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('heads', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('figure', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('worth', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'ll", 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('150', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('WHERE', 'O'), ('TO', 'O'), ('WATCH', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Here', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('places', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (':', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('San', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Jose', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Astronomical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Branham', 'LOCATION'), ('Lane', 'LOCATION'), ('Park', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('intersection', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Branham', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Camden', 'LOCATION'), ('Avenue', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('9', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), ('For', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('association', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('recorded', 'O'), ('message', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('408', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('997-3347.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('Berkeley', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Lawrence', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hall', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Science', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('offer', 'O'), ('safe', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('For', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('415', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('642-5133.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('At', 'O'), ('Foothill', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('College', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Foothill', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Observatory', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('open', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('For', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('415', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('949-7334.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('Cupertino', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('offered', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('1', 'O'), ('p.m.', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Orion', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Telescope', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('store', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('10555', 'O'), ('S.', 'LOCATION'), ('De', 'LOCATION'), ('Anza', 'LOCATION'), ('Blvd', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Call', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('408', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('255-8770', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('California', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('State', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Hayward', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('hosting', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Safe', 'O'), ('Solar', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('noon', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Student', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Union', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Society', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Physics', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Students', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('6-inch', 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('video', 'O'), ('camera', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('viewing', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('For', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('Kenton', 'PERSON'), ('White', 'PERSON'), ('or', 'O'), ('Charlie', 'PERSON'), ('Harper', 'PERSON'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('physics', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('415', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('881-3401.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('Santa', 'LOCATION'), ('Cruz', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('telescope', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Orion', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Telescope', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('at', 'O'), ('2450', 'O'), ('17th', 'O'), ('Ave.', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Seabright', 'LOCATION'), ('Brewery', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('519', 'O'), ('Seabright', 'O'), ('Ave.', 'O'), ('For', 'O'), ('information', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('408', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('464-0465.', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Source', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Mercury', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('News', 'ORGANIZATION')]]
