[[('With', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('booked', 'O'), ('trips', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('advance', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('airline', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('rental', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('hotel', 'O'), ('reservations', 'O'), ('range', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('difficult', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('impossible', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('travel', 'O'), ('agents', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('closer', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('event', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('available', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Kloetzel', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ("O'Brien", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Travel', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Jose', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('event', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('rarely', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('rarely', 'O'), ('happens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('certain', 'O'), ('element', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('traveler', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('awful', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('seen', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('central', 'O'), ('Brazil', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('If', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('spoil', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('viewers', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('slip', 'O'), ('slowly', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('sky', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('grow', 'O'), ('darker', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('dusk', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('fallen', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('completely', 'O'), ('blocked', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('falls', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('earth', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Stars', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('shine', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('length', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('period', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('totality', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('known', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('depend', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('viewers', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('longest', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('58', 'O'), ('seconds', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Tuxpan', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('coast', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bay', 'LOCATION'), ('Area', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('cover', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('55', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('surface', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Among', 'O'), ('fans', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('heavens', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('solar', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('inspires', 'O'), ('awe', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('fascination', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('grandeur', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Firm', 'O'), ('estimates', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('available', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('blotted-out-sun', 'O'), ('watchers', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('perhaps', 'O'), ('50,000', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('70,000', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('equal', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('seeing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('disappear', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('actually', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('blue', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('sky', 'O'), ('disappear', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('birds', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('singing', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('miraculous', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Irving', 'PERSON'), ('Hochman', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('San', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Francisco', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Amateur', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Astronomers', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('really', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('spectacular', 'O'), ('natural', 'O'), ('phenomenon', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Bob', 'PERSON'), ('Bruynesteyn', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('San', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Mateo', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Astronomical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Society', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('puts', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('succinctly', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Not', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('stood', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('romantic', 'O'), ('images', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('inspiring', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('last-minute', 'O'), ('surge', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('would-be', 'O'), ('eclipse-watchers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('travel', 'O'), ('agents', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Pamela', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Daniel', 'PERSON'), ('Dei', 'PERSON'), ('Rossi', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('Campbell', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('were', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('scramblers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Learning', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('month', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('calling', 'O'), ('travel', 'O'), ('agents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('basically', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('try', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('everything', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('booked', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Pamela', 'PERSON'), ('Dei', 'PERSON'), ('Rossi', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('places', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('relatives', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('stayed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('luck', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('She', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('friend', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('place', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stay', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('airline', 'O'), ('ticket', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('rental', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('loomed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Then', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('fortune', 'O'), ('struck', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('She', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('travel', 'O'), ('agent', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('class', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('West', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Valley', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('College', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('astronomy', 'O'), ('instructor', 'O'), ('Tom', 'PERSON'), ('Bullock', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Bullock', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('leading', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('late', 'O'), ('cancellations', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Dei', 'O'), ('Rossis', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('excited', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Pamela', 'PERSON'), ('Dei', 'PERSON'), ('Rossi', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Though', 'O'), ('travel', 'O'), ('arrangements', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('tough', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('opportunities', 'O'), ('remain', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('One', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('door', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('are', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('prime', 'O'), ('spots', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('statistically', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('offer', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('chance', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('cloudless', 'O'), ('skies', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('enveloping', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Big', 'LOCATION'), ('Island', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('slicing', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('shadow', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('cross', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('race', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('flank', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('coast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Central', 'LOCATION'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('biggest', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Gaudalajara', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('lie', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('path', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('totality', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('So', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('Mazatlan', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Puerto', 'LOCATION'), ('Vallarta', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('resort', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('short', 'O'), ('distance', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Airline', 'O'), ('ticket', 'O'), ('availability', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('spotty', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('resorts', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('available', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('destinations', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Another', 'O'), ('possibility', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('search', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('trip', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('late', 'O'), ('cancellations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Dei', 'PERSON'), ('Rossis', 'PERSON'), ('did', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('What', 'O'), ('probably', 'O'), ('wo', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('overland', 'O'), ('route', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('From', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('border', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('northern', 'O'), ('edge', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('16-hour', 'O'), ('drive', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Raul', 'PERSON'), ('Cardenas', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Mexican', 'O'), ('consul', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Jose', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mexican', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('checkpoint', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('7-15', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Guerrero', 'LOCATION'), ('Negro', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('halfway', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('peninsula', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Travelers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('ca', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('produce', 'O'), ('original', 'O'), ('documents', 'O'), ('showing', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('accommodations', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Cardenas', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Those', 'O'), ('staying', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('private', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('produce', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('letter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('kind', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Even', 'O'), ('firm', 'O'), ('reservations', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('seem', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Airlines', 'O'), ('routinely', 'O'), ('overbook', 'O'), ('seats', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('expectation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('no-shows', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('With', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('concern', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('overbooking', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('particularly', 'O'), ('bad', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('especially', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('inter-island', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('eclipse-watchers', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('able', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('book', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('directly', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Big', 'LOCATION'), ('Island', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ("'ve", 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('somewhere', 'O'), ('else', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('Honolulu', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('short', 'O'), ('hop', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('These', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('overbooked', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('actually', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('laughingstock', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ("O'Brien", 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Kloetzel', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('feeling', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('ugly', 'O'), ('scene', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('IF', 'O'), ('YOU', 'O'), ("'RE", 'O'), ('INTERESTED', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('An', 'O'), ('eight-page', 'O'), ('brochure', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('available', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Astronomical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Society', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pacific', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('390', 'O'), ('Ashton', 'LOCATION'), ('Ave.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Francisco', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('CA', 'O'), ('94112', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Special', 'O'), ('Mylar', 'O'), ('viewers', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('safely', 'O'), ('observing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('available', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
