[[('From', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Central', 'LOCATION'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('40', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('obscure', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('blazing', 'O'), ('ring', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('visible', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mauna', 'PERSON'), ('Loa', 'PERSON'), ('erupted', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('stunning', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('releasing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dazzling', 'O'), ('fountain', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('lava', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('height', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('And', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bay', 'LOCATION'), ('Area', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('half', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('covered', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('peaked', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('11:20', 'O'), ('a.m', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('world', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('long-lasting', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('151', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Few', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('today', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('forget', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Big', 'O'), ('One', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('looks', 'O'), ('neat', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('looks', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('someone', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bite', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('apple', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Matthew', 'PERSON'), ('Mauranoh', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('8', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mountain', 'LOCATION'), ('View', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('peered', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('homemade', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('box', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Foothill', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Observatory', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('view', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('diminished', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('low', 'O'), ('cloud', 'O'), ('cover', 'O'), ('obscured', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('celestial', 'O'), ('display', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('160-mile-wide', 'O'), ('swath', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Baja', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('Brazil', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('region', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Earth', 'LOCATION'), ('totally', 'O'), ('dark', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Clouds', 'O'), ('obscured', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('totality', 'O'), ('arrived', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('sea', 'O'), ('level', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Big', 'LOCATION'), ('Island', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('hidden', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cloud', 'O'), ('layer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('astronomy', 'O'), ('observatory', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('top', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('13,800-foot', 'O'), ('Mauna', 'LOCATION'), ('Kea', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('cirrus', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('thwarted', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('scientific', 'O'), ('experiments', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('got', 'O'), ('dark', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('disappointed', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('500', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('gathered', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('driving', 'O'), ('range', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Mauna', 'LOCATION'), ('Lani', 'LOCATION'), ('resort', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('Kohala', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Their', 'O'), ('hopes', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('fallen', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('risen', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('previous', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('especially', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('hope', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Margaret', 'PERSON'), ('MacLeod', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('mathematics', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('science', 'O'), ('teacher', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Manhattan', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('shortly', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Iraq', 'LOCATION'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('clouds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('unable', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('stages', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('got', 'O'), ('totally', 'O'), ('dark', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bay', 'LOCATION'), ('Area', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('mostly', 'O'), ('sunny', 'O'), ('skies', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('watching', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('treat', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('except', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('coast', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('obscured', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('fog', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Parks', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('parking', 'O'), ('lots', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('shopping', 'O'), ('centers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('yards', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('planetariums', 'O'), ('became', 'O'), ('Eclipsefests', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('peak', 'O'), ('approached', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('More', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('hundred', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('gazers', 'O'), ('showed', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Branham', 'LOCATION'), ('Lane', 'LOCATION'), ('Park', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Jose', 'LOCATION'), ('with', 'O'), ('almost', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('gizmos', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('spot', 'O'), ('sunspots', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moon', 'O'), ('cross', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('funny', 'O'), ('Mylar', 'O'), ('glasses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('big', 'O'), ('pinhole', 'O'), ('cameras', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('pinhole', 'O'), ('cameras', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('welder', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('glass', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('welder', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('masks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('binoculars', 'O'), ('projecting', 'O'), ('images', 'O'), ('onto', 'O'), ('cardboard', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('None', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('impressive', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Ralph', 'PERSON'), ('Reeves', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('interference', 'O'), ('birefrigent', 'O'), ('hydrogen', 'O'), ('alpha', 'O'), ('filter', 'O'), ('telescope', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('All', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('need', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('takes', 'O'), ('electricity', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('provided', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('gas', 'O'), ('generator', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('run', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('pictures', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('film', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('bring', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('film', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Reeves', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('retired', 'O'), ('Lockheed', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('instrument', 'O'), ('builder', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Is', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('awful', 'O'), ('?', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('At', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Children', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Discovery', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Museum', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('downtown', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Jose', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('hundreds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('youngsters', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('adults', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('cardboard', 'O'), ('telescopes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('projected', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('cards', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('needle', 'O'), ('hole', 'O'), ('opening', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Stonecipher', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('discovery', 'O'), ('museum', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('guide', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('wanted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('theaters', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('kids', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('burning', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('eyes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Using', 'O'), ('mirrors', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('projected', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('exterior', 'O'), ('walls', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lavendar-colored', 'O'), ('museum', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), ('theme', 'O'), ('park', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('For', 'O'), ('nearly', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Hawaii', 'LOCATION'), ('turned', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('theme', 'O'), ('park', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('More', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('500', 'O'), ('astronomers', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('tens', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('amateurs', 'O'), ('flocked', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('islands', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('sell', 'O'), ('nearly', 'O'), ('everything', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Sun-minded', 'O'), ('entrepreneurs', 'O'), ('hawked', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('T-shirts', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('60', 'O'), ('different', 'O'), ('designs', 'O'), (')', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('hats', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('posters', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('cookies', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('haircut', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('course', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('drink', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Eclipse', 'O'), ('restaurant', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Kailua-Kona', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Everything', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('selling', 'O'), ('pretty', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('except', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('Frisbees', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Nobody', 'O'), ('wants', 'O'), ('eclipse', 'O'), ('Frisbees', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Wild', 'O'), ('Bill', 'PERSON'), ("''", 'PERSON'), ('Lawrence', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('helped', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Moonshadows', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('shops', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O')]]
