[[('THE', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('administration', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('go-ahead', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('plans', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('reform', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('benefits', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Wisconsin', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('serve', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('experiments', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('broader', 'O'), ('overhaul', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('promised', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Bill', 'PERSON'), ('Clinton', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Wisconsin', 'LOCATION'), ('plan', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('cash', 'O'), ('payments', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('principal', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('programme', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Aid', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Families', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Dependent', 'O'), ('Children', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('continue', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('provide', 'O'), ('food', 'O'), ('stamps', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('health', 'O'), ('coverage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('pilot', 'O'), ('scheme', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('counties', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1995', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Republican', 'O'), ('Governor', 'O'), ('Tommy', 'PERSON'), ('Thompson', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('Wisconsin', 'LOCATION'), ('a', 'O'), ('pioneer', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('reform', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('experiments', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Schoolfare', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('cuts', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('payments', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('teenage', 'O'), ('mothers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('school', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Georgia', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('plan', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('limit', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('benefits', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('wants', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('reduce', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('payments', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('able-bodied', 'O'), ('adults', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('refuse', 'O'), ('offers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('deny', 'O'), ('increases', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('payments', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('families', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('long-term', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('grant', 'O'), ('waivers', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('wishing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('depart', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('normal', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('rules', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('considering', 'O'), ('proposals', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Vermont', 'LOCATION'), ('for', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('limits', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('benefits', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('White', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('two-year', 'O'), ('limit', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('central', 'O'), ('feature', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Clinton', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('reform', 'O'), ('plans', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('promise', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ("'end", 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('theme', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Clinton', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('election', 'O'), ('campaign', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('named', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('welfare', 'O'), ('reform', 'O'), ('task', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('reform', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('held', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('delays', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('passing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('budget', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('delayed', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ambitious', 'O'), ('reform', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('healthcare', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('passed', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
