[[('The', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('rate', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('prisons', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('higher', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('outside', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('health', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('urging', 'O'), ('testing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('isolation', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('measures', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('curb', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('bars', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Researchers', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Centers', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('for', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Disease', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Control', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('cited', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('survey', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('29', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('prisons', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('31', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('inmates', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1984-85', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('compared', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('non-incarcerated', 'O'), ('adults', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('period', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('correctional', 'O'), ('systems', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incidence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('increased', 'O'), ('dramatically', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('CDC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('noting', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('state', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('106', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('inmates', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1986', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('average', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1976-78', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Jersey', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('inmates', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('rate', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('110', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1987', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('higher', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Jersey', 'LOCATION'), ('population', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('rate', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('nearly', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('higher', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('80', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Tuberculosis', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('contagious', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('bacterial', 'O'), ('lung', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('occurs', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('22,000', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('cured', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('treatment', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('7', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('latent', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('infections', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('percent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('someday', 'O'), ('develop', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('itself', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Persons', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('highest', 'O'), ('risk', 'O'), ('...', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('contacts', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('CDC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('noting', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('pose', 'O'), ('particular', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('prisons', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('often', 'O'), ('overcrowding', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('environment', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('often', 'O'), ('conducive', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('airborne', 'O'), ('transmission', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('infection', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('inmates', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('visitors', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('CDC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Advisory', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Elimination', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Tuberculosis', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('recommending', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('testing', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('prison', 'O'), ('inmates', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), ('exception', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('inmates', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('transferring', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('CDC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('committee', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('recommends', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('tests', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('once', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('rapid', 'O'), ('chest', 'O'), ('X-rays', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('TB-infected', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('showing', 'O'), ('symptoms', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('isolation', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('prison', 'O'), ('property', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('necessary', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('suspected', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('symptomatic', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('spread', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('AIDS-virus', 'O'), ('infections', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('play', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('spread', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('prisons', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('CDC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('AIDS', 'O'), ('weakens', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('immune', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('patients', 'O'), ('susceptible', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('infections', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('ward', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('AIDS', 'O'), ('tests', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('offered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('inmates', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('TB', 'O'), ('infections', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('CDC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('report', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
