[[('Riga', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Feb.4', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('increase', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('morbidity', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('mortality', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('comparison', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('1992', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('morbidity', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('increased', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('14.8', 'O'), ('%', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('mortality', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('44', 'O'), ('%', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1993', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('868', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1992', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('771', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Inta', 'PERSON'), ('Pavlovska', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('data', 'O'), ('processing', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('registry', 'O'), ('division', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('State', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Tuberculosis', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Lung', 'O'), ('Disease', 'O'), ('Center', 'O'), ('informed', 'O'), ('DIENA', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('increase', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('morbidity', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('related', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('poor', 'O'), ('socioeconomic', 'O'), ('conditions', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('shortcomings', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('legislative', 'O'), ('process', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('present', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('laws', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Latvia', 'LOCATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('require', 'O'), ('infectious', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('undergo', 'O'), ('mandatory', 'O'), ('treatment', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('November', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Health', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('the', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ministry', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Welfare', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('submitted', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('legislative', 'O'), ('proposal', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Cabinet', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ministers', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('require', 'O'), ('infectious', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('undergo', 'O'), ('mandatory', 'O'), ('treatment', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('explained', 'O'), ('I.', 'PERSON'), ('Pavlovska', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('To', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('proposal', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Cabinet', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Ministers', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('reviewed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('present', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Latvia', 'LOCATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('hospitals', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('providing', 'O'), ('treatment', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('free', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('charge', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('newest', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('Ceplisi', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Ogre', 'O'), ('rayon', 'O'), (')', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('operations', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('January', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('patients', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('chronic', 'O'), ('alcoholics', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('suffer', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('tuberculosis', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
