[[('GOVERNMENT', 'O'), ('veterinary', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('health', 'O'), ('experts', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('putting', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('reassuring', 'O'), ('messages', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('bovine', 'O'), ('spongiform', 'O'), ('encephalopathy', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), (')', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ("'mad", 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('growing', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('anxiety', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dr', 'O'), ('Kenneth', 'PERSON'), ('Calman', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('repeated', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('advice', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('eaten', 'O'), ('safely', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ("'There", 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('scientific', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('causal', 'O'), ('link', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('CJD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('humans', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("'", 'O')]]
[[('One', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('concern', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('continuing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('rise', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('spite', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('forecasts', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Ministry', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Agriculture', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incidence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('peak', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('decline', 'O'), ('rapidly', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Farmers', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('8,581', 'O'), ('animals', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('nine', 'O'), ('weeks', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('compared', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('8,099', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('period', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Another', 'O'), ('fear', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('illness', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('humans', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('revealed', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Warhurst', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dairy', 'O'), ('farmer', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('herd', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Creutzfeld-Jacob', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Both', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('CJD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('are', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('mysterious', 'O'), ('particles', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('infectious', 'O'), ('protein', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('prions', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dr', 'O'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Will', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('Western', 'LOCATION'), ('General', 'LOCATION'), ('Hospital', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Edinburgh', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('monitoring', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('CJD', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Health', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('drew', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Warhurst', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('naming', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Lancet', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('journal', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('regrets', 'O'), ('writing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Lancet', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('unnecessary', 'O'), ('alarm', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Statistical', 'O'), ('analysis', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('account', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('average', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('incidence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('CJD', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('working', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('BSE-affected', 'O'), ('dairy', 'O'), ('farms', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('shows', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('probability', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('CJD', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('latter', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('chance', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('1', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Even', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Dr', 'PERSON'), ('Will', 'PERSON'), ('believes', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Warhurst', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('coincidence', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('related', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('exposure', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('shown', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('change', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pattern', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('CJD', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('working', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('abattoir', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('vets', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
