[[('The', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('will', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('strong', 'O'), ('backing', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Brussels', 'LOCATION'), ('today', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('seeks', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('exports', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('fear', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ("'mad", 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('bovine', 'O'), ('spongiform', 'O'), ('encephalopathy', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('European', 'O'), ('Commission', 'O'), ('planned', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('Bonn', 'LOCATION'), ('attempted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('introduce', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('unilateral', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Health', 'O'), ('ministers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('discuss', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('row', 'O'), ('tomorrow', 'O'), ('afternoon', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr', 'O'), ('Horst', 'PERSON'), ('Seehofer', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('health', 'O'), ('minister', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('prime', 'O'), ('mover', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Bonn', 'LOCATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('calling', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('live', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('exports', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('discovery', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('imported', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('reminded', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('EU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('sets', 'O'), ('veterinary', 'O'), ('rules', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('scientific', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('proving', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('link', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Creutzfeld-Jakob', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('affects', 'O'), ('humans', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('series', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('restrictions', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('imposed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('beef', 'O'), ('sector', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('working', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('certain', 'O'), ('bovine', 'O'), ('offals', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('brain', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('spleen', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('banned', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('human', 'O'), ('consumption', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Since', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('export', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('live', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('progeny', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('BSE-affected', 'O'), ('cows', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('addition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('exports', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('bone-in', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('certified', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('coming', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('herds', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('free', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ("'mad", 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('British', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('EU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('single', 'O'), ('market', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('disrupted', 'O'), ('unless', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('stick', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('scientific', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('threat', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('unilateral', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('risks', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('collapse', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('consumption', 'O'), ('similar', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fall', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('followed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1990', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('scare', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[("'We", 'O'), ('feel', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sound', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('agree', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('senior', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('agriculture', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
