[[('The', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('announced', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('launch', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('research', 'O'), ('project', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('examine', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('bovine', 'O'), ('spongiform', 'O'), ('encephalopathy', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('transmitted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('human', 'O'), ('beings', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('initiative', 'O'), ('comes', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('pushing', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('European', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Union', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('ban', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('imports', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('arguing', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('conclusive', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('affect', 'O'), ('humans', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Seven', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('universities', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('research', 'O'), ('institutes', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('sponsored', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('research', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('technology', 'O'), ('ministry', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('examine', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), ('connections', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('origins', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('diseases', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Creutzfeldt', 'PERSON'), ('Jakob', 'PERSON'), ('disease', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Gerstmann', 'PERSON'), ('Straussler', 'PERSON'), ('syndrome', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('rarely', 'O'), ('affect', 'O'), ('humans', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Several', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('expressed', 'O'), ('concern', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('popularly', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ("'mad", 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('debilitates', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('brains', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('-may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('transmissible', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('humans', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('eat', 'O'), ('contaminated', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('medicines', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('ingredients', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('contaminated', 'O'), ('animals', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[("'The", 'O'), ('danger', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('transmitted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('humans', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('minimal', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('non-existent', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Professor', 'O'), ('Hans', 'PERSON'), ('Kretzschmar', 'PERSON'), ('from', 'O'), ('Gottingen', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[("'However", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('non-existent', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('personally', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('imported', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("'", 'O')]]
[[('Contaminated', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('discussed', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('meeting', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('EU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('health', 'O'), ('ministers', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), ('30', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('decisions', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('union', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('agriculture', 'O'), ('ministers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('argue', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('existing', 'O'), ('safeguards', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('sufficient', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('1992', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('figures', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('available', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('imported', 'O'), ('2,092', 'O'), ('tonnes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('cent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('imports', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('EU', 'LOCATION'), ('countries', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('13', 'O'), ('tonnes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('veal', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('research', 'O'), ('ministry', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('catching', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('further', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('recorded', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Switzerland', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('affected', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ('imported', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
