[[('``', 'O'), ('Mad', 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('enigmatic', 'O'), ('nervous', 'O'), ('disorder', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('trade', 'O'), ('friction', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Europe', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('threatening', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('3.7-billion', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('Friday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('joined', 'O'), ('France', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('imports', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('citing', 'O'), ('health', 'O'), ('fears', 'O'), ('related', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mysterious', 'O'), ('ailment', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('technical', 'O'), ('name', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('bovine', 'O'), ('spongiform', 'O'), ('encephalopathy', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Concern', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('transmitted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('humans', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('subject', 'O'), ('Topic', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pubs', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('crimp', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('domestic', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('sales', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Despite', 'O'), ('assurances', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('safe', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('consumers', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('scientists', 'O'), ('remain', 'O'), ('skeptical', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('British', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('complain', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('French', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('import', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('economic', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('health', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('concerns', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('price', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('dropping', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wake', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('mad', 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('scare', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Therefore', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('believe', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('France', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('imposed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('bans', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('protect', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('domestic', 'O'), ('sales', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('totally', 'O'), ('unjustified', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Patrick', 'PERSON'), ('Barrow', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Meat', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Livestock', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('trade', 'O'), ('organization', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('France', 'LOCATION'), ('accounted', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('slightly', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('half', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('exports', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('buying', 'O'), ('70,000', 'O'), ('tons', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('worth', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('264', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('bought', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('worth', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('countries', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('recently', 'O'), ('placed', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('restrictions', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('French', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('German', 'O'), ('moves', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('strongest', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('far', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('does', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('import', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('recently', 'O'), ('rescinded', 'O'), ('permits', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('importation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('live', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('British', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('joined', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('European', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Community', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('commissioners', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('protesting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('French', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('import', 'O'), ('ban', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mad', 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('responsible', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('nearly', 'O'), ('14,000', 'O'), ('cows', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('noticed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mid-1980s', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('BSE-infected', 'O'), ('cows', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('degenerate', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Britain', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Ministry', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Agriculture', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('cows', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('aggressive', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('wobbly-legged', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('dying', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('certain', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('causes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('affects', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('brain', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('prime', 'O'), ('suspect', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('tainted', 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ('feed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('experts', 'O'), ('believe', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('contracted', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('eating', 'O'), ('food', 'O'), ('contaminated', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('remains', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('sheep', 'O'), ('infected', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('BSE-like', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('scrapie', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('concerned', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('mad', 'O'), ('cow', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('household', 'O'), ('word', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('recently', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('May', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Ministry', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Agriculture', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('revealed', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Siamese', 'O'), ('cat', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), ('identical', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('wild', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('story', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('suggesting', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('boldface', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('cats', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Panic', 'O'), ('ensued', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('BSE', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('David', 'PERSON'), ('Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Meat', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Livestock', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('And', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cat', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('brought', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Beef', 'O'), ('sales', 'O'), ('dropped', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('surveys', 'O'), ('showing', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('quarter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('households', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('eating', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('thousand', 'O'), ('schools', 'O'), ('dropped', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('menus', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('meat', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('fought', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('regulations', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('enacted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('disease', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('overt', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('publicity', 'O'), ('campaign', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('Princess', 'O'), ('Anne', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('family', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('eating', 'O'), ('British', 'O'), ('beef', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
