[[('US', 'LOCATION'), ('CITIES', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('from', 'O'), ('Alabama', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('were', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('headed', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('sweeping', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('severe', 'O'), ('property', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fiercest', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('decades', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('Miami', 'LOCATION'), ('directly', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('quarter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('century', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bahamas', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Jimmy', 'PERSON'), ('Curry', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('reported', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('outlying', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('islands', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr', 'O'), ('Justin', 'PERSON'), ('Balcombe', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('UK-based', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('adjuster', 'O'), ('Balcombe', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Group', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('exceed', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('15bn', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('business', 'O'), ('interruption', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('account', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('compares', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('4bn-Dollars', 'O'), ('6n', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('2.1bn-Pounds', 'O'), ('3.1bn', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('big', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('hurricane', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Hugo', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Carolina', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('brunt', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('concentrated', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('insurers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('analysts', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr', 'O'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Lloyd-Roberts', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Lloyd', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Underwriters', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Non-Marine', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Association', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('unless', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('exceeded', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('3bn', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Lloyd', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('market', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('feel', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('impact', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('reinsurance', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('reinsurance', 'O'), ('risk', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('retrocession', 'O'), ('market', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('shrunk', 'O'), ('considerably', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('insurers', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('placed', 'O'), ('far', 'O'), ('fewer', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('risks', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('Lloyd', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr', 'O'), ('Roger', 'PERSON'), ('Hill', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('analyst', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Warburg', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Securities', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('mainline', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('insurers', 'O'), ('faced', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('75m', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('far', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[("'At", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('moment', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('relaxed', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('real', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('added', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('level', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('reinsurance', 'O'), ('available', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('underwriters', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Royal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Insurance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('company', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('20m', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Among', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('UK', 'LOCATION'), ('insurers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Hill', 'PERSON'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('General', 'O'), ('Accident', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('30m', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('Guardian', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Royal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Exchange', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('faced', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('5m', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Sun', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Alliance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Commercial', 'O'), ('Union', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('10m', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'PERSON'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('gathered', 'O'), ('fresh', 'O'), ('strength', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('concern', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('towards', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Orleans', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('especially', 'O'), ('low', 'O'), ('lying', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('suffer', 'O'), ('severe', 'O'), ('flood', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Scientists', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('landfall', 'O'), ('anywhere', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Alabama', 'LOCATION'), ('port', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mobile', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Louisiana-Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('border', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('probably', 'O'), ('tomorrow', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('threaten', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('concentration', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('offshore', 'O'), ('oil', 'O'), ('production', 'O'), ('facilities', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Shell', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Oil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('evacuating', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('900', 'O'), ('workers', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('offshore', 'O'), ('platforms', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('precaution', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('substantial', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('oil', 'O'), ('refining', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('concentrated', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'O'), ('coast', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reviewing', 'O'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('plans', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('curtail', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('shut', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('plant', 'O'), ('operations', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Andrew', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('Caribbean', 'LOCATION'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('season', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eastern', 'O'), ('coast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('early', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('gusting', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('165mph', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('ripped', 'O'), ('roofs', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('houses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('smashed', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('trucks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('snapped', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('uprooted', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('heading', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('flee', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bahamas', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Sunday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Florida', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Power', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Light', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('company', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('1.2m', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('customers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('32', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('cent', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('strongest', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('affluent', 'O'), ('suburb', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Coral', 'LOCATION'), ('Gables', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Miami', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hurricane', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('located', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Its', 'O'), ('radar', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('satellite', 'O'), ('antennae', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('blown', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('President', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('authorised', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), ('assistance', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('affected', 'O'), ('areas', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('plans', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('inspection', 'O'), ('tour', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Picture', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Page', 'O'), ('14', 'O')]]
