[[('HURRICANE', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('claimed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('costliest', 'O'), ('natural', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('history', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('smashed', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('inflicting', 'O'), ('severe', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('rural', 'O'), ('communities', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('narrowly', 'O'), ('missing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('low-lying', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Orleans', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('brought', 'O'), ('havoc', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('headed', 'O'), ('north-west', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('landfall', 'O'), ('late', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('60', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('south-west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('agricultural', 'O'), ('Cajun', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('landfall', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('greater', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('initially', 'O'), ('esti', 'O'), ('mated', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('insurers', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('1bn', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('below', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('expectations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('senior', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Lloyd', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('market', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ('landed', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('speeds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('120', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('severe', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('coastal', 'O'), ('centres', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Franklin', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Iberia', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Associated', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), ('devastated', 'O'), ('Laplace', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Orleans', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Then', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('lost', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('land', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('By', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('afternoon', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('down-graded', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('tropical', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('sustained', 'O'), ('windspeeds', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('below', 'O'), ('75', 'O'), ('mph', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Initial', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('75', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('homeless', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ('coast', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('14', 'O'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bahamas', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('oil-refining', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('plants', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('halt', 'O'), ('production', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('electricity', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Lloyd', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('member', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('close', 'O'), ('contact', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('leading', 'O'), ('insurers', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('insured', 'O'), ('property', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('remarkably', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('More', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('15bn', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('mostly', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('uninsured', 'O'), ('property', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('Miami', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('minimal', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Worst', 'O'), ('affected', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('hotel', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('basement', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('flooded', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('destruction', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('10-mile', 'O'), ('band', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('Homestead', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Miami', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('typical', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('sells', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('100,000', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('150,000', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('US', 'LOCATION'), ('insurers', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bill', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('respect', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('properties', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('Lloyd', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('exposure', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('minimal', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Many', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('lines', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('uninsured', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('trees', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('shrubs', 'O'), ('uprooted', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wide', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Only', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('big', 'O'), ('hotel', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('badly', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Holiday', 'O'), ('Inn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Across', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('2m', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('remained', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('electric', 'O'), ('ity', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('health', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('warning', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('boil', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('chemically', 'O'), ('treat', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Hugo', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('devastated', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Carolina', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('4.2bn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Further', 'O'), ('uninsured', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('raised', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('6bn-Dollars', 'O'), ('10bn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
