[[('US', 'LOCATION'), ('INSURERS', 'O'), ('expect', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('pay', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('7.3bn', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('3.7bn', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('far', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('costliest', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('ever', 'O'), ('faced', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('figure', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('tally', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('resulting', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('ripped', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('last', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('battered', 'O'), ('region', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('275,000', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('electricity', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('150,000', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('either', 'O'), ('homeless', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('living', 'O'), ('amid', 'O'), ('ruins', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('President', 'O'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('visit', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('region', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('pledged', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('clean-up', 'O'), ("'until", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('done', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('preliminary', 'O'), ('guesses', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('level', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('figure', 'O'), ('comes', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Property', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Claims', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Services', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('division', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Insurance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Services', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Group', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('property-casualty', 'O'), ('insurers', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('trade', 'O'), ('association', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('follows', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('extensive', 'O'), ('survey', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('big', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('companies', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr', 'O'), ('Gary', 'PERSON'), ('Kerney', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('catastrophe', 'O'), ('services', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('PCS', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('expecting', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('685,000', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('alone', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('reckoned', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('bulk', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('6bn', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('insured', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Dade', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('rural', 'O'), ('region', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Miami', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('final', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('higher', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Yesterday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('estimate', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('projection', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('affected', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('severely', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('An', 'O'), ('estimate', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('insured', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('released', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('losses', 'O'), ('alone', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'PERSON'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('becomes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('costly', 'O'), ('insured', 'O'), ('catastrophe', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Hugo', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('east', 'O'), ('coast', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('September', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('4.2bn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Oakland', 'LOCATION'), ('fire', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('1.2bn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('By', 'O'), ('contrast', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('resulting', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('riots', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('expensive', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('disturbance', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('-', 'O'), ('totalled', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('775m', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('leaves', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('property-casualty', 'O'), ('insurers', 'O'), ('facing', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('worst-ever', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('catastrophe', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('LA', 'LOCATION'), ('riots', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('series', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tornadoes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('hailstorms', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Kansas', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Oklahoma', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Iowa', 'LOCATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('produced', 'O'), ('insured', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('3.9bn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('With', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('added', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('rises', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('11.2bn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('easily', 'O'), ('exceeds', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('7.6bn', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('catastrophe', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('seen', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('paid', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Hugo', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Loma', 'LOCATION'), ('Prieta', 'LOCATION'), ('earthquake', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Wall', 'O'), ('Street', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('reacted', 'O'), ('calmly', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('insurers', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('shares', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('lower', 'O'), ('initially', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('firming', 'O'), ('recently', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('property-casualty', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('adequate', 'O'), ('reserves', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('cover', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
