[[('DAMAGE', 'O'), ('CAUSED', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('rise', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('20bn', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('costliest', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('storms', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('century', 'O'), ('threatened', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('further', 'O'), ('devastating', 'O'), ('landfall', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Orleans', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Government', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mississippi', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('advised', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('2m', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('evacuate', 'O'), ('coastal', 'O'), ('areas', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ('tore', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('southern', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('early', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('billions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('dollars', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('property', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('moving', 'O'), ('north-west', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('with', 'O'), ('winds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('140', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('hour', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Sunday', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('crossed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Bahamas', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Ms', 'O'), ('Kate', 'PERSON'), ('Hale', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('services', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Dade', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('bore', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('brunt', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('15bn', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('20bn', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('Pounds', 'O'), ('7.5bn-Pounds', 'O'), ('10bn', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('analysts', 'O'), ('cautioned', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('assess', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('costs', 'O'), ('accurately', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('industry', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Property', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Claims', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Service', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('compiler', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('yet', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('compile', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('preliminary', 'O'), ('tally', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('bill', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ('warning', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('470', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Gulf', 'LOCATION'), ('coast', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Pascagoula', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Mississippi', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Galvestone', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Several', 'O'), ('forecasting', 'O'), ('agencies', 'O'), ('suggested', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('likeliest', 'O'), ('landfall', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('central', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('west', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Orleans', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('possibly', 'O'), ('late', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Orleans', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('1.6m', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('particularly', 'O'), ('vulnerable', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('lies', 'O'), ('below', 'O'), ('sea', 'O'), ('level', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Mississippi', 'LOCATION'), ('River', 'LOCATION'), ('running', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('centre', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('lake', 'O'), ('immediately', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('north', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Much', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('oil', 'O'), ('refining', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('concentrated', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('coastal', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('refineries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('partially', 'O'), ('shut', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('These', 'O'), ('included', 'O'), ('British', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Petroleum', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Belle', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Chasse', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('plant', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('caused', 'O'), ('greatest', 'O'), ('havoc', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('largely', 'O'), ('suburban', 'O'), ('swathe', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('10-15', 'O'), ('miles', 'O'), ('south', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Miami', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Homestead', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('centre', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('largely', 'O'), ('flattened', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('air', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('base', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Miami', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('centre', 'O'), ('escaped', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('relatively', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('More', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('24', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('825,000', 'O'), ('households', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('businesses', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('brunt', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('storm', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('fall', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('industry', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('companies', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('heavy', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('exposure', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('State', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Farm', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Group', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Allstate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Insurance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('unit', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Sears', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Roebuck', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('These', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('leading', 'O'), ('propertycasualty', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('together', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('International', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Group', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('State', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Farm', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Insurance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('believed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('company', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('roughly', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('cent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('market', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('mutually-owned', 'O'), ('company', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('reinsurance', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Its', 'O'), ('size', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('obtaining', 'O'), ('reinsurance', 'O'), ('cover', 'O'), ('difficult', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('reserves', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('24bn', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('unnecessary', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('According', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Balcombe', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Group', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('UK-based', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('adjustment', 'O'), ('firm', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('insurers', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('large', 'O'), ('exposure', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane-hit', 'O'), ('area', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('Hartford', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Insurance', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Aetna', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Travellers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Travellers', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('flown', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('adjusters', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('late', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('assessing', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('About', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('cent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Travellers', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('premium', 'O'), ('income', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('4.6', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('cent', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('commercial', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('premiums', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('hurricane', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Hugo', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('struck', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Carolina', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('4.2bn', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('insured', 'O'), ('losses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), ('estimates', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('total', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('ranged', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('6bn', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('10bn', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
