[[('SQUADS', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('workers', 'O'), ('fanned', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('storm-battered', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('massive', 'O'), ('rebuilding', 'O'), ('effort', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('flattened', 'O'), ('whole', 'O'), ('districts', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('injuring', 'O'), ('dozens', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('agencies', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Orleans', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('critical', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('delay', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('supplying', 'O'), ('food', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('drinking', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('supplies', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('thousands', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('need', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Federal', 'O'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('acknowledged', 'O'), ('distribution', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Transportation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Secretary', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('Card', 'PERSON'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('promised', 'O'), ("'dramatic", 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('improvements', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('24', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('last', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('troops', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('specifying', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('20bn-Dollars', 'O'), ('30bn', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('tidy', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('rebuild', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('care', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('displaced', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ('state', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('overall', 'O'), ('count', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('storm-related', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('initial', 'O'), ('estimates', 'O'), ('reckoned', 'O'), ('fewer', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('100', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Federal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Emergency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('setting', 'O'), ('aside', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('77m', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ('recover', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('fury', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('spent', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('sparsely', 'O'), ('populated', 'O'), ('farming', 'O'), ('communities', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('swampland', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('sparing', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('widespread', 'O'), ('destruction', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Official', 'O'), ('estimates', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Miami', 'LOCATION'), ('reported', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hurricane', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('wiped', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('homes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('Dade', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('resident', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('quarter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('strong', 'O'), ('rainstorm', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('moving', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('Mississippi', 'LOCATION'), ('state', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('heading', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('north-eastern', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Several', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('main', 'O'), ('industries', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('affected', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('oysters', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('alligators', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Wildlife', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('fisheries', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Herring', 'PERSON'), ('estimated', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('cent', 'O'), ('decline', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('alligator', 'O'), ('industry', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('cotton', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('sugar-cane', 'O'), ('crops', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('threatened', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('agriculture', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Most', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), ('oil', 'O'), ('refineries', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('barely', 'O'), ('affected', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('deliveries', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('crude', 'O'), ('oil', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('expected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('resume', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
