[[('THERE', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('growing', 'O'), ('signs', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('unwelcome', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('devastated', 'O'), ('inhabitants', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('end', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('harm', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('re-election', 'O'), ('campaign', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('After', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('faltering', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('heavily', 'O'), ('criticised', 'O'), ('initial', 'O'), ('response', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('administration', 'O'), ('seem', 'O'), ('finally', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('getting', 'O'), ('assistance', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('rendered', 'O'), ('homeless', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('businesses', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('farms', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('process', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('able', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('incumbency', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('asset', 'O'), ('denied', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('presidential', 'O'), ('rival', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'PERSON'), ('Bill', 'PERSON'), ('Clinton', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('visit', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('today', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('brought', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('graphically', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('announcement', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Homestead', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Air', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Force', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('base', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('-', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('local', 'O'), ('employer', 'O'), ('virtually', 'O'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('-', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('rebuilt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('poignant', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('brief', 'O'), ('address', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nation', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('committing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('pay', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('emergency', 'O'), ('relief', 'O'), ('costs', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('calling', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Americans', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('contribute', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('American', 'O'), ('Red', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cross', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('struck', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('sort', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('note', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('tenth', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('televised', 'O'), ('speech', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Oval', 'LOCATION'), ('Office', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('itself', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('testimony', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('gravity', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('situation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('underline', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('benefit', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Harris', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('poll', 'O'), ('conducted', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('August', 'O'), ('26', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('September', 'O'), ('1', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('showed', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('with', 'O'), ('45', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('cent', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Clinton', 'PERSON'), ('by', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('points', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('reflecting', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('closer', 'O'), ('race', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('surveys', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('With', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('constantly', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('headlines', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Clinton', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sidelines', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('able', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('offer', 'O'), ('sympathy', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('sotto', 'O'), ('voce', 'O'), ('criticism', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('initial', 'O'), ('stumbling', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('First', 'O'), ('responses', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('certainly', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('wanting', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('specifically', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('performance', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Federal', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Emergency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Management', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Agency', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('(', 'O'), ('FEMA', 'ORGANIZATION'), (')', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Carter', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('1979', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('handle', 'O'), ('disasters', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('FEMA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('has', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Republicans', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ultimate', 'O'), ('patronage', 'O'), ('backwater', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('congressional', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('ten', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('appointees', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('typical', 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Its', 'O'), ('current', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Wallace', 'PERSON'), ('Stickney', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('Hampshire', 'LOCATION'), ('political', 'O'), ('associate', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Sununu', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('governor', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('White', 'LOCATION'), ('House', 'LOCATION'), ('chief', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Contrary', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('brief', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('confirming', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('prescient', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('committee', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Stickney', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ("'uninterested", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('substantive', 'O'), ('programmes', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('FEMA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('caught', 'O'), ('completely', 'O'), ('unprepared', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('resulting', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('unseemly', 'O'), ('disputes', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('bringing', 'O'), ('relief', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arrival', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Florida', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('assignment', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('responsibilities', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), ('Card', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('telegenic', 'O'), ('transportation', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('difference', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), ('increasingly', 'O'), ('evident', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hand', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('James', 'PERSON'), ('Baker', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('ensconced', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('White', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Baker', 'PERSON'), ('who', 'O'), ('reshuffled', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('campaign', 'O'), ('schedule', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('room', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('visits', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('devastated', 'O'), ('areas', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('pushed', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bigger', 'O'), ('role', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('previously', 'O'), ('obscure', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Card', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Baker', 'PERSON'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('presidential', 'O'), ('powers', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('dispense', 'O'), ('largesse', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Yesterday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('flew', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Dakota', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('farmers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('expansion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('subsidised', 'O'), ('grains', 'O'), ('exports', 'O'), ('programme', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('General', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Dynamics', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('factory', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Texas', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('announce', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('F-16', 'O'), ('fighter', 'O'), ('sale', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Taiwan', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Both', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('course', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('intensely', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('actions', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Both', 'O'), ('involve', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('subsidies', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('relief', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('run', 'O'), ('counter', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('commitment', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('reduce', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('budget', 'O'), ('deficit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('presented', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('guarantee', 'O'), ('employment', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('election', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('largely', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('US', 'LOCATION'), ('insurers', 'O'), ('expect', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('pay', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('500m', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Hurricane', 'O'), ('Andrew', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Louisiana', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Insurance', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Services', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Group', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Nikki', 'PERSON'), ('Tait', 'PERSON'), ('reports', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('takes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('insurance', 'O'), ('bill', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('storm', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('Dollars', 'O'), ('8bn', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('costliest', 'O'), ('disaster', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('US', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
