[[('Allegations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('shaken', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('decades', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('prided', 'O'), ('itself', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('progressive', 'O'), ('attitude', 'O'), ('toward', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('reputation', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('harmony', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('raid', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('awry', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('followed', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('scuffle', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('downtown', 'O'), ('hotel', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('touched', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('outcry', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('minority', 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('outside', 'O'), ('review', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('spring', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('You', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('wind', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('tightly', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('snap', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('approaching', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('breaking', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Van', 'PERSON'), ('Hayden', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('student', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('beat', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hotel', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('Laux', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('reason', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('assume', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('immune', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('present', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('segments', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('society', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('whole', 'O'), ('society', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('different', 'O'), ('degrees', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('letter', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('supervisors', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('mid-February', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Laux', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Let', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('thing', 'O'), ('perfectly', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('act', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('bias', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('dealt', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('directly', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('severely', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('tolerance', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('type', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('inexcusable', 'O'), ('behavior', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Since', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('Vice', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Hubert', 'PERSON'), ('H.', 'PERSON'), ('Humphrey', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('35-year-old', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('running', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('electrified', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1948', 'O'), ('Democratic', 'O'), ('National', 'O'), ('Convention', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('historic', 'O'), ('speech', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Minneapolis', 'LOCATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('viewed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('liberal', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('progressive', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('Hayden', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('image', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('blocks', 'O'), ('progress', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('wake', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Everyone', 'O'), ('always', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('`I', 'O'), ('ca', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('believe', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('happening', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Minnesota', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Minneapolis', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('progressiveness', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("'", 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('real', 'O'), ('tricky', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Hayden', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('preoccupied', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('image', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('able', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('thoroughly', 'O'), ('address', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('facing', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('liberal', 'O'), ('image', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('false', 'O'), ('picture', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Chris', 'PERSON'), ('Nisan', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Minnesota', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('student', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('protests', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('series', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('rallies', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('weeks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('demanded', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('raid', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('suspended', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hotel', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('dropped', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('citizen', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('review', 'O'), ('board', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('established', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('City', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('voted', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('bad', 'O'), ('apples', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('bunch', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Minneapolis', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('exception', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Councilwoman', 'O'), ('Sayles', 'PERSON'), ('Belton', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('pleased', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('giving', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('bad', 'O'), ('rap', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('spoilers', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Lloyd', 'PERSON'), ('Smalley', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('71', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Lillian', 'PERSON'), ('Weiss', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('65', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('Jan.', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('hurled', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('stun', 'O'), ('grenade', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('lived', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('raid', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('conducting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('raid', 'O'), ('knew', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('elderly', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('living', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Laux', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('grand', 'O'), ('jury', 'O'), ('decided', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('bring', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('FBI', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('continuing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hotel', 'O'), ('scuffle', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('responsed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('loud', 'O'), ('party', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Partygoers', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('term', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('nigger', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('beat', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Laux', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('denied', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('names', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('lied', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('receiving', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('following', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arrests', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Gleason', 'PERSON'), ('Glover', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('president', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Minneapolis', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Urban', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('League', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('works', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('interracial', 'O'), ('cooperation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('league', 'O'), ('position', 'O'), ('21', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('matter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('misconduct', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('21', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'ve", 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('deaths', 'O'), ('pushed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('beyond', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('tolerance', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('usually', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('matters', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('misconduct', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Glover', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('deep', 'O'), ('resentment', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('regard', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('feel', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('perceived', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('...', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('quick', 'O'), ('fix', 'O'), ('solution', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Glover', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Allegations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('misconduct', 'O'), ('currently', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('reviewed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('panel', 'O'), ('appointed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('panel', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('recommendations', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Laux', 'PERSON'), ('opposes', 'O'), ('establisment', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('citizen', 'O'), ('panel', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('actions', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('key', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('hire', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('impose', 'O'), ('discipline', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('longer', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('charge', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Laux', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('750-member', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('includes', 'O'), ('62', 'O'), ('minority', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('68', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('women', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('cultural', 'O'), ('awareness', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('probably', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('fall', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('need', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('ourselves', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('everyone', 'O'), ('else', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Our', 'O'), ('goal', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('offer', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('us', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('form', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Laux', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('thoughtful', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('done', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
