[[('Two', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('racially', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('detailing', 'O'), ('widespread', 'O'), ('segregation', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nation', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('third-largest', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('heal', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('wounds', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('M.', 'PERSON'), ('Daley', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('elected', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('4', 'O'), ('amid', 'O'), ('fears', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('bring', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('machine', 'O'), ('politics', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('late', 'O'), ('father', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Richard', 'PERSON'), ('J.', 'PERSON'), ('Daley', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1976', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('younger', 'O'), ('Daley', 'PERSON'), ('emphasized', 'O'), ('empowerment', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('spring', 'O'), ('campaign', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('defeating', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('challengers', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('primary', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), ('election', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('named', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('21', 'O'), ('Cabinet', 'O'), ('positions', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('Daley', 'PERSON'), ('finds', 'O'), ('himself', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('defensive', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('politicians', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('indirectly', 'O'), ('sanctioning', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('enough', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('resurfaced', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('days', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('City', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('committee', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('demonstrable', 'O'), ('change', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('leadership', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('end', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Bob', 'PERSON'), ('Starks', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('associate', 'O'), ('professor', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('inner', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('studies', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Northeastern', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Illinois', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('stuff', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('seemingly', 'O'), ('getting', 'O'), ('worse', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Daley', 'PERSON'), ('maintains', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('getting', 'O'), ('worse', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('irresponsible', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('rhetoric', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('politicians', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('ahead', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1991', 'O'), ('mayoral', 'O'), ('election', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Daley', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('filling', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('remaining', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('term', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('late', 'O'), ('Harold', 'PERSON'), ('Washington', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('term', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('died', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('November', 'O'), ('1987', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Daley', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('denounced', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('ever', 'O'), ('tolerate', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('bias', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('bigotry', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Chicago', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Daley', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Everyone', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('join', 'O'), ('together', 'O'), ('...', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('alleviate', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('human', 'O'), ('relations', 'O'), ('task', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('business', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('civic', 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('released', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Chicago', 'LOCATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('fueled', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('shocking', 'O'), ('lack', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('contact', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('ethnic', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('15-month', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('race', 'O'), ('relations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('concluded', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('divisions', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('threaten', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('Chicago', 'LOCATION'), ('an', 'O'), ('increasingly', 'O'), ('unpleasant', 'O'), ('place', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('live', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('antithetical', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('economic', 'O'), ('growth', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('prosperity', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('City', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('hearings', 'O'), ('Thursday', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Friday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('victims', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('accused', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('_', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('unprovoked', 'O'), ('beatings', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('false', 'O'), ('arrests', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('intimidation', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('insulting', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('slurs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Among', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('55-year-old', 'O'), ('grandmother', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Callie', 'PERSON'), ('Bryant', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('testified', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('daughter', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('beaten', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1987', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('gave', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sign', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Ku', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Klux', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Klan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('teen-age', 'O'), ('boys', 'O'), ('testified', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('August', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('picked', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('roughed', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('dropped', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('neighborhood', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('attacked', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('youths', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('poice', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('defended', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Superintendent', 'O'), ('LeRoy', 'PERSON'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('appointee', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'m", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('bad', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'m", 'O'), ('bad', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('superintendent', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('When', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('attacked', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('defend', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('When', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('correct', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
