[[('The', 'O'), ('accidental', 'O'), ('shooting', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('stockbroker', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('burglar', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('strike', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('struggling', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Terry', 'PERSON'), ('D.', 'PERSON'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('24', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('eyes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('investigating', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('prowler', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('entered', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('3:30', 'O'), ('a.m.', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('fired', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ('got', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('bed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('seventh', 'O'), ('shooting', 'O'), ('death', 'O'), ('involving', 'O'), ('Kansas', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('previous', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('hope', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('draw', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('line', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('kill', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('innocent', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Where', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('draw', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('line', 'O'), ('?', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('said', 'O'), ('roommate', 'O'), ('Andy', 'PERSON'), ('Brez', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('23', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('sleeping', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('bedroom', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('entered', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('incidents', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('prowler', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('run', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('floor', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ('lived', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('names', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('disclosed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('noticed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('door', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('tightly', 'O'), ('shut', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('entered', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('authorities', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('An', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('encountered', 'O'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('unarmed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('T-shirt', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('boxer', 'O'), ('shorts', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('standing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('bedroom', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Greg', 'PERSON'), ('Mills', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ('made', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('kind', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('lunging', 'O'), ('motion', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('fired', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('5', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('8', 'O'), ('feet', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mills', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Friends', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ('questioned', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('door', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('ajar', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('lunged', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('defending', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Mills', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shooting', 'O'), ('itself', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('assessment', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('propriety', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('string', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('spring', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Steven', 'PERSON'), ('Bishop', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('latest', 'O'), ('slaying', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('standing', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('fallen', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('behavior', 'O'), ('modification', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('program', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('developed', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('offending', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('street', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'ve", 'O'), ('got', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('get', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('basic', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Bishop', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('death', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('bloodied', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Nigerian-born', 'O'), ('Roman', 'O'), ('Catholic', 'O'), ('priest', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('nightsticks', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('lay', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Rev', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Joseph', 'PERSON'), ('Okoye', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('suspicion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('drunken', 'O'), ('driving', 'O'), ('mistook', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('foreign', 'O'), ('accent', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('drunken', 'O'), ('speech', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('May', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('clergyman', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('shotgun', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('lying', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('youth', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Rev', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('William', 'PERSON'), ('Fountaine', 'PERSON'), ('matched', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('description', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('armed', 'O'), ('robber', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Neither', 'O'), ('clergyman', 'O'), ('nor', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('passenger', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Fountaine', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Both', 'O'), ('clergymen', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Bishop', 'PERSON'), ('suspended', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('May', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('undercover', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('suspended', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('shooting', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('spring', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('crippled', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('victim', 'O'), ('accused', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('starting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shooting', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('oficers', 'O'), ('riddled', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('brandishing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('barbecue', 'O'), ('fork', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('bullets', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('spraying', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('extinguisher', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('killings', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('two-year', 'O'), ('veteran', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('placed', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('paid', 'O'), ('leave', 'O'), ('pending', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('grand', 'O'), ('jury', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tragic', 'O'), ('chain', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('events', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('regrettable', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('family', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Bishop', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('reacting', 'O'), ('appropriately', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('circumstances', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('together', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Terry', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('husband', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('father', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('fiancee', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Alison', 'PERSON'), ('Brady', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('planned', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('marry', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
