[[('LOS', 'LOCATION'), ('ANGELES', 'LOCATION'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Daryl', 'PERSON'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('accused', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('nurturing', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('brutal', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('forces', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('attack', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('fuelling', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('violence', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('standing', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('rolled', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('poor', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('neighbourhoods', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('acknowledged', 'O'), ('yesterday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('overwhelmed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('scale', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('violence', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('outnumbered', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('crowds', 'O'), ('looted', 'O'), ('shops', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('mostly', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('protect', 'O'), ('firefighters', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('attack', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('controversial', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('argued', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Wednesday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('rioting', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('sending', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('National', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Guard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('troops', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('bowed', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('incapable', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('handling', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('violence', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('overwhelmed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('riots', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('understandable', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('represents', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('final', 'O'), ('blot', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('reputation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('14', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('critics', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('built', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('heavily', 'O'), ('politicised', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('image', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('aggressive', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('insensitive', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('widely', 'O'), ('tinged', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Shortly', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('appointment', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1978', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('told', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Hispanic', 'O'), ('audience', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Hispanic', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('promoted', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('lazy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('suggested', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('carotid', 'O'), ('choke', 'O'), ('hold', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('technique', 'O'), ('severely', 'O'), ('curbed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1983', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('killed', 'O'), ('16', 'O'), ('suspects', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('dangerous', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('arteries', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('open', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('fast', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ("'normal", 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('strongly', 'O'), ('defended', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('detective', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('17', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('killing', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('off-duty', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('judge', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('released', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('wrongfully', 'O'), ('convicted', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('calling', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('conduct', 'O'), ("'reprehensible", 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('urging', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('immediate', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ("'sordid", 'O'), ('record', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('detective', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('heads', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('unit', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('investigates', 'O'), ('shootings', 'O'), ('involving', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('almost', 'O'), ('complete', 'O'), ('protection', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('removal', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('1937', 'O'), ('statute', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('followed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('series', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('scandals', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('developed', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('clout', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('top', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), ('security', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('President', 'O'), ('George', 'PERSON'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), ("'an", 'O'), ('exemplary', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('conduct', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('officers', 'O'), ('-whose', 'O'), ('acquittal', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('motorist', 'O'), ('triggered', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('week', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('protests', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('violence', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ("'sickening", 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ("'outrageous", 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('high-ranking', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('appointed', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chairmanship', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Warren', 'PERSON'), ('Christopher', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lawyer', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('deputy', 'O'), ('secretary', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('concluded', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('got', 'O'), ('results', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('terms', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('arrests', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('developed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ("'siege", 'O'), ('mentality', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('alienates', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Besides', 'O'), ('recommending', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('should', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Christopher', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('urged', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('policy', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('policing', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('foot', 'O'), ('patrols', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('measures', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('discipline', 'O'), ('racist', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('improve', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('significant', 'O'), ('minority', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ("'repetitively", 'O'), ('misuse', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('properly', 'O'), ('disciplined', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Six', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('initial', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('noted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('44', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('identified', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('object', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('fired', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('resigned', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('11', 'O'), ('removed', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('field', 'O'), ('duty', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('finally', 'O'), ('agreed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('step', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('replacement', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr', 'O'), ('Willie', 'PERSON'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('force', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr', 'O'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('faces', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('uphill', 'O'), ('struggle', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('drawn', 'O'), ('widespread', 'O'), ('praise', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Philadelphia', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('commissioner', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('1988', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('mending', 'O'), ('fences', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('notably', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('foot', 'O'), ('patrol', 'O'), ('methods', 'O'), ('recommended', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Christopher', 'PERSON'), ('commission', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
