[[('The', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('FBI', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('are', 'O'), ('investigating', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('videotaped', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('appeared', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('shove', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('plate', 'O'), ('glass', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('routine', 'O'), ('traffic', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Long', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Beach', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('City', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('voted', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ask', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('launch', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('independent', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('secretly', 'O'), ('recorded', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('television', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Assistant', 'O'), ('Dist', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Atty', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Curt', 'PERSON'), ('Livesay', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('request', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('agreed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('review', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('matter', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('determine', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('criminal', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('appropriate', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Livesay', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('adding', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('hopes', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('decide', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Friday', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('full-fledged', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('merited', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('If', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('inquiry', 'O'), ('reveals', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('either', 'O'), ('misdemeanor', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('felony', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('filed', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('FBI', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('determine', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('Don', 'PERSON'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sergeant', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('administrative', 'O'), ('leave', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Hawthorne', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('--', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('violated', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('altercation', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('officers', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Pacific', 'LOCATION'), ('Coast', 'LOCATION'), ('Highway', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('Fred', 'PERSON'), ('Reagan', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('refused', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('requested', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ("'ve", 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('allegation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('violation', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('opened', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('ticket', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Jeff', 'PERSON'), ('Hill', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('off-duty', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('corrections', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('donned', 'O'), ('dirty', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('clothes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('drove', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('rented', 'O'), ('12-year-old', 'O'), ('sedan', 'O'), ('Saturday', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('followed', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('van', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('wanted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('demonstrate', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('long-standing', 'O'), ('problem', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('abuse', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('minority', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Full', 'O'), ('Tape', 'O'), ('Withheld', 'O'), ('While', 'O'), ('edited', 'O'), ('portions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tape', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('broadcast', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('need', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('everything', 'O'), ('filmed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('crew', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('move', 'O'), ('ahead', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('officials', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('release', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('full', 'O'), ('tape', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('violate', 'O'), ('company', 'O'), ('policy', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('release', 'O'), ('unedited', 'O'), ('footage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('considering', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('obtain', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tapes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('Long', 'O'), ('Beach', 'O'), ('Mayor', 'O'), ('Ernie', 'PERSON'), ('Kell', 'PERSON'), ('told', 'O'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Today', 'O'), ('Show', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('suspended', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Lawrence', 'PERSON'), ('L.', 'PERSON'), ('Binkley', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mark', 'PERSON'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Mark', 'PERSON'), ('Ramsey', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('remain', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('duty', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('stage', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('reassigned', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('patrol', 'O'), ('duty', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('detective', 'O'), ('bureau', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Kell', 'PERSON'), ('admitted', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('error', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Today', 'O'), ('Show', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('comments', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('favor', 'O'), ('firing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('proved', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('brutal', 'O'), ('tactics', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('dealing', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Called', 'O'), ("'Unfortunate", 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('At', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('City', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('meeting', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('unfortunate', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('circumstances', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('We', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('tolerate', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('We', 'O'), ('need', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('happened', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('sure', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('happens', 'O'), ('again', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('An', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('add', 'O'), ('credibility', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('consideration', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Kell', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('unusual', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Livesay', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('estimating', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('takes', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('determining', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('prosecutors', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('decide', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('acted', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('lawful', 'O'), ('necessity', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('assaulting', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('suspect', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('detail', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('constitute', 'O'), ('unnecessary', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('judgement', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('prosecutors', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('actions', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('statements', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('suspects', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Attorney', 'O'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('Hannon', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('representing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Tuesday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('contest', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), ('intent', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('creating', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('scene', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('Have', 'O'), ('No', 'O'), ('Comment', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('released', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Hill', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('sedan', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('pulled', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('weaving', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('line', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('highway', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('denied', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('shoved', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('elbow', 'O'), ('smashed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('glass', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('releasing', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('comment', 'O'), ('pending', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('outcome', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('internal', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('spokesman', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Misconduct', 'O'), ('Lawyer', 'O'), ('Referral', 'O'), ('Service', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('nonprofit', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('investigates', 'O'), ('citizen', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('enforcement', 'O'), ('agencies', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('televised', 'O'), ('tape', 'O'), ('makes', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('pushed', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Spokesman', 'O'), ('David', 'PERSON'), ('Lynn', 'PERSON'), ('maintained', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Hill', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('driver', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('violating', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('traffic', 'O'), ('laws', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('complained', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('also', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('string', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('obscenities', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('conversation', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('booked', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('suspicion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('offensive', 'O'), ('language', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('challenging', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('obstructing', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('released', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('recognizance', 'O'), ('pending', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Jan.', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('appearance', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Clarence', 'PERSON'), ('Smith', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Long', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Beach', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('City', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tape', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('shocking', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('argued', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('footage', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('necessarily', 'O'), ('conclusive', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('showed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('altercation', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('angle', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('showed', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('only', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('waist', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('real', 'O'), ('hard', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('happening', 'O'), ('below', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('waist', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Councilman', 'O'), ('Evan', 'PERSON'), ('Anderson', 'PERSON'), ('Braude', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('maintaining', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('vital', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('release', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('rest', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('videotapes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Concedes', 'O'), ('Error', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Officer', 'O'), ('Attorney', 'O'), ('Hannon', 'PERSON'), ('conceded', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('spice', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('orders', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('with', 'O'), ('obscenities', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cursing', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('discourtesy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('rather', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('weave', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('traffic', 'O'), ('lane', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('wanted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('check', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('driver', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('drunkenness', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('driving', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('dressed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('shabby', 'O'), ('clothes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('reasons', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lawyer', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('adding', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('section', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('appearance', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('unusual', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Obviously', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('telling', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('truth', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('nothing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('bring', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('themselves', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Hannon', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Hill', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('concerned', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('safety', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('suspiciously', 'O'), ('exited', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('soon', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('immediately', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('arguing', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('submit', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('search', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('weapons', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[("'Proper", 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Tactics', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('proper', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('tactics', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('pushed', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('side', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('building', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('unfortunately', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('broke', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Hannon', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'m", 'O'), ('sure', 'O'), ('neither', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('nor', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('wanted', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('break', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('dangerous', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('eye', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('camera', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('screamed', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('moved', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('cruiser', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('earlier', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('conduct', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('investigated', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('determined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('unfounded', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
