[[('A', 'O'), ('controversial', 'O'), ('videotape', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('shown', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), ('nationwide', 'O'), ('shows', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('intentionally', 'O'), ('hurting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nonviolent', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('arresting', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('fingers', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('noses', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('dig', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('knuckles', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('necks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('torque', 'O'), ('martial', 'O'), ('arts', 'O'), ('weapons', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('wrists', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('twist', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('till', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('rises', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('wrenched', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('agony', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('scene', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('winces', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('lead', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('contorted', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('finally', 'O'), ('snaps', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('enforcement', 'O'), ('name', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('departments', 'O'), ('nationwide', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tried', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('true', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('uncooperative', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('cooperate', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('opponents', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('term', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('euphemism', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('torture', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Demonstrators', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('Freedom', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Riders', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('launched', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('sit-down', 'O'), ('strikes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Alabama', 'LOCATION'), ('almost', 'O'), ('30', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('outcry', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('videotapes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('comes', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Operation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('tend', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('themselves', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('law-and-order', 'O'), ('conservatives', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('traditional', 'O'), ('political', 'O'), ('alliances', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('topsy-turvy', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Suddenly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('pro-choice', 'O'), ('liberals', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('supportive', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('hawks', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('1960s', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('Republicans', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('voicing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sort', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('rhetoric', 'O'), ('once', 'O'), ('associated', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('anti-war', 'O'), ('radicals', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('introducing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('measure', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('limit', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('arresting', 'O'), ('nonviolent', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('Armstrong', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('Colorado', 'LOCATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('Republican', 'O'), ('senator', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('decried', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('something', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('expect', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('hear', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Nicaragua', 'LOCATION'), ('or', 'O'), ('Nazi', 'O'), ('Germany', 'LOCATION'), ('--', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('United', 'LOCATION'), ('States', 'LOCATION'), ('of', 'LOCATION'), ('America', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Other', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('lawmakers', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('echoed', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('concerns', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Nov.', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('media', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), ('Bush', 'PERSON'), ('signed', 'O'), ('legislation', 'O'), ('withholding', 'O'), ('certain', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('grants', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Meanwhile', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('whom', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('sympathetic', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('claim', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('religious', 'O'), ('zeal', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('perhaps', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('muscle', 'O'), ('relaxants', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('unusually', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('tolerance', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('martyr', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('appetite', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Caught', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('guard', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('ambush', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('allies', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('howling', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('deprive', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('alone', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('aid', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('handcuff', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('utter', 'O'), ('stupidity', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Daryl', 'PERSON'), ('F.', 'PERSON'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Utter', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('complete', 'O'), ('stupidity', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('reaction', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('uproar', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('phasing', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('term', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('student', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Vietnam', 'LOCATION'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('all', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ("'60s", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ("'70s", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('smiled', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('You', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('hear', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('Republicans', 'O'), ('complain', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('?', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('While', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('acknowledged', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('stirs', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('memories', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('controversy', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('chokeholds', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('restraint', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('now', 'O'), ('uses', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('life-threatening', 'O'), ('situations', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('fierce', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('pressure', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('argues', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('come-along', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('properly', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('safest', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('effective', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('nonviolent', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('His', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('added', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('well-trained', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('holds', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('On', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('morning', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('example', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Angeles', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Academy', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('gym', 'O'), ('echoed', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('unmistakable', 'O'), ('sounds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('exerted', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('pairs', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('recruits', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('dressed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('dark', 'O'), ('blue', 'O'), ('sweats', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('kicked', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('jabbed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('swung', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('sticks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('grappled', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('chokeholds', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('holds', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Reacting', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('phase', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('exam', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ('cadet', 'O'), ('knocked', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('assailant', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('hand', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('backed', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('leveled', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('weapon', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('chest', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('shouting', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Put', 'O'), ('your', 'O'), ('hands', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('lock', 'O'), ('your', 'O'), ('elbows', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('spread', 'O'), ('your', 'O'), ('fingers', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Had', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('real', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('decide', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('flash', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('synapses', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('reasonable', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('included', 'O'), ('opening', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('handgun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Deadly', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('extreme', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('choose', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('confronting', 'O'), ('suspected', 'O'), ('lawbreakers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('explained', 'O'), ('Sgt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fred', 'PERSON'), ('Nichols', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('academy', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('expert', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('least', 'O'), ('forceful', 'O'), ('tactic', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('simple', 'O'), ('request', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Would', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('?', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Pain-compliance', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('fit', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('scale', 'O'), ('above', 'O'), ('talk', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('below', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Taser', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('gun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('tear', 'O'), ('gas', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('baton', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Among', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('simple', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('come-along', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('compliance', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('twist-', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('wrist-locks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('subject', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('wrists', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('manipulated', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('soft', 'O'), ('tissue', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('nerves', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('bone', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Nichols', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Another', 'O'), ('trick', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('trade', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('mastoid', 'O'), ('lift', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nerves', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('side', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('neck', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Demonstrated', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('recruits', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('seated', 'O'), ('themselves', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Academy', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('playing', 'O'), ('field', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('worked', 'O'), ('promptly', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('standard', 'O'), ('civil-disobedience', 'O'), ('technique', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('limp', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('asked', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('move', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('link', 'O'), ('arms', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('human', 'O'), ('worm-balls', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('themselves', 'O'), ('tense', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('rendering', 'O'), ('standard', 'O'), ('compliance', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('ineffective', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Trying', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('carry', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('becomes', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('dangerous', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('arresting', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('So', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('forces', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Orange', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('San', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Diego', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('modified', 'O'), ('martial', 'O'), ('arts', 'O'), ('tool', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('nunchaku', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('termed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('control', 'O'), ('device', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('consisting', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('12-inch', 'O'), ('lengths', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('plastic', 'O'), ('connected', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('length', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('nylon', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('To', 'O'), ('demonstrate', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('instructors', 'O'), ('jabbed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('device', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chest', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cadet', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('twisted', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('trap-and-wrap', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('maneuver', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('gentlest', 'O'), ('twist', 'O'), ('triggered', 'O'), ('enough', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('recruit', 'O'), ('comply', 'O'), ('promptly', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Nichols', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('puzzled', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('compare', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cattle', 'O'), ('prods', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Africa', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Protesters', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('chance', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('move', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('actually', 'O'), ('plead', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Then', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ("'ll", 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('subjected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('excruciating', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('control', 'O'), ('technique', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('hurt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('That', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('means', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('elsewhere', 'O'), ('assert', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nunchakus', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('conventional', 'O'), ('come-along', 'O'), ('holds', 'O'), ('produced', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('agony', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('applied', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('lingering', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('broken', 'O'), ('bones', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('torn', 'O'), ('ligaments', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('long-lasting', 'O'), ('nerve', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('result', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('filed', 'O'), ('lawsuits', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Sacramento', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Atlanta', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Nichols', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('suspicious', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Operation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('pressure', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('applied', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('fall', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Nichols', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('With', 'O'), ('Right-to-Lifers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('feel', 'O'), ('something', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('rotten', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Denmark', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('kind', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('watching', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('movie', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('someone', 'O'), ('gets', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('keeps', 'O'), ('walking', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('You', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('something', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('policeman', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Capt', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Patrick', 'PERSON'), ('E.', 'PERSON'), ('McKinley', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('Metro', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Division', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('worked', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Revolutionary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Communist', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Party', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Jewish', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Defense', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('League', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('protests', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('everything', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('apartheid', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('animal', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('stand', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Pain', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('catharsis', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('failure', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('action', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sworn', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('August', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('challenge', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('devices', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Nichols', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('simply', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('muscle', 'O'), ('relaxants', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('increase', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('tolerance', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('charge', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Operation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('100', 'O'), ('%', 'O'), ('incorrect', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('either', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('results', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('dangerous', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('McKinley', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'m", 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('doctor', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('purpose', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('telling', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('If', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('respond', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('applied', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('fact', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('mounting', 'O'), ('ever', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('squared', 'O'), ('off', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1988', 'O'), ('Democratic', 'O'), ('convention', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Atlanta', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('built', 'O'), ('momentum', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('engaging', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('disobedience', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('clinics', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('increased', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('*', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Diego', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('reportedly', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('singing', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('try', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('understand', 'O'), ("'em", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('round', 'O'), ("'em", 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('brand', 'O'), ("'em", 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('*', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('Pittsburgh', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('women', 'O'), ('claimed', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('sexually', 'O'), ('molested', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('*', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Hartford', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Conn.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('removed', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('badges', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('name', 'O'), ('tags', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('purportedly', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('avoid', 'O'), ('cutting', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('allegedly', 'O'), ('hauled', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('come-along', 'O'), ('holds', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('lifting', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('sharp-edged', 'O'), ('plastic', 'O'), ('handcuffs', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('crotch', 'O'), ('carries', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('stick', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('stuck', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('protester', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('legs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('priest', 'O'), ('testified', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('seemed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('enjoy', 'O'), ('inflicting', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('demonic', 'O'), ('element', 'O'), ('entered', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('said', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('By', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('got', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('arms', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('intense', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('screaming', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[("'Jesus", 'O'), ('!', 'O')]]
[[('Jesus', 'PERSON'), ('!', 'O'), ("'", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('Boston', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Atlanta', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('continued', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('apply', 'O'), ('come-along', 'O'), ('holds', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('complied', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('commands', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('administering', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('form', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('curbside', 'O'), ('justice', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Implicit', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sense', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('betrayed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('kindred', 'O'), ('spirits', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('old', 'O'), ('anti-war', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('calling', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('pigs', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('belligerent', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Dan', 'PERSON'), ('Bruno', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('accountant', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Orange', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('whose', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('wrist', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('broken', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), ('25', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('demonstration', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Frankly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('lead', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('middle-class', 'O'), ('life', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ("'ve", 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('roughed', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Maybe', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('got', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('insight', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('demonstrating', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('gone', 'O'), ('limp', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('encounters', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rather', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('aggressive', 'O'), ('letter-writing', 'O'), ('campaign', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('encouraging', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('felt', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('abused', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('saw', 'O'), ('videotapes', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('abuse', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('file', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('write', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('senators', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('congressmen', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Justice', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('on', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Civil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rights', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('Pro-Life', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('formed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('member', 'O'), ('testified', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('witnessed', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('real', 'O'), ('atrocities', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('behaved', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('restraint', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('For', 'O'), ('example', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('feminist', 'O'), ('lawyer', 'O'), ('Gloria', 'PERSON'), ('Allred', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('hesitant', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('criticize', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('abuses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('believes', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('acted', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('professionalism', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('issuing', 'O'), ('fair', 'O'), ('warnings', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('acting', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('failed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('comply', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('ca', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('sympathy', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('rescuers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('stood', 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('vociferous', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('pro-choice', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('clinic', 'O'), ('defenders', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Dec.', 'O'), ('9', 'O'), ('demonstration', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('counterdemonstration', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Fullerton', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('inflicted', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('women', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('lives', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('enormous', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('What', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('suffering', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('drop', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ocean', 'O'), ('compared', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'ve", 'O'), ('endured', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('exercising', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('constitutional', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('throngs', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('pro-choice', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('whom', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), ('end', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('sticks', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('era', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('watched', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('twist', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('arms', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('chanted', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('L.A.', 'LOCATION'), ('blue', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('outspoken', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('bask', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('new-found', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('felt', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('stands', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('cheering', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('threw', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Christians', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lions', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('fact', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('emotional', 'O'), ('volatility', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('shaken', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('debate', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('uses', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Village', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Voice', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('columnist', 'O'), ('Nat', 'PERSON'), ('Hentoff', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('skewered', 'O'), ('liberal', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('libertarians', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('letting', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('ideology', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('supporting', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('restrain', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('calls', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('torture', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('media', 'O'), ('colleagues', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('backs', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('uncomfortably', 'O'), ('complex', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('William', 'PERSON'), ('B.', 'PERSON'), ('Allen', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('controversial', 'O'), ('Ronald', 'PERSON'), ('Reagan', 'PERSON'), ('appointee', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('on', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Civil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rights', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('similar', 'O'), ('views', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('value', 'O'), ('tolerance', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('tolerant', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('challenged', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('something', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('care', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('This', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('touched', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('very', 'O'), ('raw', 'O'), ('nerves', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('tolerant', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('pretend', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('briefing', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('organized', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Allen', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('September', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('McCue', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Hartford', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('defended', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('heard', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('consists', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('stretchers', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('class', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('prisoner', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('come-along', 'O'), ('holds', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('motivation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('crime', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('All', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('somebody', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('custody', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('resistance', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('concerned', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('abortions', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('nuclear', 'O'), ('freezes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('saving', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('whales', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('whatever', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Even', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('met', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('lawmakers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('joining', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Armstrong', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('lashing', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('tactics', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('pushing', 'O'), ('legislation', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('restrain', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Rep.', 'O'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Dornan', 'PERSON'), ('(', 'O'), ('R-Garden', 'O'), ('Grove', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('read', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Congressional', 'O'), ('Record', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('column', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('F.', 'PERSON'), ('Buckley', 'PERSON'), ('Jr.', 'PERSON'), ('comparing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Hartford', 'LOCATION'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Alabama', 'LOCATION'), ('three', 'O'), ('decades', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('hard', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('believe', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Bull', 'PERSON'), ('Connor', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('directing', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('redneck', 'O'), ('policemen', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('treatment', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('caused', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Hartford', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('treatment', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('An', 'O'), ('amendment', 'O'), ('introduced', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('lawmakers', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('House', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('tagged', 'O'), ('onto', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('HUD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('bill', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('signed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('President', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('Community', 'O'), ('Planning', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Development', 'O'), ('grants', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('paid', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('municipality', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('fails', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('adopt', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('enforce', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('policy', 'O'), ('prohibiting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('enforcement', 'O'), ('agencies', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('jurisdiction', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('municipality', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('individuals', 'O'), ('engaged', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('nonviolent', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('received', 'O'), ('almost', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('56', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('grants', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('fiscal', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Democrats', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('blackmailing', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('wants', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Now', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ("'ve", 'O'), ('got', 'O'), ('Republicans', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Justice', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('already', 'O'), ('investigates', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('abuse', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('pointed', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('horrendous', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('measure', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('intended', 'O'), ('effect', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('eliminating', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('painful', 'O'), ('control', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('nonviolent', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('choice', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('watch', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('stripe', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('facility', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('choose', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Carol', 'PERSON'), ('Sobel', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('Chapter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ACLU', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('shares', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('assessment', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('acted', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('lawmakers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('sympathetic', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('unlike', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('believes', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('pain-compliance', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('nonviolent', 'O'), ('demonstrator', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('often', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('barbaric', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('supports', 'O'), ('restraints', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Sobel', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('amused', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('lawmakers', 'O'), ('addressed', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('raised', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('policy', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('El', 'LOCATION'), ('Salvador', 'LOCATION'), ('by', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Revolutionary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Communist', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Party', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('generally', 'O'), ('viewed', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('sympathetically', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('conservatives', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Still', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('believes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('measure', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('assure', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('demonstrating', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('escalate', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('hope', 'O'), ('conservatives', 'O'), ('remember', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('includes', 'O'), ('everyone', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Jim', 'PERSON'), ('Cady', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Editorial', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Library', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('assisted', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('research', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('article', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('*', 'O'), ('NEW', 'O'), ('USE', 'O'), ('FOR', 'O'), ('OLD', 'O'), ('TOOL', 'O'), ('An', 'O'), ('ancient', 'O'), ('Asian', 'O'), ('farm', 'O'), ('tool', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('become', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cutting', 'O'), ('edge', 'O'), ('weapon', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Southern', 'LOCATION'), ('California', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('E1', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
