[[('A', 'O'), ('white', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('allegedly', 'O'), ('pushed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('plate-glass', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('secretly', 'O'), ('videotaped', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('acknowledged', 'O'), ('Friday', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('errors', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('official', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Officer', 'O'), ('Mark', 'PERSON'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('speaking', 'O'), ('publicly', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Jan.', 'O'), ('14', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('oversight', 'O'), ('committee', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('sworn', 'O'), ('testimony', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('faith', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('want', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('suspected', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('crime', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('blamed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('discrepancies', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('faulty', 'O'), ('memory', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('wrote', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('altercation', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('testifying', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('subpoena', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('admitted', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('questioning', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Don', 'PERSON'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('profanity', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('indicated', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('also', 'O'), ('admitted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('intended', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('inflict', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('when', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('handcuffs', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('control', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('Misconduct', 'O'), ('Allegations', 'O'), ('Sen.', 'O'), ('Daniel', 'PERSON'), ('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('(', 'O'), ('D-Concord', 'O'), (')', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Select', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Committee', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('on', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('State', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Procurement', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Expenditure', 'O'), ('Practices', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('review', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('misconduct', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('legislative', 'O'), ('committee', 'O'), ('monitors', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('funds', 'O'), ('disbursed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('departments', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('state', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Officer', 'O'), ('Standards', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Training', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('nationwide', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('camera', 'O'), ('hidden', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('videotaped', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('swore', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('after', 'O'), ('stopping', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('traffic', 'O'), ('violation', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('appeared', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('push', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('plate-glass', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Hawthorne', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('sergeant', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('disability', 'O'), ('leave', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('self-styled', 'O'), ('crusader', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('gone', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('television', 'O'), ('crew', 'O'), ('following', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('separate', 'O'), ('vehicle', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('termed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('sting', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('operation', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('validate', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Investigations', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('launched', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('FBI', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Long', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Beach', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('temporarily', 'O'), ('reassigned', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('desk', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('interfering', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('repeatedly', 'O'), ('played', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('videotape', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('committee', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('observers', 'O'), ('watched', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('monitors', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('commented', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('scene', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('questioned', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('riding', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('actually', 'O'), ('weaving', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('stated', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('traffic', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('acted', 'O'), ('aggressively', 'O'), ('toward', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('asked', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('You', 'O'), ('became', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('judge', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('jury', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('executioner', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('challenged', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), ('?', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('No', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('tersely', 'O'), ('replied', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('Hannon', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('refused', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('allow', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('answer', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('questions', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('nearly', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('questioning', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('hostile', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('badgering', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('nature', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('inquiry', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('kangaroo', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('gives', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('politicians', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('chance', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('run', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Any', 'O'), ('resemblance', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fair', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('imaginary', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Hannon', 'PERSON'), ('told', 'O'), ('reporters', 'O'), ('afterward', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('taking', 'O'), ('stuff', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('context', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('badgering', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Earlier', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('questioning', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('videotape', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('played', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('testified', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('infraction', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('car', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('crossing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('divider', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('occurred', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('seen', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tape', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('NBC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('chase', 'O'), ('vehicle', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('maintained', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tape', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('weaving', 'O'), ('slowly', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('traffic', 'O'), ('lane', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('standing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('monitor', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('pointed', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('videotape', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('car', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('rear', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('shows', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('street', 'O'), ('lights', 'O'), ('passing', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('consistent', 'O'), ('pattern', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('indicating', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('weaving', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('acknowledged', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('driving', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('weaving', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('tailed', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('testifying', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('subpoena', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Jeff', 'PERSON'), ('Hill', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('off-duty', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('corrections', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('drove', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('took', 'O'), ('great', 'O'), ('care', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('break', 'O'), ('traffic', 'O'), ('laws', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('cruised', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('Pacific', 'LOCATION'), ('Coast', 'LOCATION'), ('Highway', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('addition', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('pushing', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('glass', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('hurt', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('bending', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('fingers', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('handcuffing', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('pushed', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hood', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Also', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('alleged', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('refused', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('requests', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('loosen', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('handcuffs', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('station', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('eight-page', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('provided', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('reporters', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('offensive', 'O'), ('words', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('allegation', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('dropped', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('conceded', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('uttered', 'O'), ('obscenities', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('No', 'O'), ('Taunts', 'O'), ('Heard', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('challenged', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('although', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('never', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('heard', 'O'), ('taunting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tape', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('verbal', 'O'), ('challenge', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('adding', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('fists', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('clenched', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('sides', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('swearing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('try', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('alleviate', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('fear', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('testified', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('thought', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('immediately', 'O'), ('stepped', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('came', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('halt', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('trying', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('provide', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('diversion', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('armed', 'O'), ('partner', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('actions', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('attempt', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('accomplish', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('No', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('1', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('piece', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('proceeding', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('weighed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('attempt', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('shorter', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('weighs', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('At', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('point', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('assumed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('role', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('play', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('trying', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('demonstrate', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('type', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('hold', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('used', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('contended', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('type', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('hold', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('push', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('deliberately', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), ('denied', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('crashed', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('suddenly', 'O'), ('pulled', 'O'), ('forward', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Dickey', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('struck', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('window', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('elbows', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('contends', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Dickey', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('hand', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('noted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('facial', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('glass', 'O'), ('shattered', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Jackson', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('testimony', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('defended', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('self-appointed', 'O'), ('role', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('anti-brutality', 'O'), ('activist', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('duty', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('uphold', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('am', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('highest', 'O'), ('tradition', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('troubled', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Long', 'LOCATION'), ('Beach', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('investigating', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('background', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Hawthorne', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('rather', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('concentrating', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Boatwright', 'PERSON'), ('adjourned', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hearing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('held', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Hall', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Administration', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('downtown', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('testimony', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('reconvene', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('hear', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('additional', 'O'), ('witnesses', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
