[[('Over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Ventura', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('separate', 'O'), ('incidents', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('suspects', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('contended', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('victims', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('various', 'O'), ('offenses', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('records', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fifth', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('file', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('charge', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('assaulting', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('man', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('guests', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('private', 'O'), ('party', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('beaten', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Instead', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Anthony', 'PERSON'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('22', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('misdemeanor', 'O'), ('counts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('resisting', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('incidents', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('filed', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('lawsuits', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('suits', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('seek', 'O'), ('unspecified', 'O'), ('damages', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('expenses', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('pending', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incidents', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('internal', 'O'), ('affairs', 'O'), ('division', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Deputy', 'O'), ('Dist', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Atty', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Edward', 'PERSON'), ('Brodie', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('misdemeanor', 'O'), ('supervisor', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('decisions', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suspects', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('necessarily', 'O'), ('mean', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('justified', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arrests', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('each', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Brodie', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('provide', 'O'), ('enough', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prove', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('beyond', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('reasonable', 'O'), ('doubt', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Jean', 'PERSON'), ('Farley', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('supervisor', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Ventura', 'LOCATION'), ('County', 'LOCATION'), ('public', 'O'), ('defender', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('extremely', 'O'), ('rare', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('suspect', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('accused', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suspects', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Prosecution', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('usually', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arresting', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('suspected', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Assistant', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('Kady', 'PERSON'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('discuss', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('officers', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('pending', 'O'), ('litigation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('decisions', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suspects', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('reflect', 'O'), ('poorly', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('reputation', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('worse', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('always', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('disagreement', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('latest', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('involving', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('accusation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('stemmed', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), ('clash', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('18', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('party', 'O'), ('guests', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('house', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1300', 'O'), ('block', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('South', 'O'), ('E', 'O'), ('Street', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('answered', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('loud', 'O'), ('party', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('started', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('shoving', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('policeman', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('brothers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Alex', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('19', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Luis', 'PERSON'), ('Jr.', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('24', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('whom', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('gashes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('scrapes', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('heads', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('bodies', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('beat', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('provocation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('on', 'O'), ('suspicion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('assaulting', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('resisting', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('decided', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('weeks', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('misdemeanor', 'O'), ('counts', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('resisting', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Based', 'O'), ('upon', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('review', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('appropriate', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('file', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Deputy', 'O'), ('Dist', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Atty', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Donald', 'PERSON'), ('Gran', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('elaborate', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Owens', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), ('7', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Sergio', 'PERSON'), ('E.', 'PERSON'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('19', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('accused', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('officers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('ordering', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('dog', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('attack', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('suit', 'O'), ('filed', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('29', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('standing', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Sunkist', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Circle', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('when', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dog', 'O'), ('attacked', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('biting', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('left', 'O'), ('shoulder', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('St.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('John', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Regional', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Medical', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Center', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('underwent', 'O'), ('surgery', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('spent', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('weeks', 'O'), ('recovering', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('injuries', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Edward', 'PERSON'), ('M.', 'PERSON'), ('Fox', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('representing', 'O'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('client', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('gardener', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('suffer', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('permanent', 'O'), ('injury', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('According', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('filed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Officer', 'O'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('Cole', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('parking', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('outside', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Moose', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Lodge', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('investigate', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('altercation', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wedding', 'O'), ('reception', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Cole', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('hiding', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('parking', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('bit', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('service', 'O'), ('dog', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('why', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dog', 'O'), ('attacked', 'O'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('or', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('resisted', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Police', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('on', 'O'), ('suspicion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('disturbing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('peace', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Brodie', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('file', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('failed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('altercation', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Brodie', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Fox', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('Gonzalez', 'PERSON'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('attend', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wedding', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('visiting', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('friend', 'O'), ('nearby', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('parking', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commotion', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('third', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Louis', 'PERSON'), ('M.', 'PERSON'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('retired', 'O'), ('teacher', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('licensed', 'O'), ('gun', 'O'), ('dealer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('beaten', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Oct.', 'O'), ('20', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('custody', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('headquarters', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('altercation', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('returning', 'O'), ('home', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('scouting', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('site', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('quail', 'O'), ('hunting', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('Santa', 'LOCATION'), ('Maria', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Officer', 'O'), ('Robert', 'PERSON'), ('Camarillo', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('3600', 'O'), ('block', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Taffrail', 'LOCATION'), ('Road', 'LOCATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('suspicion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('brandishing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('weapon', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('resisting', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('possessing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('loaded', 'O'), ('firearm', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Camarillo', 'LOCATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('while', 'O'), ('investigating', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('waving', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('gun', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('threatening', 'O'), ('youngsters', 'O'), ('packed', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('vehicle', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Camarillo', 'LOCATION'), ('said', 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('fit', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('description', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('allegedly', 'O'), ('brandished', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('weapon', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('When', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('searched', 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('car', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Camarillo', 'LOCATION'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('semiautomatic', 'O'), ('handgun', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('rounds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('ammunition', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('12-gauge', 'O'), ('shotgun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Camarillo', 'LOCATION'), ('admitted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('shoved', 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('against', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wall', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('headquarters', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suspect', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('struggled', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('clenched', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('fists', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('threatening', 'O'), ('manner', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lawsuit', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('Camarillo', 'LOCATION'), ('filed', 'O'), ('May', 'O'), ('8', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('alleges', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('custody', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('station', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Camarillo', 'LOCATION'), ('shoved', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('punched', 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mouth', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('He', 'O'), ('slammed', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mouth', 'O'), ('once', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('twice', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('third', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Cornett', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('maintaining', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('struggled', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('broken', 'O'), ('tooth', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cut', 'O'), ('lip', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('file', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('because', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Brodie', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('insufficient', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prove', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Cornett', 'PERSON'), ('brandished', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('gun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('fourth', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Alejandro', 'PERSON'), ('Guzman-Flores', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('21', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('accused', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('officers', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('severe', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('eyesight', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Guzman-Flores', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('working', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('motorcycle', 'O'), ('repair', 'O'), ('shop', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Jan.', 'O'), ('27', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('boss', 'O'), ('asked', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('investigate', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('noise', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('alley', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shop', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1500', 'O'), ('block', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('South', 'LOCATION'), ('Pine', 'LOCATION'), ('Street', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('suit', 'O'), ('filed', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('Nov.', 'O'), ('14', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('Jana', 'PERSON'), ('Younger', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('Fred', 'PERSON'), ('Sedillos', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('James', 'PERSON'), ('Struck', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('Guzman-Flores', 'PERSON'), ('contends', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('grabbed', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Younger', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('alley', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('poked', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('baton', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('questioned', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('parked', 'O'), ('nearby', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Guzman-Flores', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('declined', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('release', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officials', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('contains', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('criminal', 'O'), ('history', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('lawyer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Sherrie', 'PERSON'), ('L.', 'PERSON'), ('McCracken', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('states', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shop', 'O'), ('responding', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('gun', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('McCracken', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('continued', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('English', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('--', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('immigrant', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Mexico', 'LOCATION'), ('who', 'O'), ('speaks', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('Spanish', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('respond', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('handcuffed', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('shoved', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('causing', 'O'), ('Sedillos', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('trip', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('fall', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Sedillos', 'PERSON'), ('got', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('punched', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('kicked', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('several', 'O'), ('times', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('Younger', 'O'), ('held', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('choke-hold', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suit', 'O'), ('alleges', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('suspicion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('resisting', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('obstructing', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('decided', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('but', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('dismissed', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ("'", 'O'), ('trial', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('failed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('turn', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('recording', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('dispatcher', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('requesting', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('investigate', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('motorcycle', 'O'), ('shop', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('McCracken', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('McCracken', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('never', 'O'), ('struggled', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('placed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('choke-hold', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('McCracken', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('Flores', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('beaten', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('severely', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('detached', 'O'), ('retina', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('lose', 'O'), ('partial', 'O'), ('sight', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('eye', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('essentially', 'O'), ('beat', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hell', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('nothing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Luis', 'PERSON'), ('C.', 'PERSON'), ('Luna', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('alleges', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('filed', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('June', 'O'), ('27', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('beaten', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('near', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('restaurant', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Port', 'LOCATION'), ('Hueneme', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Luna', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('interview', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('wife', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('friends', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('leaving', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('restaurant', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('July', 'O'), ('16', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1988', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Oxnard', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('pulled', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Luna', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('works', 'O'), ('inspector', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Port', 'LOCATION'), ('Hueneme', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('walked', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('asked', 'O'), ('Officer', 'O'), ('Peter', 'PERSON'), ('Ruggiero', 'PERSON'), ('``', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('kidding', 'O'), ('manner', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Port', 'LOCATION'), ('Hueneme', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('jumped', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('started', 'O'), ('pushing', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pillar', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('front', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('building', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('baton', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('throat', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Luna', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('When', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('asked', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('why', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('shoved', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Ruggiero', 'PERSON'), ('told', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Officers', 'O'), ('Steven', 'PERSON'), ('Vendt', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Humberto', 'PERSON'), ('Jimenez', 'PERSON'), ('were', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('assist', 'O'), ('Ruggiero', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('forcible', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('hitting', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('baton', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('elbow', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('knees', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('forcing', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('drop', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('sidewalk', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('slammed', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pavement', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Luna', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Luna', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('suspicion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('disorderly', 'O'), ('conduct', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('influence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('drugs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('district', 'O'), ('attorney', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('office', 'O'), ('decided', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('prosecute', 'O'), ('Luna', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('September', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1988', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('trial', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('charges', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('withdrawn', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('lack', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Brodie', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Owens', 'PERSON'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('internal', 'O'), ('affairs', 'O'), ('division', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('investigate', 'O'), ('Luna', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('Luna', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('later', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('letter', 'O'), ('saying', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('revealed', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('wrongdoing', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('parts', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Luna', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('asked', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('50,000', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('medical', 'O'), ('expenses', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('compensate', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('humiliation', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('failed', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('submit', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('claim', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('damages', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('statutory', 'O'), ('six-month', 'O'), ('period', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('barred', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('filing', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lawsuit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
