[[('As', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('scanned', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('flow', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('passengers', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('International', 'LOCATION'), ('Airport', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('detective', 'O'), ('Clayton', 'PERSON'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('fellow', 'O'), ('narcotics', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('searched', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('likely', 'O'), ('companion', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suspected', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('courier', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('stood', 'O'), ('handcuffed', 'O'), ('nearby', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('When', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('noticed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('short', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('muscular', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('walk', 'O'), ('toward', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('turn', 'O'), ('abruptly', 'O'), ('toward', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bank', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('telephones', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('plainclothes', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('detective', 'O'), ('moved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Within', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('however', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('words', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('turned', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('violence', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('toppled', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('terminal', 'O'), ('floor', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('handcuffed', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('suspect', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('pulled', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('feet', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Placing', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('hand', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('mouth', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('marched', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('gathering', 'O'), ('crowd', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('gaping', 'O'), ('passersby', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Only', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('partner', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Drug', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Enforcement', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Administration', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('realize', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('suspected', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('courier', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('1988', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('Cincinnati', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Reds', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('second', 'O'), ('baseman', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('inducted', 'O'), ('Monday', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('Major', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('League', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('baseball', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Hall', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Fame', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('46-year-old', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Oakland', 'LOCATION'), ('businessman', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('baseball', 'O'), ('broadcaster', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('suing', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('claiming', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('unfairly', 'O'), ('targeted', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('fit', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('certain', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('profile', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('narcotics', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('courier', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('doubt', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('mind', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('reason', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('was', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('happened', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('Barnes', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('attorneys', 'O'), ('representing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('ballplayer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('case', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('reflects', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('growing', 'O'), ('criticism', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('courier', 'O'), ('profile', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stem', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('flow', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('drugs', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('airports', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('purely', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('race', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('dress', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('activity', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Gary', 'PERSON'), ('Trichter', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Houston', 'LOCATION'), ('defense', 'O'), ('lawyer', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('specializes', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('First', 'O'), ('developed', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('1970s', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('courier', 'O'), ('profile', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('patterns', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('behavior', 'O'), ('believed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('commercial', 'O'), ('airline', 'O'), ('flights', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('transport', 'O'), ('narcotics', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Such', 'O'), ('suspicious', 'O'), ('behavior', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('erratic', 'O'), ('movements', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('paying', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('tickets', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('cash', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('alias', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('boarding', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('without', 'O'), ('luggage', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('staying', 'O'), ('briefly', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('distant', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('known', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('sources', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('narcotics', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Supreme', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Court', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('ruled', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('agents', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('question', 'O'), ('airline', 'O'), ('passengers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('act', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('couriers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('brief', 'O'), ('detentions', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('behavior', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('race', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('appearance', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Profiles', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('exactly', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('profile', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Los', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Angeles', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Cmdr', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('William', 'PERSON'), ('Booth', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('certainly', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('something', 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('prejudice', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('based', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('trying', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('protect', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('254', 'O'), ('narcotics', 'O'), ('arrests', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('International', 'LOCATION'), ('Airport', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Through', 'O'), ('Aug.', 'O'), ('3', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('121', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('arrests', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Frank', 'PERSON'), ('Schults', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('affairs', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('DEA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('denied', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('agency', 'O'), ('uses', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('courier', 'O'), ('profiles', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('number', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('investigative', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('ways', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('identify', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('moving', 'O'), ('drugs', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('profile', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Neither', 'O'), ('Booth', 'PERSON'), ('nor', 'O'), ('Schults', 'PERSON'), ('would', 'O'), ('comment', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('lawsuit', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('scheduled', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('trial', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('month', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('seeking', 'O'), ('unspecified', 'O'), ('damages', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('claiming', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('violated', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Last', 'O'), ('April', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('six-person', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('jury', 'O'), ('rejected', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), ('District', 'O'), ('Judge', 'O'), ('Mariana', 'PERSON'), ('R.', 'PERSON'), ('Pfaelzer', 'PERSON'), ('set', 'O'), ('aside', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('verdict', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('ruling', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('failed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('instruct', 'O'), ('jurors', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('illegally', 'O'), ('detained', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('There', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('possible', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('conclusion', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('illegal', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('judge', 'O'), ('concluded', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Both', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('20-year', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('veteran', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('Woessner', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('DEA', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('agent', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('subsequently', 'O'), ('dropped', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lawsuit', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('denied', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('anything', 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('wish', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('happened', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('wish', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('luck', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('hope', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('never', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('again', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('could', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('reached', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('comment', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('documents', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), ('15', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('1988', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('waiting', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('International', 'LOCATION'), ('Airport', 'LOCATION'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('connecting', 'O'), ('flight', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Tucson', 'LOCATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('attend', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('golf', 'O'), ('tournament', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('innocently', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('phone', 'O'), ('call', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('suddenly', 'O'), ('grabbed', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('shoulder', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('spun', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Asked', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('identify', 'O'), ('himself', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('wallet', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('attache', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('40', 'O'), ('feet', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('refused', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('let', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('retrieve', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('When', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bystander', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), ('testify', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('--', 'O'), ('recognized', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('player', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('tried', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('intervene', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('both', 'O'), ('men', 'O'), ('claimed', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('warned', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stay', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Minutes', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('grabbed', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('neck', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('fell', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('floor', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('knee', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('wrenched', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('arms', 'O'), ('behind', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('handcuffed', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('small', 'O'), ('children', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('nursery', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('terminal', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('interrogated', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('minutes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('confirmed', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('identity', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('then', 'O'), ('offered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('free', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('forget', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('matter', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('according', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('lawsuit', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Instead', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('filed', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('complaint', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('discourage', 'O'), ('similar', 'O'), ('incidents', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('occurring', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('attorneys', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('happened', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('really', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('applicable', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('uses', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('airport', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Oakland', 'LOCATION'), ('attorney', 'O'), ('Edwin', 'PERSON'), ('Wilson', 'PERSON'), ('Jr.', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('Joe', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('happened', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('my', 'O'), ('father', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Searle', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('42', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('denied', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('allegations', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('told', 'O'), ('The', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Times', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('he', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('discuss', 'O'), ('specifics', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('All', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('guy', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('great', 'O'), ('baseball', 'O'), ('player', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('appears', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('announcer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('wish', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('happen', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('sort', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('went', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('control', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Assistant', 'O'), ('City', 'O'), ('Atty', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Honey', 'PERSON'), ('A.', 'PERSON'), ('Lewis', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('represents', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('had', 'O'), ('acted', 'O'), ('properly', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('merely', 'O'), ('asking', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('identify', 'O'), ('himself', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('suddenly', 'O'), ('became', 'O'), ('belligerent', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('spewing', 'O'), ('profanities', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('slapping', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('My', 'O'), ('argument', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('overreacted', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('Lewis', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('If', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('cooperated', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('none', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('happened', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('I', 'O'), ('think', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bruised', 'O'), ('ego', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('offended', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('recognized', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('According', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('sworn', 'O'), ('court', 'O'), ('deposition', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Woessner', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('working', 'O'), ('together', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('airport', 'O'), ('anti-drug', 'O'), ('task', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('passenger', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('suspected', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('courier', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('They', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('alias', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Although', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('drugs', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('possession', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('discovered', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('passenger', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('holding', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('plane', 'O'), ('ticket', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('companion', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Since', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('passenger', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('indicated', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('companion', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('looked', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('began', 'O'), ('looking', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('nervous-looking', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('characteristics', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('narcotics', 'O'), ('courier', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('When', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('spotted', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('Searle', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('tried', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('speak', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('started', 'O'), ('screaming', 'O'), ('profanities', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('making', 'O'), ('animal', 'O'), ('noises', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('hit', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chest', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wild', 'O'), ('swing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('In', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('suit', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Morgan', 'PERSON'), ('denies', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('contends', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('suffered', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('acute', 'O'), ('physical', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('emotional', 'O'), ('distress', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('embarrassment', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('expressed', 'O'), ('concern', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('reputation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('RELATED', 'O'), ('STORY', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('C14', 'O')]]
