[[('In', 'O'), ('mid-June', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lawsuit', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Angeles', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('was', 'O'), ('settled', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('agreed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('stop', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('martial-arts', 'O'), ('weapon', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('nunchakus', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('arresting', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('advocates', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Hundreds', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('50', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('removing', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('intent', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('closing', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('facilities', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('associated', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('charged', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('testified', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('tactics', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('past', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('12', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('cities', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Denver', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Atlanta', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('Pittsburgh', 'LOCATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('have', 'O'), ('resulted', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('serious', 'O'), ('injury', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('sexual', 'O'), ('abuse', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('women', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Operation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('draws', 'O'), ('participants', 'O'), ('largely', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('conservative', 'O'), ('Catholic', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Protestant', 'O'), ('circles', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('movement', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('organizes', 'O'), ('demonstrations', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('facilities', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('practice', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('limp', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('ordered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('move', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('otherwise', 'O'), ('offer', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('resistance', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('persistent', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('numerous', 'O'), ('suits', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('Operation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('have', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('significance', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wake', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('motorist', 'O'), ('Rodney', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('images', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('police', 'O'), ('swinging', 'O'), ('nightsticks', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('King', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('lay', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ground', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('played', 'O'), ('repeatedly', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('news', 'O'), ('programs', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('burned', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('conscience', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('widespread', 'O'), ('calls', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('government', 'O'), ('agencies', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('libertarians', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('reacted', 'O'), ('quite', 'O'), ('differently', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('videos', 'O'), ('showing', 'O'), ('apparent', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('reports', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('abuse', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('hundreds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), ('across', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('videotape', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Operation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('demonstration', 'O'), ('shows', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('apparently', 'O'), ('snapping', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pressure', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('lifted', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('manner', 'O'), ('similar', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Lynch', 'PERSON'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Other', 'O'), ('scenes', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('apparently', 'O'), ('placing', 'O'), ('fingers', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nostrils', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('demonstrator', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('grabbing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('breast', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('female', 'O'), ('protester', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('compliance', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('settlement', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('nunchakus', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('videos', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('photographs', 'O'), ('showing', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('compliance', 'O'), ('techniques', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('participants', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('press', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Some', 'O'), ('critics', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lack', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('sign', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('double', 'O'), ('standard', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('Assistant', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Craig', 'PERSON'), ('Carrucci', 'PERSON'), ('of', 'O'), ('West', 'LOCATION'), ('Hartford', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('deny', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('FBI', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('investigated', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('misconduct', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('single', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('closed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('He', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('pain', 'O'), ('compliance', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('valid', 'O'), ('tool', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('direct', 'O'), ('proportion', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('amount', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('resistance', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Even', 'O'), ('Gandhi', 'PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Martin', 'PERSON'), ('Luther', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('Jr.', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('cooperated', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('courts', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Shortly', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('Rodney', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('news', 'O'), ('program', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('ABC', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('illustrating', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('showed', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('photo', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('using', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('martial-arts', 'O'), ('weapon', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('person', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('arrested', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('mention', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('episode', 'O'), ('involved', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Similarly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('CBS', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Evening', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('News', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('reported', 'O'), ('March', 'O'), ('27', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('various', 'O'), ('aspects', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('include', 'O'), ('examples', 'O'), ('involving', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('producer', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ('(', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('abuse', 'O'), (')', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('attracted', 'O'), ('much', 'O'), ('attention', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('sympathetic', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Dr.', 'O'), ('James', 'PERSON'), ('Fyfe', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('professor', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('justice', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('University', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('D.C.', 'LOCATION'), (';', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('predisposition', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Fyfe', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('New', 'LOCATION'), ('York', 'LOCATION'), ('City', 'LOCATION'), ('policeman', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Their', 'O'), ('tactics', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('going', 'O'), ('limp', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('chaining', 'O'), ('themselves', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('buildings', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('dealing', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Dr.', 'O'), ('Philip', 'PERSON'), ('Wogaman', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('professor', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Christian', 'O'), ('social', 'O'), ('ethics', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('Wesley', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Theological', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Seminary', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('D.C.believes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('comparison', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('kinds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('protests', 'O'), ('breaks', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('points', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('For', 'O'), ('instance', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('normally', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('picketing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('assert', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('right', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('eat', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lunch', 'O'), ('counter', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('ride', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bus', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('closing', 'O'), ('facilities', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('deny', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('early', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('soon', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('Operation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('began', 'O'), ('widespread', 'O'), ('sit-ins', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('disrupt', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('facilities', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('William', 'PERSON'), ('B.', 'PERSON'), ('Allen', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('then', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Civil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rights', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('sounded', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('alarm', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('am', 'O'), ('concerned', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('protesters', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('receiving', 'O'), ('selective', 'O'), ('prosecution', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('selectively', 'O'), ('harsh', 'O'), ('treatment', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('unlike', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('demonstrators', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('causes', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Allen', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('generally', 'O'), ('opposes', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('Colleen', 'PERSON'), ("O'Connor", 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Civil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Liberties', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Union', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Carol', 'PERSON'), ('Sobel', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ACLU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('senior', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('counsel', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('agree', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('abused', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('participants', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('ACLU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('is', 'O'), ('supporting', 'O'), ('Operation', 'O'), ('Rescue', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('those', 'O'), ('situations', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('civil', 'O'), ('liberties', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('clearly', 'O'), ('caught', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('conflicting', 'O'), ('rights', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('ACLU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('may', 'O'), ('support', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Operation', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rescue', 'ORGANIZATION'), ("'s", 'O'), ('claims', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('Sobel', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('won', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('110,000', 'O'), ('judgment', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('case', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ACLU', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('had', 'O'), ('obtained', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('injunction', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('Civil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Rights', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('in', 'O'), ('1989', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('under', 'O'), ('pressure', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('decided', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('investigation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('alleged', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('anti-abortion', 'O'), ('activists', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('decided', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ask', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Justice', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('to', 'O'), ('investigate', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[(';', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('spokeswoman', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('legal', 'O'), ('mandate', 'O'), ('prohibits', 'O'), ('dealing', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Critics', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('decision', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('investigate', 'O'), ('say', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('issue', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('abortion', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
