[[('While', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('stopped', 'O'), ('short', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('blaming', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('serve', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('two', 'O'), ('consecutive', 'O'), ('five-year', 'O'), ('terms', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('having', 'O'), ('served', 'O'), ('13', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('therefore', 'O'), ('turn', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('badge', 'O'), ('following', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('transition', 'O'), ('period', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('remained', 'O'), ('steadfast', 'O'), ('through', 'O'), ('repeated', 'O'), ('calls', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('ouster', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('later', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('expect', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('just', 'O'), ('run', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Nearly', 'O'), ('one-quarter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('650', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('responding', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('survey', 'O'), ('agreed', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('bias', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('toward', 'O'), ('minority', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('currently', 'O'), ('exists', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('contributes', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('negative', 'O'), ('interaction', 'O'), ('between', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('lead', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('scant', 'O'), ('eight', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('devoted', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('cultural', 'O'), ('awareness', 'O'), ('training', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Angeles', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Academy', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('train', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('recruits', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('field', 'O'), ('openly', 'O'), ('perpetuate', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('siege', 'O'), ('mentality', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('alienates', 'O'), ('patrol', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('concluded', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Officers', 'O'), ('commonly', 'O'), ('typed', 'O'), ('racial', 'O'), ('epithets', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('patrol', 'O'), ('car', 'O'), ('computer', 'O'), ('systems', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('Sounds', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('monkey', 'O'), ('slapping', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ('almost', 'O'), ('got', 'O'), ('me', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Mexican', 'O'), ('last', 'O'), ('night', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Yet', 'O'), ('supervisors', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('effort', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('monitor', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('control', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('messages', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('evidence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('significant', 'O'), ('breakdown', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('management', 'O'), ('responsibility', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('found', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Los', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Angeles', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('has', 'O'), ('long', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('emulated', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('reputation', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('efficient', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('corruption-free', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('shift', 'O'), ('away', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('paramilitaristic', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('us-against-them', 'O'), ('style', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('embrace', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('community-based', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('policing', 'O'), ('style', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('encourages', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('spend', 'O'), ('less', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('cars', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('interacting', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('communities', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('serve', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('This', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('must-read', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chiefs', 'O'), ('around', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Hubert', 'PERSON'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('executive', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Foundation', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Washington', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('D.C.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('enforcement', 'O'), ('research', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('word', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('clear', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('expects', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('quality', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('enforcement', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('parameters', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('Mr.', 'O'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('likened', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Knapp', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('1970s', 'O'), ('blue-ribbon', 'O'), ('study', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('exposed', 'O'), ('widespread', 'O'), ('corruption', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('New', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('York', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('and', 'O'), ('led', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('significant', 'O'), ('improvements', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('As', 'O'), ('troubling', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('our', 'O'), ('findings', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('.', 'O')]]
[[('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('unique', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('John', 'PERSON'), ('A.', 'PERSON'), ('Arguelles', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('vice', 'O'), ('chairman', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('10-member', 'O'), ('Independent', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Commission', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Angeles', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Department', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Among', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('recommendations', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('appointed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('oversees', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('reorganized', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('strengthened', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('responsible', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('handling', 'O'), ('citizen', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('reconstituted', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('linked', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('current', 'O'), ('controversy', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('fresh', 'O'), ('start', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('--', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('overhaul', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('disciplinary', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('process', 'O'), ('used', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('file', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('especially', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('cases', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('needed', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('current', 'O'), ('system', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('skewed', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('complainants', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('allowing', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('station-house', 'O'), ('colleagues', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('investigate', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('perpetuating', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('code', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('silence', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('among', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('--', 'O'), ('A', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('community-based', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('focus', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('service', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('prevention', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('crime', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('primary', 'O'), ('tasks', 'O'), ('rather', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('amassing', 'O'), ('arrest', 'O'), ('statistics', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('address', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('would', 'O'), ('pay', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('major', 'O'), ('overhaul', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Christopher', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('you', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('costs', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('settlements', 'O'), ('accelerating', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('misconduct', 'O'), ('lawsuits', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('recent', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('I', 'O'), ("'m", 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('sure', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('net', 'O'), ('cost', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('increase', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('implement', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('changes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), ('sharply', 'O'), ('divided', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('future', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('general', 'O'), ('feeling', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('taxes', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('enough', 'O'), ('already', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('questionable', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('popular', 'O'), ('groundswell', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('immediately', 'O'), ('fund', 'O'), ('changes', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Over', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('council', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('reluctant', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('add', 'O'), ('additional', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('largest', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('departments', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('U.S.', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('nation', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('largest', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fewest', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('per', 'O'), ('thousand', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('8,450', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('3.5', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('Chicago', 'LOCATION'), (',', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('smaller', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('12,000', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('However', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Michael', 'PERSON'), ('Yamaki', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('five', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('commissioners', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('believes', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('given', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('systemic', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('come', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('willing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fund', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('recommendations', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('reviewed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('City', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Council', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('weigh', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('adopt', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('whole', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Ultimately', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('voters', 'O'), ('must', 'O'), ('decide', 'O'), ('several', 'O'), ('issues', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('term', 'O'), ('limits', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('tenure', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('intends', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('reconvene', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('six', 'O'), ('months', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('assess', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('progress', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Even', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('issued', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('groups', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('monitor', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('noted', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('decline', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('harsh', 'O'), ('tone', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('welcome', 'O'), ('vindication', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('claimed', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('widespread', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('proves', 'O'), ('once', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Rodney', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('incident', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('aberration', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('Ramona', 'PERSON'), ('Ripston', 'PERSON'), (',', 'O'), ('executive', 'O'), ('director', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('American', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Civil', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Liberties', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Union', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('of', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Southern', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('California', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('Any', 'O'), ('fair', 'O'), ('reading', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('constitutes', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('`F', 'O'), ("'", 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('{', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('}', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), ('performance', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('shows', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('particularly', 'O'), ('damning', 'O'), ('pattern', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('acceptance', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('encouragement', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('violate', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('rules', 'O'), ('governing', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('One', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('seven', 'O'), ('complaints', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('sustained', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('well', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('numerous', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('described', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('performance', 'O'), ('evaluation', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), (':', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('His', 'O'), ('contacts', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('always', 'O'), ('professional', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('positive', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('attitude', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('concern', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('reveals', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('racially', 'O'), ('derogatory', 'O'), ('remarks', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('ongoing', 'O'), ('basis', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), (';', 'O'), ('racist', 'O'), ('jokes', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('cartoons', 'O'), ('appear', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('bulletin', 'O'), ('boards', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('station', 'O'), ('locker', 'O'), ('rooms', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Sexism', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('homophobia', 'O'), ('abound', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Minority', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('complain', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('whites', 'O'), ('dominate', 'O'), ('managerial', 'O'), ('posts', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), (',', 'O'), ('possibly', 'O'), ('contributing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('these', 'O'), ('problems', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('More', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('80', 'O'), ('%', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('black', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Hispanic', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Asian', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('entry-level', 'O'), ('ranks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('most', 'O'), ('surprising', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('recommendation', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), ('resign', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('transitional', 'O'), ('period', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('begin', 'O'), ('implementing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('proposals', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('``', 'O'), ('We', 'O'), ("'re", 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('startled', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('any', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('things', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('hours', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('release', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('added', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('worked', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('accomplish', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('what', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ('suggested', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('often', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('stymied', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('budget', 'O'), ('cuts', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('As', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('recommendation', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('step', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('embattled', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('wait', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('voters', 'O'), ('sanction', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('move', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('limit', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('tenure', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Overall', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('added', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('It', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('report', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('There', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('lot', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('thoughtful', 'O'), ('recommendations', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('stay', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('implement', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mayor', 'O'), ('Bradley', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('hopes', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('follow', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('commission', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('recommendations', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('commence', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('transition', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('mayor', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('appointed', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('lacks', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('authority', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('previously', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('resignation', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
