[[('A', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('plays', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('essential', 'O'), ('role', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('setting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('climate', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('operates', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Through', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('public', 'O'), ('statements', 'O'), ('clearly', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('odds', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('concept', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('policing', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('which', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('improve', 'O'), ('neighborhoods', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('prevent', 'O'), ('crime', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('A', 'O'), ('few', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), ('Chief', 'O'), ('Gates', 'O'), ('referred', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('gang', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('dirty', 'O'), ('little', 'O'), ('cowards', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('warned', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('resounding', 'O'), ('applause', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('fall', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hammer', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('exchange', 'O'), ('sounded', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('gang', 'O'), ('challenging', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('seeking', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('reduce', 'O'), ('conflict', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Indeed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Rambo-like', 'O'), ('challenge', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('lower', 'O'), ('violence', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('may', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('increased', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Hundreds', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('gang', 'O'), ('homicides', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('despite', 'O'), ('sweeps', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('better', 'O'), ('advised', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('seek', 'O'), ('community', 'O'), ('programs', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('jobs', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('education', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('elimination', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('prejudice', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('improvement', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('neighborhoods', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('kind', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('reasoning', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('foreign', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('publicly', 'O'), ('claimed', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('SWAT', 'O'), ('team', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('free', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Iranian', 'O'), ('hostages', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Similarly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('vehemently', 'O'), ('opposed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Program', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('backed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chiefs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('would', 'O'), ('send', 'O'), ('idealistic', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('serve', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('four', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('tour', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('duty', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('college', 'O'), ('graduation', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('return', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('federal', 'O'), ('funding', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('educations', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('opposed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('Corps', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('because', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('members', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('professionals', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Yet', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('presence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('non-professionals', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('discourage', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('racism', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('exposed', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Rodney', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('beating', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Such', 'O'), ('attitudes', 'O'), ('survive', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('closed', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('culture', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('presence', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('corps', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), ('witness', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('deterred', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('criminal', 'O'), ('cops', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Many', 'O'), ('chiefs', 'O'), ('openly', 'O'), ('disagreed', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('when', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('opposed', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Corps', 'O'), ('Bill', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Congress', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('We', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('openly', 'O'), ('critical', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('other', 'O'), ('statements', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('For', 'O'), ('example', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('once', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('susceptible', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('normal', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('chokeholds', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('More', 'O'), ('recently', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('described', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('killer', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('policewoman', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('El', 'O'), ('Salvadoran', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('here', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('nationality', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('murderer', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('irrelevant', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('nothing', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('lessen', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tragedy', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fallen', 'O'), ('officer', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('statement', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('blacks', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('gave', 'O'), ('comfort', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('bigots', 'O'), ('within', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('outside', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('hardly', 'O'), ('reduced', 'O'), ('conflict', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('majority', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('population', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('made', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('minorities', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('need', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('deserve', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('protection', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('whether', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('citizens', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Two', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('ago', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('national', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('documentary', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('defended', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('special', 'O'), ('unit', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('many', 'O'), ('criminals', 'O'), ('during', 'O'), ('stakeouts', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('unit', 'O'), ('had', 'O'), ('advance', 'O'), ('knowledge', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('crimes', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('often', 'O'), ('stayed', 'O'), ('outside', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('let', 'O'), ('robberies', 'O'), ('occur', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('even', 'O'), ('though', 'O'), ('innocent', 'O'), ('retailers', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('customers', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('put', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('risk', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('arresting', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('criminals', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('robberies', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('good', 'O'), ('idea', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('courts', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('lenient', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('The', 'O'), ('unit', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('allowed', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('continue', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('operate', 'O'), ('despite', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('high', 'O'), ('shooting', 'O'), ('rate', 'O'), ('--', 'O'), ('or', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('worse', 'O'), ('still', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('because', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('shootings', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Last', 'O'), ('year', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('paid', 'O'), ('$', 'O'), ('3', 'O'), ('million', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('52', 'O'), ('residents', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('apartment', 'O'), ('complex', 'O'), ('ransacked', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('reluctantly', 'O'), ('admitted', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('did', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ransacking', 'O'), ('were', 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('could', 'O'), ('understand', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('frustration', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('trying', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('fight', 'O'), ('drugs', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Even', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('recently', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('told', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Senate', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('that', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('casual', 'O'), ('drug', 'O'), ('users', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('taken', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('shot', 'O'), ('.', 'O'), ("''", 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('assured', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('senators', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('facetious', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('And', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('initial', 'O'), ('reaction', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('television', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Rodney', 'O'), ('King', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('tapes', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('defensive', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mayor', 'O'), ('Tom', 'PERSON'), ('Bradley', 'PERSON'), ('told', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('media', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('conduct', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('tolerated', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wrongdoers', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('sought', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('punishment', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('while', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('shocked', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('drawing', 'O'), ('conclusions', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('would', 'O'), ('look', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('``', 'O'), ('background', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ("''", 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Presumably', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('now', 'O'), ('received', 'O'), ('wiser', 'O'), ('council', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('prosecution', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('three', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('produced', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('videotape', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('troops', 'O'), ('condemning', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('condemnation', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('misconduct', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('excessive', 'O'), ('force', 'O'), ('should', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('constant', 'O'), ('message', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('command', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('before', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('not', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('afterthought', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Yet', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('hard', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('imagine', 'O'), ('commanders', 'O'), ('preaching', 'O'), ('restraint', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('light', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('constant', 'O'), ('belligerent', 'O'), ('pronouncements', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Even', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('apology', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('sent', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), ('message', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('said', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('hoped', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('incident', 'O'), ('might', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('straighten', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('life', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('hard', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('imagine', 'O'), ('someone', 'O'), ('unlawfully', 'O'), ('beaten', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('uniformed', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('looked', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('being', 'O'), ('inspired', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('respect', 'O'), ('law', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('order', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Or', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('suggesting', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('beating', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('warning', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('further', 'O'), ('run-ins', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('?', 'O')]]
[[('Clearly', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('Daryl', 'PERSON'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('words', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('actions', 'O'), ('create', 'O'), ('doubt', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('claim', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Rodney', 'PERSON'), ('King', 'PERSON'), ('incident', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('aberration', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Public', 'O'), ('opinion', 'O'), ('polls', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('show', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('majority', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('people', 'O'), ('believe', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('common', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('disapprove', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ('has', 'O'), ('done', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('job', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('When', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('characterizes', 'O'), ('such', 'O'), ('opposition', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('cop-haters', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('embitters', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('department', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('some', 'O'), ('extent', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('Mr.', 'O'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('military', 'O'), ('style', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('policing', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('odds', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('rest', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('country', 'O'), (',', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('leaders', 'O'), ('publicly', 'O'), ('repudiated', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('hard', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('see', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Los', 'LOCATION'), ('Angeles', 'LOCATION'), ('Police', 'O'), ('Department', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('regain', 'O'), ('credibility', 'O'), ('unless', 'O'), ('Daryl', 'PERSON'), ('Gates', 'PERSON'), ("'s", 'O'), ('leave', 'O'), ('becomes', 'O'), ('permanent', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('But', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('videotape', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('LAPD', 'ORGANIZATION'), ('brutality', 'O'), ('affects', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('credibility', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('officers', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('It', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('cast', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cloud', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('policing', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('wo', 'O'), ("n't", 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('lifted', 'O'), ('until', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chiefs', 'O'), ('drop', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ('code', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('silence', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('speak', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('against', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('own', 'O'), ("'s", 'O'), ('peculiar', 'O'), ('philosophy', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('policing', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('--', 'O'), ('-', 'O'), ('Mr.', 'O'), ('McNamara', 'PERSON'), ('is', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('police', 'O'), ('chief', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('San', 'LOCATION'), ('Jose', 'LOCATION'), ('.', 'O')]]
[[('He', 'O'), ('comes', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('family', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('policemen', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('has', 'O'), ('been', 'O'), ('one', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('35', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('.', 'O')]]
